<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MOOC on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/mooc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MOOC on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/mooc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Predicting mooc dropout over weeks using machine learning methods</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-11-kloft14predicting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-11-kloft14predicting/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @kloftpredicting
Kloft, M., Stiehler, F., Zheng, Z., and Pinkwart, N. (2014). Predicting mooc dropout over weeks using machine learning methods. In Modeling Large Scale Social Interaction in Massively Open Online Courses Workshop (EMNLP 2014).
Notes A potentially useful paper. The element of using historical features to predict dropouts is useful. It also built and tested a number of features for predicting dropouts. But the value of predicting dropouts in later weeks of a MOOC is limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Studying learning in the worldwide classroom: Research into edX’s first MOOC</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-15-breslow2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-15-breslow2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Breslow2013
Breslow, L. and Pritchard, D. (2013). Studying learning in the worldwide classroom: Research into edX’s first MOOC. Research &amp;amp; Practice Assessment, 8(1):13–25.
Notes This article is one of my favorite piece about MOOC research. It was also one of the earliest to look more deeply into MOOC learner activities. The questions got answered are important, and preliminary at the same time. But these many questions the authors ask are even more important to further explore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Unpacking mooc scholarly discourse</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-15-ebben13unpacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-15-ebben13unpacking/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @ebben13unpacking
Ebben, M. and Murphy, J. S. (2014). Unpacking mooc scholarly discourse: a review of nascent mooc scholarship. Learning, Media and Technology, 39(3):328–345.
Notes A review of MOOC research is useful for someone who is new to the topic (and its history). Based on a review of about two dozen journal articles, the authors identified two phases of MOOC scholarly discourse, characterizing each phase by their key ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Zhang2016-ps-Understanding the dynamics of MOOC discussion forums with simulation investigation for empirical network analysis (SIENA)</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-01-zhang2016-ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-01-zhang2016-ps/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Zhang2016-ps
Zhang, J., Skryabin, M., &amp;amp; Song, X. (2016). Understanding the dynamics of MOOC discussion forums with simulation investigation for empirical network analysis (SIENA). Distance Education, 37(3), 270–286. https://doi.org/10.1080/01587919.2016.1226230
Notes Interesting and well-grounded study of MOOC forums using SIENA. It adopts a hypothesis-testing paradigm. The discussion of the literation is extensive and useful. The findings could be further discussed. For example, I would like to see the authors&amp;rsquo; discussion of why reciprocity declined across the time periods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>