<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>https://meefen.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Bodong Chen.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 12:19:31 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://meefen.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Socio-Temporal Dynamics in Peer Interaction Events</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2020-lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 12:19:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2020-lak/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Conditions for Knowledge Building for the Public Good</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-icce-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-icce-keynote/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Epistemic Cognition in Knowledge Building: Discourse, Tools, and Analytics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-pel-episteic-cultures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-pel-episteic-cultures/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Statement of Graduate Advising</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-08-20-advising-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-08-20-advising-statement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://coen.boisestate.edu/advising/files/2012/08/advising-sign.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following advice from a fantastic leadership coach from my university, I drafted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://advisingmatters.berkeley.edu/professional-development/writing-statement-advising-philosophy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;statement of advising philosophy&lt;/a&gt; in the past summer (yes the summer has already passed in MN).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://via.hypothes.is/https://bodong.me/file/BChen_Advising_Statement.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here it is!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to leave suggestions via &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.hypothes.is/start/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hypothesis annotations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other project that I haven&amp;rsquo;t accomplished this summer is to create a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/03/smarter-living/failure-resume.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Résumé of Failures&lt;/a&gt;. Hope I don&amp;rsquo;t need to wait for the next summer because that will be a big failure :).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Call for Third-Order Change in Learning Analytics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-06-06-ecological-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 12:28:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-06-06-ecological-design/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Disclaimer: It&amp;rsquo;s summer time, meaning time for some bold statements.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Any educational intervention, for the obvious, common-sense reasons mentioned above, can do harm&amp;hellip; ignoring side effects is one of the main reasons for the perpetual wars and pendulum swings in education.” — Yong Zhao (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education often turns to other disciplines for inspirations. In medicine, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/primer/precisionmedicine/definition&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;precision medicine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;takes into account individual variability in genes, environment, and lifestyle for each person&amp;rdquo; when treating diseases. In business, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Business_intelligence&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;business intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; harnesses information and analytics to improve and optimize decisions and performance. All good stuff, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the emergence of &lt;strong&gt;learning analytics&lt;/strong&gt;—now often referred to as ‘AI in Education’—was motivated by these very analogies. With more and richer data, as well as stronger data science methods, education is poised to better understand and support learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as pointed out by &lt;a href=&#34;http://zhaolearning.com/2018/10/07/what-evidence-problems-with-evidence-based-education-side-effects-in-education/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Yong Zhao&lt;/a&gt;, we rarely talk about ‘side effects’ in education when discussing changes and reforms. So aren’t more of us talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newcultureoflearning.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;types of learning and learning cultures&lt;/a&gt; out of the ‘curriculum box’, or not in the mainstream accountability-centric education system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work tagged with ‘learning analytics’ is probably facing the same challenges as earlier educational interventions, especially those related to the integration of EdTech in the education systems. While precision medicine is a great idea, is &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;precision education&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; necessarily a good one? If precision medicine is optimizing conditions of combating a disease, what outcomes would precision education work for? Outcomes worthwhile for whom?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- **To have a better chance of success, we do not only need to consider ‘side effects’ and but also use some ideas from complexity theory and ecological perspectives.** --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;different-levels-of-learning&#34;&gt;Different Levels of Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me first turn to the ‘learning’ part in learning analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Stephen Sterling’s (2001) book titled &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Education&lt;/em&gt;, he delineates three levels of learning. The &lt;em&gt;first-order&lt;/em&gt; learning is about ‘basic’ acquisition of knowledge and skills. The &lt;em&gt;second-order&lt;/em&gt; learning deals with ‘learning about learning’ and requires reflexitivity. The &lt;em&gt;third-order&lt;/em&gt; learning recognizes the existing paradigm of learning and facilitates paradigmatic reconstruction to transform learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, such categorization is coarse to a certain degree. What is useful an exercise is to scan articles from the &lt;em&gt;Learning Analytics and Knowledge&lt;/em&gt; (LAK) conference or the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Learning Analytics&lt;/em&gt; (JLA) to see what learning analytics research cares about when discussing learning. I would be not surprised if many/most articles are found to deal with &lt;em&gt;first-order&lt;/em&gt; learning, such as earning a passing grade in an introductory algebra course. This is not saying passing a course is not a worthwhile educational goal. Rather, we need to think more broadly about what learning means and entails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need more learning analytics work that pushes our views of learning, given we are now better aided by data, AI, dashboards, and so on. We need to, for instance, look at nurturing higher-order competencies as demonstrated by &lt;a href=&#34;https://learning-analytics.info/journals/index.php/JLA/issue/view/381&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this JLA special issue&lt;/a&gt;. We need to look at nascent (or simply more natural) learning contexts that involve dynamic, messy interactions among learners, artifacts, information systems, and the physical world. Recent work on ‘&lt;a href=&#34;http://simon.buckinghamshum.net/2019/02/chi19-towards-collaboration-translucence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Collaboration Translucence&lt;/a&gt;’ is one great example. We need to build ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/44429572?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pedagogical biases&lt;/a&gt;’ (Scardamalia, 2008)—biases conducive to fresh ideas of learning—into learning analytics applications to combat traditional fixation on first-order learning, and to help educators unlearn and relearn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, to realize its full potential, discourse around learning analytics should not be dominantly about first-order learning. While the field is progressing steadily (e.g., penetrating into board rooms of the provost offices), we probably should set bolder educational goals for learning analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;different-aims-of-education&#34;&gt;Different Aims of Education&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I believe that education, therefore, is a process of living and not a preparation for future living.” — John Dewey, &lt;a href=&#34;http://dewey.pragmatism.org/creed.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Pedagogic Creed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, we do not agree on the aims of education, like what we don’t agree on the meanings of learning, and like we don’t agree on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/food-and-drink/pizza-pineapple-is-it-acceptable-chefs-expert-opinion-a8074571.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;whether pineapple can be a legitimate pizza topping&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When discussing, designing, and integrating learning analytics at an educational institution, we need to recognize that &lt;strong&gt;the education system is multi-functional&lt;/strong&gt; and carries a mix of very different aims like the following (Sterling, 2001):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liberal&lt;/em&gt;: To develop the individual and his/her potential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Socializing&lt;/em&gt;: To replicate society and culture and promote citizenship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transformative&lt;/em&gt;: To encourage change toward a fairer society and better world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vocational&lt;/em&gt;: To train people for employment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are fundamental tentions among these educational aims, fueling debates such as whether education ought to be &lt;em&gt;intrinsic&lt;/em&gt; (an end in itself) or &lt;em&gt;instrumental&lt;/em&gt; (a means to an end).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like my prior criticism of the fixation on first-order learning, I also caution a predominant emphasis on the &lt;em&gt;vocational&lt;/em&gt; aim of education. Indeed, graduation rates and employability are important, but only to a degree of serving individual and societal well-being. Without attending to the other aims, the vocational aim would most certainly fail to stand on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-call-for-third-order-change&#34;&gt;A Call for Third-Order Change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If learning analytics is serving a narrow band of learning and educational aims, it may lead to changes&amp;mdash;but most likely only at the &lt;em&gt;functional&lt;/em&gt; level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In learning analytics, much work is serving the functional realm of education (not learning) that resolves into a current institution and its established system. Earlier attempts of distincting learning analytics from &lt;em&gt;academic analytics&lt;/em&gt; were well-intended but futile. It seems academic analytics would naturally focus more on the functional side, while learning analytics could truly dig into complex processes of learning using sophisticated data science methods. Of course, both tracks are progressing. But I observe a chasm between people whose job codes are on the functional side vs. those who care about the learning side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Few learning analytics efforts I witness are aiming at making a &lt;em&gt;third-order change&lt;/em&gt;; that is, to harness data analytics to see learning differently.&lt;/strong&gt; Startups may conveniently claim to totally transform learning or disrupt education, but unfortunately many of their claims fall flat. In the adaptive learning space, for instance, we already know the story about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.insidehighered.com/blogs/just-visiting/knewton-gone-larger-threat-remains&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Knewton&lt;/a&gt;. And we now have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.edsurge.com/news/2018-02-05-act-bets-big-on-analytics-adaptive-learning-with-7-5m-investment-in-smart-sparrow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SmartSparrow&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/syncedreview/adaptive-learning-startup-squirrel-ai-raises-cn-1b-df275cbce068&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Squirrel AI&lt;/a&gt;. A problem with many “disruptive” technologies is on Day One they decide to side themselves with a dated educational paradigm and never look back. Still too often, EdTech products harnessing learning analytics merely contribute to the &lt;em&gt;functional&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;managerial&lt;/em&gt; aspects of education such as tracking student progress in a prescribed curricular space. In this case, the third-order change would hardly occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, the side effects of the managerialist use of analytics in education cannot be neglected. It has been warned a long time ago that the managerialist approach tends to corrode what a ‘good education’ could be (Sterling, 2001), leading towards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a narrowing of what counts as achievement to that which can be measured&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;deprofessionalization of teachers, who become technicians rather than reflective practitioners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decline in teacher-led innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a creeping up of marks over time as it is in everybody’s interests to demonstrate ‘high standards’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;valuing what can be measured, rather than measuring what is valued&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To move towards third-order change, analytics in education need to broaden the scene from perfecting functional/managerial/mechanistic tasks to consider complex, emergent processes in the ‘ecosystem’.&lt;/strong&gt; At a basic level, a learning analytics application needs to be clearly positioned in the existing institutional structure in relation to the other ‘agents’ in place&amp;mdash;people and information systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking inward into the application, rather than focusing on single variables, it could focus on a set of relations and the whole; rather than powering external evaluation of student learning (or &amp;ldquo;turning students into numbers on a teacher dashboard&amp;rdquo;), it could aim to support self-assessment and self-discovery by students; rather than striving for normative values and homogenization, it could nurture heterogeneity among learners in a class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking outward from the application, we need to design for a meaningful social life of learners, and to design interactions between the application and other information systems as well as &amp;lsquo;locations&amp;rsquo; of learning (Edwards &amp;amp; Usher, 2007).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To a certain degree, I’m advocating for some type of &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ecological_design&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ecological design&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; of learning analytics&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s certainly vague right now. It is clear though that the field of learning analytics needs to develop a set of principles and toolkits, things like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B036SlUSi-z4UkkzYUVGTGdocXc/view&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;feminist chatbot design approach&lt;/a&gt;, to help ourselves achieve third-order change.  How can we get there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edwards, R., &amp;amp; Usher, R. (2007). Globalisation &amp;amp; Pedagogy: Space, Place and Identity. Routledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scardamalia, M., &amp;amp; Bereiter, C. (2008). Pedagogical biases in educational technologies. Educational Technology, 45(3), 3–11.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sterling, S. (2001). Sustainable Education: Re-Visioning Learning and Change. Schumacher Briefings. Green Books for the Schumacher Society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2019-06-04-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2019-06-04-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;光&lt;br /&gt;
看见了&lt;br /&gt;
但不让看啊&lt;br /&gt;
可看见了&lt;br /&gt;
看见了也不能说&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;你看见了吗&lt;br /&gt;
看见了&lt;br /&gt;
可还是要装着没看见&lt;br /&gt;
说不让看&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不让看的人看见了吗&lt;br /&gt;
也看见了吧 应该&lt;br /&gt;
可他装着没看见&lt;br /&gt;
还不让别人看&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;他知道我们看见了吗&lt;br /&gt;
知道&lt;br /&gt;
啊&lt;br /&gt;
不说出就行&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;霓虹灯闪着&lt;br /&gt;
却驱不走黑&lt;br /&gt;
还是怕&lt;br /&gt;
都被困住了&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Verbeek, 2008, Cyborg intentionality: Rethinking the phenomenology of human–technology relations</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/note/2019-05-20-verbeek2008-qt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/note/2019-05-20-verbeek2008-qt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citekey&lt;/strong&gt;: @Verbeek2008-qt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verbeek, P.-P. (2008). Cyborg intentionality: Rethinking the phenomenology of human–technology relations. Phenomenology and the Cognitive Sciences, 7(3), 387–395. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11097-008-9099-x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11097-008-9099-x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Summarize&lt;/em&gt;: An illuminating essay about hybrid intentionality and human&amp;ndash;technology relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly relevant to current thinking on learning analytics. The author has also written on &amp;ldquo;moralizing technology&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;design for socially responsible behavior&amp;rdquo;. Worth checking&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract This article investigates the types of intentionality involved in human– technology relations. It aims to augment Don Ihde’
s analysis of the relations between human beings and technological artifacts, by analyzing a number of concrete examples at the limits of Ihde’
s analysis. The article distinguishes and analyzes three types of “
cyborg intentionality,”
which all involve specific blends of the human and the technological. Technologically mediated intentionality occurs when human intentionality takes place “
through”
technological artifacts; hybrid intentionality occurs when the technological actually merges with the human; and composite intentionality is the addition of human intentionality and the intentionality of technological artifacts.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 1)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A cyborg is a border- blurring entity, uniting both human and nonhuman elements.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 1)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is more, authors like Bernhard
Stiegler argue that we have always been cyborgs in a sense, since technology can be seen as constitutive for humanity. For Stiegler, humanity is an invention of technology, rather than the other way round; human beings exist by realizing themselves technologically (cf. Stiegler 1998).&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In this article, I will use the figure of the cyborg to reconceptualize a specific phenomenon which has long been considered to be exclusively human: the phenomenon of intentionality.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intentionality and technology&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the phenomenological tradition, especially in the existential and embodied directions it took in the work of Jaspers, Heidegger, and Merleau-Ponty, intentionality is the core concept to understand the relation between human beings and their world.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just like human beings can only
be understood from their relation with reality, so can reality only be understood from the relation human beings have with it.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don Ihde has introduced a technological dimension in this phenomenological tradition of understanding human–
world relations. In our technological culture, many of the relations we have with the world around us are either mediated by or directed at technological devices&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mediated intentionality&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ihde (1990) discerns several relationships human beings can have with technological artifacts&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firstly, technologies can be embodied by their users, establishing a relationship between humans and their world&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secondly, technologies can be the terminus of our experience.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A third human –
technology relation is the “
hermeneutic relation.”
In this relation, technologies provide representations of reality, which need interpretation in order to constitute a “
perception”–
like a thermomete&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fourth human –
technology relation Ihde distinguishes, is the background relation, where technologies are not experienced directly, but rather create a context for our perceptions, like the humming of the air conditioning&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intentionality can work through technological artifacts, it can be directed at artifacts and it can even take place against the background of them.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fig. 1 Human–
technology rela- tionships (Ihde 1990)&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiences like reading off a thermometer and having a telephone
conversation, therefore, involve “
cyborg intentionality”–
intentionality that is partly constituted by technology.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intentionality beyond mediation&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I would like to distinguish two other forms of intentionality
related to human–
technology associations. First, I would like to introduce the concept of hybrid intentionality, indicating the intentionality of human–
technology hybrids, in which the human and the technological are merged into a new entity, rather than interrelated, as in Ihde’
s human–
technology relations. And second, I will develop the notion of composite intentionality to indicate situations in which not only human beings have intentionality, but also the technological artifacts they are using.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Because
Ihde’
s primary focus is on the relations between humans and technologies rather than the intentionalities involved, his analysis tends to blackbox the various forms of intentionality involved in these relations.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ihde’
s schematic representations of human–
technology relations do not only contain arrows, indicating intentionality, but also dashes, indicating a relation between entities which is not specified further.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is precisely by investigating the nature of these dashes that a closer characterization can be developed of what can be called “
cyborg intentionality.”&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hybrid intentionality&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a fifth variant could be added to Ihde ’ s&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yet, prior to the embodiment relation there are human–
technology relations in which the human and the technological actually merge rather than “
merely”
being embodied.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(human/technology) →
world&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This fifth human–
technology relation is the basis for what can be called hybrid intentionality. Rather than being a technologically mediated form of human intentionality, this form of intentionality is “
beyond the human.”&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;to distinguish two distinct ways of moving beyond the human&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First of all, a “
posthumanist”
approach can be taken&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;we need
to take into account how the human and the technological co-constitute each other.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second, there is a “
transhumanist”
approach, which does not see human–
technology relations in terms of constitution but in terms of an actual, physical fusion&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter Sloterdijk ’
s analysis of “
anthropotechnol- ogies”
in his infamous lecture&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Composite intentionality&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A third form of cyborg intentionality that deserves a closer analysis, beside its mediated and hybrid variants, can be called composite intentionality. In this case, the intentionalities of technological artifacts themselves play a central role, in cooperation with the intentionalities of the human beings using these artifacts.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don Ihde elaborated the example of the sound recorder as
having a different intentionality for sound than human beings have, recording background noises at a louder volume than perceived by human beings who only focus on the sounds that are meaningful to them in that specific situation (Ihde 1979: 77–
78; Ihde 1983:56;Ihde1990:102–
103).&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;is added to human intentionality, composite intentionality comes about: a form of intentionality which results from adding technological intentionality and human intentionality.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ermeneutic relations always involve a technologically generated
representation of the world, which inevitably is the product of a specific technological directedness at the world: thermometers focus on temperature, spectrographs on light frequencies, sonograms on how material objects reflect ultrasound.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The concept of composite intentionality, therefore, urges us to augment Ihde’ s analysis of the hermeneutic relation. There is a double intentionality involved here; one of technology toward “
its”
world, and one of human beings toward the result of this technological intentionality. In other words: humans are directed here at the ways in which a technology is directed at the world.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The night photographs of Wouter Hooijmans embody the “
mildest”
form of composite intentionality. Hooijmans makes landscape photographs using shutter times of several hours. This allows him to make use of starlight for exposing his pictures, which has stunning effects&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hooijmans’
s photographs embody an extreme mechanical makeover of the intentionality of the human vision. Contrary to the most common use of the photo camera, Hooijmans does not create instantaneous exposures, but rather “
sustained exposures.”
His photographs blend together an infinite number of visual impressions into one single representation of the world, which the human eye could never produce itself. We could call this form of composite intentionality “
augmented intentionality,”
since it consists in making accessible to the human eye an artificially expanded form of human intentionality.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These photographs do not aim to represent reality in any sense, but to generate a new reality which can only exist for human intentionality when it is complemented with technological intentionality.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The “
intentionality” that De Realisten gave to their stereographic camera is not directed at making visible an existing reality but at constructing a new reality. For this reason, the intentionality involved here can be called “
constructive intentionality.”&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intentionality used to be one of
these concepts which belonged to the realm of the exclusively human, but by now it has become clear that it needs to be extended to the realm of technology –
and to the realm of human–
technology amalgams&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By re-articulating phenomenological and philosophical – anthropological concepts philosophers can contribute to a better understanding of the “
posthuman”
or perhaps even “
transhuiman”
beings we are becoming –
and to the development of a better sense of the limits of humanity.&lt;/strong&gt; (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating Collaborative Learning in a Teacher Professional Development MOOC</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-aera-mooc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-aera-mooc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IdeaMagnets: Towards Knowledge Building on the Open Web</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-ideamagnets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-ideamagnets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teachers as Co-designers of a Knowledge Building Environment</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-teacher/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hickey2017</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/note/2019-04-05-hickey2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/note/2019-04-05-hickey2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citekey&lt;/strong&gt;: @Hickey2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Summarize&lt;/em&gt;: This chapter introduces the Participatory Learning and Assessment (PLA) framework derived by Dan Hickey and his team in the &amp;ldquo;BOOC&amp;rdquo; context. PLA distinguishes different kinds of interactions that include public, local, private, and discreet.  It explains PLA&amp;rsquo;s five design principles, which draw inspiration from &lt;em&gt;productive disciplinary engagement&lt;/em&gt; (PDE).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Public Contexts to Give Meaning to Knowledge Tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize and Reward Productive Disciplinary Engagement (PDE)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate/Grade Artifacts through Local Endorsements and Reflections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assess Individual Knowledge Privately&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measure Aggregated Achievement Discreetly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They commened that scaling should be done gradually and iteratively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assess&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reflect&lt;/em&gt;: The BOOC project is inspirational. The distinction made among public/local/private interactions are congruent with my thinking on (public) online pedagogy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two references I plan to check out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some observers had already commented on the difficulty of connecting with other learners in the cMOOCs (Mackness, Mack, and Williams 2010). It turned out that supporting social interaction in the xMOOCs was proving much harder. (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the “myths and paradoxes” of xMOOCs (Daniel 2012). These included number of students taught (but single-digit completion rates), value (dubious certificates of completion), purpose (disregard for outcomes and focus on posturing and profits rather than spreading learning), pedagogy (essentially behaviorism), access (mostly serving elites), and risks (MOOCs as degree mills). (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chapter summarizes one ongoing effort that is intended to inform the entire range of efforts to scale open learning. (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructionist approaches are rooted in a more “associationist” perspective on learning (e.g., Anderson 1990; Gagné 1985) which assumes that higher order knowledge can and should be broken down into smaller elements that can be individually learned, mastered, and assessed.1 This perspective is explicitly manifested in artificially intelligent tutors, like those associated with Carnegie Mellon University (Koedinger and Corbett 2006) and competency-based education (Bramante and Colby 2012) (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, constructivist approaches are rooted in more “rationalist” views of learning (e.g., Glaser 1984) that emphasize the construction of higher-level conceptual schema that learners create to make sense of the world (rather than by assembling numerous smaller associations). (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;constructivist approaches can be very difficult to scale. This is because both the people who design a course and then the instructors and facilitators who teach that course need a lot of TPCK (technological pedagogical content knowledge; Koehler and Mishra 2008) concerning the way that disciplinary knowledge can optimally unfold within the particular technology. In many settings this knowledge will be in very short supply, very expensive, or both. (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participatory Learning and Assessment (PLA) (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflecting a continued focus on participation in sociocultural practices, the larger framework that these principles formed was deemed Participatory Learning and Assessment (PLA). (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;drew significant inspiration from three strands of research that extended situative theories of learning into the era of digital knowledge networks. Two of these were Henry Jenkins’s (2009) notion of online “participatory culture” and studies by Ito et al. (2009) of the way young people “geek out” in interest-driven social networks. (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What distinguishes the PLA framework that emerged from these two courses were online strategies for delivering useful evidence that could be used to enhance participation, individual knowledge, and group achievement, without undermining any of them, and without compromising that evidence for making claims about the resulting knowledge or achievement. (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research and Development Context (p. 9)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google offered grants to faculty for developing MOOCs that were “more interactive than typical MOOCs.” (p. 9)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing on Hall and Rubin’s (1989) study of situated learning in mathematics classrooms, the principles distinguish between interactions that are public (presented to every member of the class and potentially beyond), local (in public but between specific peers and/or the instructor), or private (between individuals). A fourth kind of interaction, discreet (i.e., unobtrusive), was added to highlight the core PLA assumption that conventional achievement tests should be used judiciously and inconspicuously. (p. 10)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;draw inspiration from Engle and Conant’s (2002) notions of productive disciplinary engagement (PDE). (p. 10)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the “multilevel” assessment model (p. 10)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Public Contexts to Give Meaning to Knowledge Tools (p. 10)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.1 Personalized learning contexts. In the Assessment BOOC, registrants were directed through a process that asked them questions about their actual or aspirational role in the education system and helped them draft a curricular aim that embodied their practices in that role to personalize their learning in the course. (p. 11)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.2 Networking groups. Registration information regarding primary academic domain and role was used to organize students into networking groups (manually in 2013 and automatically in 2014). Doing so structured local interactions with both similar and different peers and revealed how course content interacted with domains and roles. (p. 11)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;discussion forums were not used for group interaction (p. 12)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.3 Public course artifacts. (p. 12)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, all the BOOC assignments consisted of public (to the class) wikifolios that focused primarily on disciplinary practices. (p. 12)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.4 Relevance ranking. (p. 13)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;students rank the relevance of elements of disciplinary knowledge or disciplinary resources to their aim and/or role, and then justify that ranking. (p. 13)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.5 Personalized open educational resources (OERs). (p. 13)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the BOOC, students posted OER URLs in their wikifolios; the annotated URLs were then automatically placed all together on a separate page, where students could easily review them. (p. 13)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.6 Streaming instructor videos. (p. 13)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize and Reward Productive Disciplinary Engagement (PDE) (p. 14)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.2 Engagement reflections. (p. 19)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;students were instructed to reflect on their contextual engagement (“How suitable was your context for learning this knowledge?”), collaborative engagement (“Who else’s work and whose comments helped you learn this new knowledge?”), and consequential engagement (“What will you do differently in your context and beyond as a consequence of learning this knowledge?”). (p. 19)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assess Individual Knowledge Privately (p. 20)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Findings, Next Steps, and Conclusions (p. 22)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first conclusion is that scaling should be done gradually. To quickly scale up to massive numbers of users, most MOOCs and MOOC platforms were forced to sacrifice interaction and personalization (p. 23)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our second conclusion is that scaling should be done iteratively. Our efforts were directly shaped by newer design-based research methods that emphasize the development of “local” theories in the context of reform efforts (Cobb et al. 2003). Furthermore, we conclude that such iterative refinements should be done within a coherent theoretical framework. (p. 23)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we conclude that the PLA framework seems generally useful for guiding efforts to scale learning. (p. 23)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this framework can also “scale out” to large numbers of teachers in conventional online classes. (p. 24)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hickey, Daniel, Gita Taasoobshirazi, and Dionne Cross. 2012. “Assessment as Learning: Enhancing Discourse, Understanding, and Achievement in Innovative Science Curricula.” Journal of Research in Science Teaching 49 (10): 1240–70. (p. 26)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hickey, Daniel, and Steven J. Zuiker. 2012. “Multilevel Assessment for Discourse, Understanding, and Achievement.” Journal of the Learning Sciences 21 (4): 522–82. (p. 26)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is about timing: Network prestige in asynchronous online discussions</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-mu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 21:08:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-mu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate for Whom?</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-03-14-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 13:57:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-03-14-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working at a large public R1 university long enough &amp;ndash; 4 years &amp;ndash; to witness steady changes with technology installed in public restrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a newly installed automatic paper towel dispenser in our office building. As someone who tends to use 1 paper towel, I was very frustrated by the design that doesn&amp;rsquo;t keep me &amp;ndash; a user &amp;ndash; in the loop and forces me to use that much paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;automatic-towel-dispenser.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a picture of a fancy hand wash station I saw during last week&amp;rsquo;s conference travel. It neatly integrates a soap dispenser, a water tap, and a hand dryer together. There are at least three sensors built in this integrated system. It&amp;rsquo;s probably based on a zero-paper consumption philosophy, and has fundamentally transformed one&amp;rsquo;s hand-washing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;hand-wash-station.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to wonder: &lt;strong&gt;Whom does automation &amp;ndash; and an integrated automation system &amp;ndash; serve? Whom did the designers have in mind when designing these products?&lt;/strong&gt;  And finally, &lt;strong&gt;what lessons we can learn as designers of learning systems&lt;/strong&gt; (or using a new fancy title, as &lt;strong&gt;learning engineers&lt;/strong&gt;)?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#LAK19 Conference Report [Part 2]: Main Conference</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-03-08-lak19-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 21:45:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-03-08-lak19-part2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;(This is the second part of a report of the #LAK19 conference. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-03-08-lak19-part1/&#34;&gt;Part 1 here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the only beginning of many fun conversations when the Main Conference kicked off on Wednesday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our conference and program chairs delivered an exciting welcome message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LAK is becoming larger,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Largest LAK ever &amp;amp; 60% attendees are 1st timers! - shared by conference chair &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/shoha99?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@shoha99&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/k7C02NGWol&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/k7C02NGWol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bodong Chen (@bod0ng) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng/status/1103323756661882882?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 6, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but still selective &amp;ndash; with a 33% acceptance rate for Full and Short papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LAK is international &amp;ndash; given representation and collaboration patterns. And interdisciplinary &amp;ndash; based on which publication sources we cite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;International collaboration and interdisciplinarity are in the genes of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK&lt;/a&gt; community &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/xK1ZwCMuqK&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/xK1ZwCMuqK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bodong Chen (@bod0ng) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng/status/1103326619362455552?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 6, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See their &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1DBDxkoW7WdcCLxM6kpR5M6S7Nw-9sHiH9PAbFpXKmig/edit?usp=sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; for more detailed information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keynotes-1-and-2&#34;&gt;Keynotes 1 and 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a young family, I could only stay till Thursday and had to miss the third keynote by  &lt;strong&gt;Shirley Alexander&lt;/strong&gt; (Professor &amp;amp; Deputy Vice-Chancellor, University of Technology Sydney, Australia) on how to nurture a &lt;em&gt;Data-Intensive University&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-cards=&#34;hidden&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The final &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; keynote with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SAlexander_UTS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@SAlexander_UTS&lt;/a&gt; on building a data intensive university, the talk today outlines a field guide. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Watch now at &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/IadDaNy8mA&#34;&gt;https://t.co/IadDaNy8mA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; LAK19 (@lak19asu) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lak19asu/status/1104054595704127488?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 8, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; --&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other two keynotes were delivered by &lt;strong&gt;Ryan Baker&lt;/strong&gt; (UPenn) and &lt;strong&gt;Lise Getoor&lt;/strong&gt; (UC Santa Cruz). I am reviewing these two keynotes together because they were both slightly more technical (compared by the third keynote by Alexander) and both about addressing challenges in building models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan Baker is the founding president of the international society of Educational Data Mining (EDM), a sister community of learning analytics. His talk was focused on six important challenges faced by both EDM and learning analytics. As a keynote it almost sets a future research agenda for the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;First keynote at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BakerEDMLab?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@BakerEDMLab&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/EkrAAOA6qv&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/EkrAAOA6qv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sweet San Pedro (@sweetsp) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sweetsp/status/1103330050059857920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 6, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Challenges set by ⁦&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BakerEDMLab?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@BakerEDMLab&lt;/a&gt;⁩ &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/lak19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#lak19&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/na9aBhwwCa&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/na9aBhwwCa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bodong Chen (@bod0ng) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng/status/1103337235158429696?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 6, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Predictive models&lt;/em&gt; has been a trending topic in the community even though prediction is only one of those five EDM techniques outlined by &lt;a href=&#34;https://jedm.educationaldatamining.org/index.php/JEDM/article/view/8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Baker and Yacef (2009)&lt;/a&gt; (see also &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0002764213498851?journalCode=absb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Siemens, 2013&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciated Ryan&amp;rsquo;s keynote because it pointed out a few acute problems with our current research and practice. We build models and analytics facing a serious constraint &amp;ndash; the &amp;lsquo;learning system wall&amp;rsquo; problem (&lt;strong&gt;Challenge #1&lt;/strong&gt;). Learning analytics systems we build are not making lasting impact on student lives (&lt;strong&gt;Challenge #2&lt;/strong&gt;). Findings from models are not necessarily interpretable (&lt;strong&gt;Challenge #3&lt;/strong&gt;). We are less confident in detecting student learning in real-world scenarios (say, not in front of a computer) (&lt;strong&gt;Challenge #4&lt;/strong&gt;). Our models are not generalizable across contexts (&lt;strong&gt;Challenge #5&lt;/strong&gt;). Our models are not general either &amp;ndash; not built for a non-typical population (e.g. high school dropouts, Alaska students) (&lt;strong&gt;Challenge #6&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These important challenges are closely aligned with LAK19&amp;rsquo;s theme, &lt;em&gt;Promoting Inclusion and Access&lt;/em&gt;, and vital for the long-term legitimacy of this field. Framing them in technical terms was intended to help us find practical solutions. But I started to feel less optimistic about addressing them within the next 18 years when considering the complex political, ethical, socio-technical, theoretical terrain facing these challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Note: Expect Ryan to share more details about these challenges via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BakerEDMLab&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; soon.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second keynote by Prof. &lt;strong&gt;Lise Getoor&lt;/strong&gt; was focused on &lt;em&gt;Collective Reasoning&lt;/em&gt; as a key challenge in data mining and machine learning. She first called attention to structures in data and critiqued the widespread practice of flattening rich behavioral data into tables. Starting from this recognition, she highlighted that all decisions are structured and argued we should use multimodal, multi-relational, spatio-temporal features of data when making decisions, instead of flattening data and discarding relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getoor went further to explain Collective Reasoning and suggested constructing logial rules &amp;ndash; many of them &amp;ndash; to further support reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;.⁦&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lgetoor?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@lgetoor&lt;/a&gt;⁩ speaks about the challenge of achieving Collective Reasoning! &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/lak19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#lak19&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/fH7DzjMh8D&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/fH7DzjMh8D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bodong Chen (@bod0ng) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng/status/1103688260641972224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 7, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her group developed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://psl.linqs.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probabilistic soft logic (PSL)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; framework and toolkit for building probabilistic models. She then went ahead to introduce the application of PSL in a wide range of problem spaces (including MOOC discussion forums).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Second keynote at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lgetoor?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@lgetoor&lt;/a&gt; presenting her approach named Probabilistic Soft Logic for &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/machinelearning?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#machinelearning&lt;/a&gt; to deal with relations, inconsistencies and inference. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/fsNo64swLx&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/fsNo64swLx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daniele Di Mitri (@dimstudi0) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dimstudi0/status/1103693761589067776?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 7, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issues discussed by Getoor spoke to my heart. In the learning sciences, we&amp;rsquo;ve been criticizing the practice of coding-and-counting approach. While part of my research has been trying to cast light on micro-temporal dynamics in learning processes, I am also interested in maintaining the complexity of learning data intact when conducting data analysis. The keynote itself did not provide more details about Probabilistic Soft Logic (PSL), given the time limit, so I look forward to digging into the PSL framework and tools later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-sciences-panel&#34;&gt;Learning Sciences Panel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, I moderated a Learning Sciences panel featuring Ryan Baker, Nancy Law (University of Hong Kong), Phil Winne (Simon Fraser University), and Alyssa Wise (New York University). We were charged to inspire the audience with &amp;ldquo;Design and analysis strategies that promote inclusion and increase access&amp;rdquo;. While all of our panelists had very wise things to say, we all concurred we need more expertise represented in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@bod0ng&lt;/a&gt; Important observation about how learning science&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt; have gone far to help elucidate the political and material conditions affecting learning and what is valued about what we measure in &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LearningAnalytics?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LearningAnalytics&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Robin Pappas (@RobinPappas1) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/RobinPappas1/status/1103361698709164032?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 6, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the end of the session, one of this year&amp;rsquo;s Doctoral Consortium participants Catherine Manly (UM-Amherst) mentioned her work on Universal Design for Learning. We need more work like this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;It&amp;#39;s exciting to have my dissertation work recognized by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; Doctoral Consortium! &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/imn52QpD0E&#34;&gt;https://t.co/imn52QpD0E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Catherine Manly (@c_manly) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/c_manly/status/1096210546888769537?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 15, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sessions-on-text-discourse-design-ethics&#34;&gt;Sessions on Text &amp;amp; Discourse, Design, Ethics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of my conference participation was a bit disjointed. Besides my own presentation on &lt;em&gt;Value Sensitive Design&lt;/em&gt;, I was only able to attend a few sessions on &lt;em&gt;Ethics&lt;/em&gt; (which I chaired), &lt;em&gt;Dialogue &amp;amp; Engagement&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Reading Analytics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many sessions I wished to attend. And I missed an important talk on &lt;a href=&#34;https://dl-acm-org.ezp1.lib.umn.edu/citation.cfm?id=3303784&amp;amp;dl=ACM&amp;amp;coll=DL&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the impact of learning analytics&lt;/a&gt;, by Shane Dowson and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;analysis of 522 papers thus far in#LAK: simplification, techno-centric, case studies, exploratory&amp;hellip; similar trends in the last several years.. where is learning optimisation? how do we move the field forward in education as a complex system &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/shaned07?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@shaned07&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/s_joksimovic?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@s_joksimovic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/lak19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#lak19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Sasha (@choux) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/choux/status/1104081335784599554?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 8, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3303772&amp;amp;picked=prox&amp;amp;preflayout=tabs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the conference proceedings&lt;/a&gt; are nicely organized by sessions for us to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slides of my talk on &lt;strong&gt;Towards Value-Sensitive Learning Analytics Design&lt;/strong&gt; can be found below. I am excited about this direction!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/uaJEb1QKL12xpa&#34; width=&#34;595&#34; height=&#34;485&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style=&#34;margin-bottom:5px&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/dirkchen/lak19-towards-valuesensitive-learning-analytics-design&#34; title=&#34;LAK19 - Towards Value-Sensitive Learning Analytics Design&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LAK19 - Towards Value-Sensitive Learning Analytics Design&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-ahead&#34;&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a great LAK!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given it will be LAK&amp;rsquo;s 10th anniversary, I do wonder how much this community has achieved and what needs to be down in the next 5 or 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;below-i-offer-my-own-list-of-challenges&#34;&gt;Below I offer my own list of challenges:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work with the larger system&lt;/strong&gt;. While we&amp;rsquo;re doing detailed, careful work, it is important to make sure our work is contributing to the betterment of the larger education system. We need to connect models with design, and with feedback. We need to engage more voices in our work. We need to look at choice-making by learners besides knowledge acquisition. We need to connect learning that&amp;rsquo;s life-wide and lifelong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move towards knowledge convergence&lt;/strong&gt;. While we can do all sorts of cool analyses on all sorts of interesting data, we need to be an even better job on understanding learning in richer contexts. How can we put advances from multiple analytical perspectives together?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on impact&lt;/strong&gt;. While there are convincing cases of data-rich educational practices, we need to invest more in studying acceptance and impact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Include one keynote speaker from a &amp;ldquo;non-&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apa.org/monitor/2010/05/weird&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WEIRD&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; country each year&lt;/strong&gt;. While the society has been doing an amazing job on equity and inclusion, I would like to see a stronger representation from the Global South in the next 10 years. Ensuring voices from &amp;ldquo;non-WEIRD&amp;rdquo; countries could be a good start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lak20.solaresearch.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/lak2020-banner-no-affiliations-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look forward to seeing you at &lt;a href=&#34;https://lak20.solaresearch.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LAK &amp;lsquo;20&lt;/a&gt; in Frankfurt, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#LAK19 Conference Report [Part 1]: Pre-Conference Workshops</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-03-08-lak19-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 21:45:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-03-08-lak19-part1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I just came back from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lak19.solaresearch.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2019 &lt;em&gt;Learning Analytics and Knowledge (LAK)&lt;/em&gt; conference&lt;/a&gt; hosted by Arizona State University. This conference, surely one of my favorites, is inching to its 10th anniversary next year. I still remember when I was in the 2nd year of my PhD in 2010, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.si.umich.edu/people/chris-teplovs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chris Teplovs&lt;/a&gt; told me about &lt;a href=&#34;https://tekri.athabascau.ca/analytics/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an exciting, upcoming gathering&lt;/a&gt; of 60~ people in Banff, Canada to discuss a thing called &amp;ldquo;learning analytics.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After nearly a decade of development, we see clear progress this community has accomplished. The growth of the conference size itself, from 60 to  500+ attendees, while impressive, does not speak to the international sensation around this topic. As someone who first attended LAK as a doctoral student in 2014 and now work on a tenure-track position to grow this area at my institution, I can speak to my lived experiences of observing the rise of local interests in this topic (e.g., the &amp;ldquo;R1&amp;rdquo; university I&amp;rsquo;m part of, the state&amp;rsquo;s Department of Education), as well as an international passion for learning analytics when I travel to Singapore, Manila, and Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rise of learning analytics (the field), LAK (its conference) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://solaresearch.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SoLAR&lt;/a&gt; (its society), coincides with many other things. In education, there is a push for &amp;ldquo;evidence-based practice&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;data use&amp;rdquo; in schools (however we mean by evidence or data). In EdTech, words like A.I., adaptive learning, personalization are mentioned in board rooms, websites of philanthropist foundations, and news headlines. Of course, an earlier surge of MOOCs and an ongoing rise of online, lifelong learning demand analytic supports while also offering fertile grounds for learning analytics to grow. In many cases, learning analytics are truly needed and making impossible things possible. But in others, it&amp;rsquo;s scooped up to be a tag on a product to drive sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realities, for better or worse, just like many other fields we can think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overall-impression-of-lak19&#34;&gt;Overall impression of LAK19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, many thanks to the amazing organizing team who has done a wonderful job to make everything real and enjoyable! The program is cohesively organized; conference amenities are thoughtfully arranged; student volunteers are kind and amazingly helpful. These are on top of myself escaping -30C weather in Minnesota for the 20C dessert temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; Defrosting in progress. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/C1lPgc52XE&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/C1lPgc52XE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bodong Chen (@bod0ng) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng/status/1102575805559758849?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 4, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the community grows bigger, I always found multiple concurrent sessions/talks I hoped to check out. So my impression and report of this conference are surely biased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday-full-day-workshop-on-connectivism&#34;&gt;Monday: Full-Day Workshop on Connectivism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to this workshops mainly for jokes among Canadians, Aussies, and Serbians :). I was sorted of disappointed because &lt;a href=&#34;https://vitomir.kovanovic.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vita&lt;/a&gt; was clearly jet-lagged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jokes aside, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Connectivism&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Connectivism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, George Siemens, and Stephen Downes for years. Many ideas under Connectivism resonate with me, as a big part of my research is grounded in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_building&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Knowledge-Building Community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; model created by Scardamalia and Bereiter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George kicked off the workshop by briefly explaining its 15-year history. Connectivism emerged in the early stage of the Read/Write web (Web 2.0) and grew out of a dissatisfaction with existing frameworks of learning that were not very helpful in explaining the construction of &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo; knowledge in a networked world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core arguments made by Connectivism are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge is networked&lt;/strong&gt;. This idea is in line with works from Rosen (2012), combinatorial creativity, Nielsen (2013), and Borner (network of science).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning is the process of developing those networks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These two ideas apply beyond learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this workshop, George challenged us to work on &lt;strong&gt;three domains where learning is networked: Neural; Cognitive/Conceptual; and Social/External&lt;/strong&gt;. Future work on Connectivism should try to deliver quality empirical research about networks of learning at these levels, detail how things fit together, integrate networks across levels, and articulate human and artificial cognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critiques of Connectivism as a learning theory were mentioned for multiple times. It&amp;rsquo;s probably accurate to say George found these critiques fair and highlighted that Connectivism meant to provide a framework (or paradigm) to think about knowledge and learning in a fresh way. There is a vast empty space left by Connectivism, including pedagogy, learning analytics, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Downes joined the workshop remotely and shared a very informative review* of recent work on connectivism. His review looked at scholars&amp;rsquo; various interpretations of connectivism, criticisms, connectivism as pedagogy (e.g., &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irrodl.org/index.php/irrodl/article/view/3269&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wang, Anderson, &amp;amp; Chen 2018&lt;/a&gt;), connectivism as a theory of learning, and properties of a successful network. He offered a number of future directions, including critical thinking and deep learning (not the ML sense), rhizomatic learning, social networking, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/303894484_What_Are_Cognitive_Cities&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cognitive cities&lt;/a&gt;. Listening to such a review from one of the creators was helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(*: &lt;em&gt;As a strong advocate of open scholarship, Stephen may have chosen to focus this review on open-access publications.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming into this workshop, I was looking for two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conceptually, I was wondering why many research papers on cMOOCs used frameworks such as the &lt;em&gt;Community of Inquiry&lt;/em&gt; to examine connectivist learning instead of connectivism itself. I was curious about further articulation of connectivism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In terms of design &amp;ndash; of both connectivist learning environments and analytics &amp;ndash; I was looking for design principles and design ideas to inform some of our ongoing projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Four principles&lt;/strong&gt; of connectivism Stephen laid out later was quite useful. These principles include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomy&lt;/strong&gt; of learners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diversity&lt;/strong&gt; of learners, ideas, information, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Openness&lt;/strong&gt; of the environment and process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactivity&lt;/strong&gt; within the network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found these principles valuable even though more work is needed to further unpack and articulate them. Stephen predicted a shift is going to happen (if not yet) even if it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily tagged with connectivism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the workshop, there were several interesting research talks as well, including analyzing group communication (Nia Dowell), assessing idea development using &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compartmental_models_in_epidemiology&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;epidemiological modeling&lt;/a&gt; (Sasank Peri), and modeling network dynamics (Renzhe Yu). They represented promising directions to further advance connectivism, especially in the areas of analyzing connective learning processes and developing automated indices about connective learning. &lt;a href=&#34;http://sjoksimovic.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Srećko Joksimović&lt;/a&gt; also presented findings from an ongoing bibliometric study of the connectivism literature. More details can be found on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://connectivism.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;workshop website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I very much appreciated the multi-level network view laid out by George and his urge for us to connect levels. These ideas are informative for my recent thinking, tinkering, and design (since 2017) to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Represent, describe, and model learning (at multiple levels) as complex networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design tools for &lt;em&gt;personal, connectivist learning&lt;/em&gt; that give learners agency to maintain their networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brainstorm an analytical infrastructure that maintains complexity of all sorts of learning processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attending this workshop was a treat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday-workshop-on-fairness&#34;&gt;Tuesday: Workshop on Fairness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an honor to give an invited talk about &lt;em&gt;Value-Sensitive Design&lt;/em&gt; in learning analytics at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/fairlak&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FairLAK workshop&lt;/a&gt; organized by Kenneth Holstein and Shayan Doroudi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a timely workshop that deals with a topic that&amp;rsquo;s critical for our work in this community and beyond. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know there are 21 fairness definitions (Narayanan, 2018; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jIXIuYdnyyk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Youtube video&lt;/a&gt;). During my limited time spent at the workshop, it is refreshing to see multiple approaches to considering fairness, ranging from creating new metric based on slice analysis to evaluate fairness in predictive models (Josh Gardner), to applying the Socio-Technical Integration Research approach to design processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program and slides of the FairLAK workshop can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/fairlak&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;its website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday-workshop-on-curriculum-development-in-la-programs&#34;&gt;Tuesday: Workshop on Curriculum Development in LA Programs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephanie Teasley and John Stamper asked me to stop by another workshop about curriculum development in learning analytics. It was half-way through after coming from the FairLAK workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charles Lang and Leah Macfadyen showed us their informative reviews of degree programs related to learning analytics. John Stamper showed us &lt;a href=&#34;https://hcii.cmu.edu/masters-educational-technology-and-applied-learning-science-program-overview&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CMU&amp;rsquo;s Master&amp;rsquo;s Educational Technology and Applied Learning Science program&lt;/a&gt; that interestingly integrates courses from different disciplines and connects deeply with the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following Charles&amp;rsquo; lead, we even got a chance to co-design a class activity to engage students to consider and experience themselves as data &lt;em&gt;producers&lt;/em&gt;, data &lt;em&gt;analysts&lt;/em&gt;, and analytics &lt;em&gt;consumers&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;I believe nurturing criticality in all course of a learning analytics program is critical.&lt;/strong&gt; Interesting activities like this could be very helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed collectively mapping out a learning analytics curriculum. Workshop leaders will be working on compiling a list of courses and syllabi to be shared on the SoLAR website. I look forward to being part of this important work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-pre-conference-workshops&#34;&gt;Other Pre-Conference Workshops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many interesting workshops happening at LAK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Writing Analytics workshop&lt;/strong&gt; has generously shared &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1cwd90hDVQgDwK_wODCfuA7SXti9pufjWIGU1cV_gDCU/edit#heading=h.lq1iijue859q&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;their notes&lt;/a&gt; that I look forward to dig into. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MladenRakovic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mladen Rakovic&lt;/a&gt; from SFU channeled some &amp;ldquo;knowledge telling vs. knowledge transforming&amp;rdquo; wisdom (Bereiter &amp;amp; Scardamalia) I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Writing analytics for helping students move from knowledge telling to knowledge transforming in writing &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/WaLAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#WaLAK19&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MladenRakovic?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@MladenRakovic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/TIb20hWbRl&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/TIb20hWbRl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Shibani Antonette (@ShibaniAntonett) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ShibaniAntonett/status/1102637203748876288?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 4, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Doctoral Consortium seemed to be going strong as well! I chatted with a couple of student participants during the conference. I&amp;rsquo;m sure they received great advice from this panel (see below). As you may find out from an upcoming SoLAR 10-year anniversary video, I feel in indebted to this community especially because it has been so invested in emerging scholars. Way to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; Doctoral Consortium careers panel with special guests  ⁦&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aekrumm?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@aekrumm&lt;/a&gt;⁩ &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sasha?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@sasha&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/whitmer?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@whitmer&lt;/a&gt; joining the co-chairs to share the pros and cons of future trajectories After The PhD&amp;hellip;! &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/RheoO3IOH2&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/RheoO3IOH2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Simon Buckingham Shum (@sbuckshum) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sbuckshum/status/1103071063141838848?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 5, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue to read &lt;a href=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-03-08-lak19-part2/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the conference report.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Value-Sensitive Learning Analytics Design</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 21:08:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-lak/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing for Networked Collaborative Discourse: An UnLMSApproach</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-tw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-tw/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Value-Sensitive Learning Analytics Design</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-lak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the slides.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Cress2013-av</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/note/2018-12-27-cress2013-av/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/note/2018-12-27-cress2013-av/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citekey&lt;/strong&gt;: @Cress2013-av&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cress, U., Barron, B., Fischer, G., Halatchliyski, I., &amp;amp; Resnick, M. (2013). Mass collaboration - An emerging field for CSCL research. In CSCL Proceedings (Vol. 1, pp. 557–563).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Summarize&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assess&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reflect&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The participants in such communities are not just a mass of learning individuals or passive consumers; they actively produce meaningful content and act as “prosumers” (O’Reilly, 2006; Tapscott &amp;amp; Williams, 2006). (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the symposium on long-tail learning at the CSCL conference in 2009 (Brown &amp;amp; Adler, 2008; Collins, et al 2009) (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In sum, the aim of the symposium is threefold: (1) to establish the concept of mass collaboration as a relevant topic of CSCL (2) to present and interconnect existing research on the subject, and (3) to give prototypical examples of learning communities and mass collaboration platforms (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas CSCL in its early times mainly dealt with synchronous small group or classroom-settings, currently, CSCL research faces a much broader range of real-life situations, where people take part in decentralized communities, act asynchronously and do not necessarily all come to a shared conception of a problem. (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;shared conception of a problem. In fact, complex knowledge phenomena involve long periods of time, large and changing numbers of people, and fuzzy-structured settings. (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSCL research is just starting to address this global level of human learning and creation of knowledge (Kafai &amp;amp; Peppler, 2011; Collins et al, 2009). (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artifacts as Mediators of Mass Collaboration (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the more so when the process is collaborative and fulfills the conditions that individuals act consciously following a common direction; that they take the perspective of the other participants into account; and that they contribute by building on the accomplishments of others. (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution to the coordination problem resides in artifacts that support the collaborative process by mediating common understanding (Bruner, 1996). (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaborative artifacts represent crystallized knowledge that is preserved from past interactive situations and that can be built on in future to produce phenomena like scientific understanding, social practices or social norms (Engeström &amp;amp; Sannino, 2010; Paavola, Lipponen &amp;amp; Hakkareinen, 2004). (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An artifact is a means to an end (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;learning and knowledge creation in a collaborative setting are one continuous process of internalization and externalization (Nonaka &amp;amp; Takeuchi, 1995; Vygotsky, 1978). (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “learning” of a community and the learning of the participating individuals are intertwined and suggest a systemic understanding of mass collaboration (Cress &amp;amp; Kimmerle, 2008). (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mass Collaboration Environments (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Wikipedia has emerged as a self-organized community, a lot of mass collaboration platforms have been deliberately designed to support learning. (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third example of a mass collaboration environment in this symposium is Citizen Science (presentation by Brigid Barron). (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the Co-Evolution Model of Individual Learning and Collaborative Knowledge Building (Cress &amp;amp; Kimmerle, 2008) serves as a systemic framework for describing and analyzing mass collaboration. (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presentation 1: Cultures of Participation — Fundamental Transformations of Learning, Working, and Collaborating (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a world in which everyone would be able to actively participate following their own interests and to make their voices heard. (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presentation 2: The Co-Evolution Model as a Theoretical Framework for Describing Mass Collaboration (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model describes individuals as cognitive systems, who externalize their knowledge into an artifact. The community deals with the individuals’ contributions by interlinking, revising or even deleting them. (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aileen Oeberst will present a study of the development of the Wikipedia article about the nuclear power plant in Fukushima during the first nine days after the nuclear disaster on March 11, 2011. (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their activities and coordination were only mediated by Wikipedia’s norms, that valuable and thus accepted contribution should be verifiable and written from a neutral point of view. This norm effectively shaped individuals’ edits and enabled authors without much domain expertise to construct an article, which nuclear experts judged to be of high quality. (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iassen Halatchlyiski will present an approach to studying mass collaboration that can encompass large-scale and long-term characteristics: the macro level of the phenomenon (Halatchliyski, Moskaliuk, Kimmerle &amp;amp; Cress, 2010). His study deals with pivotal knowledge within Wikipedia. He asks (1) what pivotal knowledge in Wikipedia is, and (2) who its authors are. (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;he operationalizes “pivotal knowledge” as articles with a central position at the macro level and distinguishes two types of pivotal knowledge: knowledge that is central within a single domain or knowledge that relates two different domains and resides at the border between them. The presentation shows that social network analysis (SNA) is an appropriate methodological approach to go about the complex large-scale and long-term patterns of creation of pivotal knowledge. (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presentation 3: Large-Scale Collaboration and Cultures of Accountability (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presentation 4: Learning through Remixing Mitchel Resnick (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presentation 5: Long-tail learning and access to external resources Brigid Barron and Caitlin Martin from Stanford University will report findings from a study of a genre of cyber-enabled massively collaborative activity known as Citizen Science. Citizen Science projects capitalize on the interest and efforts of non-scientist collaborators who join forces to contribute data that helps address problems of concern. (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chose to study a Citizen Science project with a significant focus on education called Vital Signs. Vital Signs is a citizen science networked system located in the state of Maine, linked statewide to schools and accessible not only to teachers but to anyone who want to learn. (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collins, A., Fischer, G., Barron, B., Liu, C., &amp;amp; Spada, H. (2009). Long-Tail Learning: A Unique Opportunity for CSCL? In C. O&amp;rsquo;Malley, D. Suthers, P. Reimann, A. Dimitracopoulou (Eds.), Computer Supported Collaborative Learning Practices: CSCL2009 Conference Proceedings (Vol. II, 22-24). Rhodes, Greece: International Society of the Learning Sciences. (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Mattarelli2018-mn</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/note/2018-11-10-mattarelli2018-mn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/note/2018-11-10-mattarelli2018-mn/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citekey&lt;/strong&gt;: @Mattarelli2018-mn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mattarelli, E., Schecter, A., Hinds, P., Contractor, N., Lu, C., &amp;amp; Topac, B. (2018). How Co-creation Processes Unfold and Predict Submission Quality in Crowd-based Open Innovation. Presented at the Thirty Ninth International Conference on Information Systems, San Francisco, CA: aisel.aisnet.org. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1042&amp;amp;context=icis2018&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1042&amp;amp;context=icis2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Summarize&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assess&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reflect&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In crowd-based open innovation, organizations generally invite novel contributions from outside the boundaries of the firm via an online platform that enables a large, diverse network of contributors to participate. (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;only a few studies have started to address how work is coordinated within the crowd and how to design systems to support higher levels of innovation among crowdworkers. In particular, crowdworkers engaged with knowledge intensive and innovation activities in online platforms, such as Open Idea and Local Motors, are encouraged to collaborate intensively with each other (e.g., Fuller et al, 2011; Langner and Seidel, 2015) in co-creation processes, such as the joint creation of value by a network of diverse actors (Perks et al, 2012; Lusch and Nambinsan, 2015). (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;micro-level patterns of collaboration between knowledge workers impact innovation outcomes (e.g. Perry-Smith and Shalley, 2003) (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we pose the following research question: How do co-creation processes unfold and predict submission quality in crowd-based open innovation and what is the role of the diversity of the crowd in this process? (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theoretical Background and Hypotheses (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crowd-based open innovation (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open innovation has been broadly defined to include flows of knowledge and ideas both into and outside of the organization (e.g. Dahlander and Gann, 2010; Lichtenthaler, 2011). (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;work has tended to focus on the firm (West et al., 2014) and not at the level of the workers called upon to enact these new forms of work. (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As defined by Howe (2009), “crowdsourcing represents the act of a company or institution taking a function once performed by employees and outsourcing it to an undefined and generally large network of people in the form of an open call.” (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies suggest, for example, that monetary payments, when available, increase motivation (e.g. Boudreau et al., 2014; Brabham, 2010, 2008), but that other intrinsic factors, such as being challenged by a complex problem (Boudreau et al., 2014), developing skills (e.g. Brabham, 2010), being identified with the community and forming friendships (e.g. Brabham, 2010; Langer and Seidel, 2015), and having fun (Brabham, 2008) are all equally or more important. (p. 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although informative, most studies do not push beyond questions of individual motivation to understand the work itself and few consider how work is coordinated among individuals and what contributes to high quality submissions. (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unpacking co-creation processes in crowd-based open innovation (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Perks et al. (2012) and Lusch and Nambinsan (2015), co-creation involves the joint creation of value. “Innovations are thus the outcomes of behaviors and interactions between individuals and organizations” (Perks et al., 2012: 935). (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, even if they have promising ideas for a challenge, creators are not always able, alone, to refine and develop them into coherent submissions (Kittur et al., 2013). (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the theoretical framework proposed by Lusch and Nambisan (2015) underscores the importance of the processes that lead to knowledge integration within a network of heterogenous actors and calls for more research on the micro-dynamics of co-creation, e.g. on the different roles played by diverse actors. In a similar vein, Storbacka et al. (2016) call for more research on co-creation that unpacks how different actors engage with each other. (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fewer works, however, have examined how heterogeneous actors involved in co-creation collaborate among themselves, how this evolves over time, and the outcomes of these collaborative processes (see Lusch &amp;amp; Nambisan, 2015; Storbacka et al., 2016). (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One exception is the work of Perks et al. (2012), who investigated the micro-level processes of co-creation and identified two interaction patterns in a network of customers, suppliers, distributors, and intermediaries in the car insurance industry. They found, for example, that successful outcomes often involved high levels of intense interactions among contributors. (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The literature on how creative workers build relationships (e.g., Perry-Smith and Shalley, 2003), interact and exchange feedback (e.g., Perlow, 1999; Harrison and Rouse, 2015; Hargadon and Bechky, 2006), and coordinate their efforts (e.g. Bechky, 2006) is well established and offers important insights into collaboration practices that foster innovative outcomes. (p. 3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A handful of recent studies have also begun to examine interactions in teams composed of crowdworkers (e.g., Retelny et al., 2014; Valentine et al., 2017; Riedl and Wooley, 2017). (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Riedl and Woolley also reported that more successful crowdsourcing teams were characterized by “synchrony” dynamics (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teams that exchanged more diverse information among team members also performed better. (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but extant research leaves us without a clear understanding of which patterns and sequences of interactions, over time, exemplify co-creation, and their influence on innovation outcomes. The objective of our work is thus to unpack the concept of co-creation and identify the core interaction patterns, or “signatures” that make it successful. (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, we focus on how the co-creation patterns contribute to completion and refinement of ideas, i.e. on submission quality. (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypotheses (p. 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;H1 A submission is more likely to be of higher quality if, over time, the number of different contributors (sources) posting on a design idea decreases. (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;H2 A submission is more likely to be of higher quality if, over time, posts are coming from a smaller number of community members who emerge as proportionately dominant. (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;H3 A submission is less likely to be of higher quality if the creator is proportionally dominant, e.g. responsible for the majority of posts. (p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;H4 A submission is more likely to be of higher quality if, over time, the creators’ responses to posts from community members escalates. (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data and Method (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research Context (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local Motors (LM) is a manufacturing company founded in 2007 with the initial aim of becoming the first organization developing an open-source car in collaboration with an online community. (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LM was an ideal company for our study because crowd-based open innovation is a strategic emphasis, and they are engaged on a day-to-day basis with the contributions from their online community. (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data Collection (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We collected data from multiple sources, both qualitative and quantitative, to have a rich and detailed understanding of community members’ behaviors. (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preliminary Interviews with Online Community Members and LM Community Managers (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We conducted 13 preliminary interviews with 10 online community members, i.e., external contributors who participated in the challenges, and 3 LM community managers (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These interviews were used exclusively as a foundation for the authors to better understand the context and make informed decisions about how to design our data collection and analysis (p. 6)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data from the Online Platform on Project REDACTED and the Airbus Cargo Drone Challenge (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We downloaded all data from the community’s message archives (web log of interactions) during the timeframe of the two contests (i.e., from the initial post of the design brief to the announcement of the winners). In particular, we collected data on all the interactions exchanged by 600 community members and employees during the online contest (consisting of more than 10.000 posts). We downloaded information about the sender of each posting, timing, subject, and message content. We also downloaded demographic and personal information about community members to use as controls. (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding of Data from the Online Platform (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we collected information on the timestamp, sender, entry, and content of every comment logged across all entries (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if User A left a comment on Submission B at Time T, with Message K, we would log the observed data point as a tuple of information (A, B, T, K). Our full dataset is then a collection of such tuples, which are grouped by entry and sorted by the time of the post. (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sequence statistics (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put another way, we want to use numerical descriptions of past behavior, which we call signatures, to predict future behavior (Leenders, Contractor, &amp;amp; DeChurch, 2016). (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to examine these signatures or interaction patterns over time, we created sequence statistics that capture interaction events (posts) on a creator’s entry over the course of the design challenges. These measures are a post-by-post indicator of who is contributing to an entry. (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submission Quality (p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Table 1. Summary of Sequence Statistics (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;only 45% follow (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ed the requirements and were considered ‘complete’ and thus accepted for evaluation. (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acceptance of a design for evaluation is therefore a proxy for submission quality, distinguishing between higher quality submissions (i.e. those meeting the requirements and being accepted for evaluation=1) and lower quality submissions (i.e. those not meeting the requirements and not being accepted for evaluation=0). (p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relational Event Modeling Analysis (p. 9)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explaining communication sequences (p. 9)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the relational event model (REM), which is a statistical framework for analyzing sequences of actions and interactions, or relational events (Butts 2008). (p. 9)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This model builds on temporal social network analytic techniques, but emphasizes the role of short-term linkages occurring in sequence (Quintane et al. 2013). We define the rate of activity by an individual 𝑖𝑖 on a particular forum 𝑗𝑗 as the following: (p. 9)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting parameter estimates 𝜃𝜃 thus capture the overarching patterns observed across entries, as determined by the sequence statistics we previously defined. (p. 9)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Differentiating Quality Submissions (p. 9)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach is similar to the ANCOVA methodology used by Johnson and Faraj (2011) to delineate network patterns across online communities, as well as the moderation approach of Schecter et al. (2017) to characterize behaviors of teams based on variations in emergent constructs. (p. 9)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We differentiate our approach from a typical causal inference model; rather than predict the outcome as a function of some antecedents, we characterize an outcome by the underlying process associated with it. In this way, we avoid claiming that a pattern or measure is better or worse, or that a specific sequence leads to a specific result. Rather, we determine if specific variations in certain behaviors are systematically associated with different outcomes. (p. 10)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results (p. 10)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypothesis Testing (p. 11)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test our four main hypotheses, we conduct relational event analysis. We apply a step-wise approach in which we add additional model terms and determine if there is significant improvement in fit. Our first model (Model 1) contains only the main effects, measured across all entries. Our second model includes these main effects, but also includes number of posts, number of users, and competition version as crossentry controls (Model 2). Finally, our third model includes all prior terms and also differentiates between completed entries and those that were not completed (Model 3). The parameter results for these models are presented in Table 3. Based on reduction in deviance, AIC, and BIC values, we conclude that Model 3 provides the strongest fit to our data. (p. 11)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking first at the main effects (Model 3), we see that, overall, entries tended to have increased diversity over time. That is, over time, different contributors posting to creators’ entries escalated. (p. 11)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;me, it is more likely that 41 quality submissions as compared to low quality submissions, over time, the diversity of contributors to the feedback originates from a smaller number of individuals (other than the creator) in high quality entries as compared to low quality entries,. This finding lends support to Hypothesis 1, suggesting escalating diversity across all submissions, but much less so in high quality submissions. Second, we find a positive and quality submissions (𝛽𝛽 = 1.57, 𝑝𝑝 &amp;lt; 0.001). This result indicates that as interactions revolving around a significant tendency for centralization of contributors over time in high quality as compared with low 42 high-quality submission progresses, feedback is significantly more likely to originate from a small number high quality entries, the creator has a lower overall tendency to post, relative to other contributors (𝛽𝛽 = 44 We also performed additional analyses for robustness which are not included in this manuscript for sake of brevity. Specifically, we tested a variety of interaction terms, as well as a curvilinear effect for diversity. We found that none of the variance associated with these terms across entries explained variance in outcomes among the entries. Surprisingly, this analysis suggests that there is not a point at which increasing diversity has a positive effect. That is, even small amounts of increasing diversity over time were associated with lower submission quality. of active contributors, proving support for Hypothesis 2. Third, as hypothesized (H3), we observe that in −1.20, 𝑝𝑝 &amp;lt; 0.001). In other words, for high quality submissions, the creator of an entry does not dominate to feedback more, over time, in high quality submissions, as compared with low quality submissions (𝛽𝛽 = 43 the discussion of their own idea. Finally, we find a positive and significant tendency for creators to respond 1.21, 𝑝𝑝 &amp;lt; 0.001). Thus, as an entry accumulates more contributor feedback over time, creators of high quality submissions are more likely to respond to and engage with the feedback in the later stages of the context. This result lends support to Hypothesis 4. (p. 11)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discussion (p. 12)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In doing so, we respond to the calls for more research on the micro-mechanisms of co-creation (e.g., Lusch and Nambisan; Storbacka et al., 2016). (p. 12)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With regard to diversity, our results show that there is a tendency in the overall sample for more unique contributors to flock to an entry over time, but the entries that are most successful have fewer contributors over time. (p. 13)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in high quality submissions, feedback to the creator tends to originate from a smaller number of individuals, and these individuals are significantly more active relative to other contributors as the project moves from idea generation to elaboration. (p. 13)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the creators of more successful submissions, while not dominating the discussion, are particularly responsive to feedback in later stages. (p. 13)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the primary contributions of this research is that we were able to detect different interaction patterns over time and their effects. (p. 13)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, in analyzing the patterns of interactions between actors, we did not consider the role played by the content of the messages exchanged. (p. 14)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Use in K-12 Schools: Cases from North America</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-mingda-institute-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-mingda-institute-lecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the Google Slides.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotation as Infrastructure for Next Generation Digital Learning Environments</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-educause/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-educause/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the Google Slides.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#OAWeek 2018: My Personal Journey</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-10-oa-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 19:48:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-10-oa-week/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This week is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openaccessweek.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Access Week 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Yesterday we spent some time during a student advising meeting talking about the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; of Open Access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Access Week website has provided &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openaccessweek.org/profiles/blogs/researchers-ideas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a great list of ideas for researchers to get involved in Open Access&lt;/a&gt;. My own institution does have an &lt;a href=&#34;https://policy.umn.edu/research/scholarlyarticles&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Access policy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.umn.edu/openaccess&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Our univeristy library system&lt;/a&gt; also provides support for Open Access including &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.umn.edu/openaccess/open-access-publishing-fund&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an Open Access Publishing Fund&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://conservancy.umn.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a Digital Conservancy system&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://conservancy.umn.edu/handle/11299/166578&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a Research Data Repository&lt;/a&gt;, etc. Not to mention my college is spearheading the &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.cehd.umn.edu/otn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Textbook Library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I am writing up a few vignettes based on my humble journey with Open Access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-aware&#34;&gt;Being Aware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009, I became aware of Open Access during a talk at Beijing Normal (probably given by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/houshuang&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stian Haklev&lt;/a&gt;). At that time, he was finishing up his master&amp;rsquo;s thesis on &amp;ldquo;top-quality open courses in China,&amp;rdquo; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://p2pu.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;P2PU&lt;/a&gt; he co-founded was still an emerging thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Open access, Open license, &amp;quot;Free Speech/Beer&amp;quot;, Peer production, Yochai Benkler, P2PU, CMU OLI, Stephen Downes, SLL&amp;hellip; (May 31th in BNU)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; ʙᴏᴅᴏɴɢ ᴄʜᴇɴ (@bod0ng) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng/status/1981115328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;May 31, 2009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, I participated in an Open Access Week event at OISE of the University of Toronto. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.utsc.utoronto.ca/acm/leslie-chan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Leslie Chan&lt;/a&gt;, a professor from University of Toronto at Scarborough, and Stian were running a panel in the OISE library. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember what they were presenting but I&amp;rsquo;m quite sure their arguments were so eloquent that I became invested in Open Access on that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sharing-drafts-posting-preprints&#34;&gt;Sharing Drafts, Posting Preprints&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I participated in a fun discussion with colleagues from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ai.umich.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Office of Innovation&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Michigan about my paper about &lt;a href=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-tw/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;unLMS&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. Interestingly, this paper has yet to be included in a formal, printed issue of the journal &lt;em&gt;TechTrends&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Great turnout for brown bag lunch with guest  &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@bod0ng&lt;/a&gt; on networked collaborative discourse &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UMichiganAI?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@UMichiganAI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rebquintana?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@rebquintana&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/fwe2thdsJE&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/fwe2thdsJE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Nobuko Fujita (@nobukofujita) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nobukofujita/status/1055855364405526528?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;October 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the timeline of this particular piece of work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In April 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, I started an open manuscript on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.authorea.com/users/4746/articles/169983-designing-for-collaborative-discourse-in-an-online-class-an-unlms-approach&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Authorea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;authorea.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In June 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, before submitting this paper to &lt;em&gt;TechTrends&lt;/em&gt;, I openly invitated colleagues on Twitter to comment on this manscripts. I received a bunch of comments from Stian, which I incorporated into the submitted version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;authorea-hy.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Jan 2018&lt;/strong&gt;, I uploaded &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/ebjfp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a &lt;em&gt;preprint&lt;/em&gt; on the Open Science Framework&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dr_jdean&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jeremy Dean&lt;/a&gt; from Hypothes.is chimed in on Authorea later in Jan 2018 and we eventually met in June 2018 at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://iannotate.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I Annotate&lt;/a&gt; conference in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;osf.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On April 22, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;, after going through two rounds of revisions (with great comments from reviewers and the editor), the article was publised &amp;ldquo;Online First&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;TechTrends&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till now, &lt;strong&gt;October 2018&lt;/strong&gt;, this article is still in its &amp;ldquo;Online First&amp;rdquo; status and may get included in an issue next year. However:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;its first version on Authorea has been annotated 24 times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;its OSF preprint has been downloaded 89 times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;its Springer &amp;ldquo;Online First&amp;rdquo; version has been downloaded 89 times, shared 14 times, and annotated 43 times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From its inception in 2017 to its &amp;ldquo;formal&amp;rdquo; appearance in a printed issue in 2019, a whole lot has happened to this particular work.&lt;/strong&gt; Indeed, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent extra hours to make things work (e.g., converting between document formats, uploading to OSF). But this journey, which I did not anticipate in the beginning, has been extremely rewarding. This article may not be my seminal work, but &lt;strong&gt;it is reassuring that by doing bits and pieces related to Open Access, we as researchers can (1) receive feedback from a broader audience, (2) make valuable connections with colleagues, and (3) get our work read and discussed &amp;ndash; much earlier than its formal publication&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;voicing-the-stance&#34;&gt;Voicing the Stance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the power of Open Access &amp;ndash; and more broadly, &lt;a href=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/notes&#34;&gt;Open Scholarship&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced so far, &lt;strong&gt;it is unfortunate some disciplines and some tenure committees (&lt;em&gt;not mine&lt;/em&gt;) would bluntly equate Open Access with &amp;ldquo;lesser quality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.sciencemag.org/books/2018/01/30/the-tyranny-of-metrics/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tyranny of metrics&lt;/a&gt; is worth a separate post. But here I want to share a statement related to Open Access I decided to include in my dossier (as a tenure-track professor):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an interdisciplinary scholar, I seek to publish in refereed journals from various fields of research, including learning sciences, educational technology, educational psychology, and learning analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an advocate of Open Scholarship, I also attempt to balance my publication venues between “traditional” journals and quality open-access alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a scholar with Chinese heritage, I also write for audiences who speak my mother tongue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite 10 years of #OpenAccessWeek, we still have a long way to go to make &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Invisible Labour&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; in Open Scholarship visible and valued. This is a sudden realization I had this year, thanks to the tweet below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-cards=&#34;hidden&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/OAweek?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#OAweek&lt;/a&gt; event in Vancouver BC Canada: Open but not free: Invisible Labour in Open Scholarship. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/aNz8txzD1c&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/aNz8txzD1c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Christina Hendricks (@clhendricksbc) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/clhendricksbc/status/1055265533765926912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;October 25, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I will continue to do those &amp;ldquo;bits and pieces,&amp;rdquo; I will especially try to be a strong adavocate for: (1) valuing work published in many quality open-access journals, and (2) crediting labor put into Open Scholarship &amp;ndash; including &lt;a href=&#34;https://sparcopen.org/why-open-matters/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Access, Open Education, and Open Data&lt;/a&gt; (according to SPARC) &amp;ndash; in tenure or performance review committees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More broadly, we need &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irrodl.org/index.php/irrodl/article/view/2523/3877&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;changes with institutional culture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;re-imagined writing and publishing practices&lt;/strong&gt; (like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pubpub.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PubPub&lt;/a&gt;), and &lt;strong&gt;better Open Scholarship infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt; (like &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the Open Science Framework&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ICPSR&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-07-public-scholarly-annotation&#34;&gt;Open Web Annotation&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder how things may look like in 2028!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Magnets</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/project/idea-magnets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 15:42:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/project/idea-magnets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orchestration Graphs for Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/project/frog-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 15:42:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/project/frog-online/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated STEM learning in an idea-centered knowledge-building environment</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/hong2018-ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/hong2018-ch/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A.I.与鸡头蛇怪</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2018-07-22-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2018-07-22-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ---
date: &#39;2018-07-22&#39;
title: &#39;A.I.与鸡头蛇怪&#39;
categories: zh
tags: [artificial intelligence, algorithm]
--- --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A.I.，也就是人工智能，已渗透到各个领域。它就像一个迅速膨胀的热气球，几乎所有人都在往里鼓气。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;网上报道，中国的人脸识别技术已让世界颤抖。警察戴上人脸识别墨镜，分分钟教“逃犯”做人。它像极了希腊神话里的“鸡头蛇怪”，必杀技是一对电眼，冷却时间为零。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/14/Basilisk_aldrovandi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(图片来源：Wikipedia)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;然而，热气球不爆炸是因为有冷空气的平衡。鸡头蛇怪被杀死，是因为镜子里自己的眼神，或公鸡的一声啼鸣。&lt;/strong&gt; A.I.的发展，却需要这一套装备——包裹它的冷空气，能照请它的镜子，和一声声啼鸣。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A.I.也好，机器学习也罢，一个重要的特征是其输出结果不会“好过”输入数据。&lt;strong&gt;电脑算法是一种政治文化制品。&lt;/strong&gt; A.I.在被用于解决社会问题的同时，也被封装进了已有的社会文化现实、关系、及偏见。例如，2016年一篇名为《基于面部图像的自动犯罪性概率推断》的文章，试图运用机器学习分析1856张人脸照，从中提取能用来区分“罪犯”与“非罪犯”的面部特征。可不曾想，罪犯的照片来自警察局，而非罪犯的照片来自其个人页面。试想，哪类照片里的人更容易嘴角上扬？机器学习，难免会习得数据里的偏见。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;其实这个文章的例子还好，因为文章作者带着追求学术的初衷，把研究的细节都公之于众。想想那些被封存于“黑箱”里的算法，它们运转着脸书上的动态墙、银行给的信用分、雇员的任免与晋升…… &lt;strong&gt;有A.I.的世界里没有乌托邦式的愿望。相反，当决策越来越多地被自动化、批量化时，我们需要更透明、更具反思性的机制。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/51eUw-v0X%2BL._SX329_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(图片来源：Amazon)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;此时，面对A.I.热，我们需要给它周围包裹上一层冷空气，让它不致爆炸。再找来一面镜子，让它能看到自己，看到那些从人类继承下来的偏见。然后再让每个人学会“公鸡的啼鸣”，包括那些被A.I.束缚的人、因A.I.而收获便利的人、制造A.I.的人，让A.I.真正为更多的人谋福祉。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ongoing Experiment: Public Scholarly Annotation</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-07-public-scholarly-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-07-public-scholarly-annotation/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-stories&#34;&gt;Background stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I value &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open Scholarship&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and have been practicing it for years &amp;ndash; both in terms of &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt; it and &lt;em&gt;learning to do&lt;/em&gt; it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/houshuang&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stian Haklev&lt;/a&gt;, an OER and Open Access champion, introduced me to this idea. He built a wiki-based workflow system, named &lt;em&gt;researchr&lt;/em&gt;, and convinced a few OISE friends, including &lt;a href=&#34;http://cresenciafong.com/blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cresencia Fong&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://alisaacosta.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Alisa Acosta&lt;/a&gt;, to share our annotations publicly, in a well-organized manner. For us, the benefits of using researchr are obvious: the system scaffolds the scholarly process of reading and annotating articles, as well as summarizing and organizing our notes. Its openness adds another important piece that&amp;rsquo;s a bit murkier. &lt;strong&gt;What does it mean to share out annotations publicly &amp;ndash; to academics who annotate, to authors of an annotated article, and to academia?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pratim&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pratim Sengupta&lt;/a&gt;, whose work was &lt;a href=&#34;http://bodong.ch/notes/2015-12-17-sengupta2015/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;annotated by myself&lt;/a&gt; when running a journal club with a dozen grad students, just gave me a chance to really ponder on these questions. He and his team&amp;rsquo;s work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/computing-in-public-computing-for-public-b722f60c9f98&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;public computing&lt;/a&gt; inspires my evolving thinking on the value of openness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thinking is also contextualized in my recent attendance to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://iannotate.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I Annotate&lt;/a&gt; conference and the idea of creating &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.hypothes.is/blog/a-coalition-of-scholarly-annotators/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;A Coalition for Scholarly Annotation&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; shared by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/judell&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jon Udell&lt;/a&gt;. My key takeaway from the conference was that the web annotation community has been thinking deeply about web information, knowledge and workflows. Their work has generated nascent web standards, tools and practices that are making an impact on publishing, information &amp;lsquo;consumption&amp;rsquo;, and human collaboration on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;now-enters-this-blog-post&#34;&gt;Now enters this blog post&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will be an evolving document reflecting my ongoing thinking on &lt;em&gt;open scholarly annotation&lt;/em&gt;. Writing this blog post is a new experiment. I admit my bias upfront. That is, &lt;strong&gt;I strongly believe scholarly annotations generated at various stages of the scholarly process are of great value&lt;/strong&gt;. However, these annotations have become part of the &amp;lsquo;dark data&amp;rsquo; generated by scholars and are rarely talked about. While &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/news/1-500-scientists-lift-the-lid-on-reproducibility-1.19970&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;research reproducibility&lt;/a&gt; has been embraced by many disciplines and scholarly communities, how we actually &amp;lsquo;annotate&amp;rsquo; each other&amp;rsquo;s ideas into new ones remains opaque. Remaining in the dark is not doing justice to hidden value we produce as scholars and is not helping with the training of emerging scholars. Further enriching openness in scholarly practices &amp;ndash; even beyond open data and analysis reproducibility &amp;ndash; would be a meaningful next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;phase-1-of-writing-this-post&#34;&gt;Phase 1 of writing this post&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Phase 1, I will publicly annotate web documents about &lt;em&gt;open scholarly annotation&lt;/em&gt;, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypothes.is/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hypothes.is&lt;/a&gt; and a tag &lt;code&gt;ValueAnnotation&lt;/code&gt;. Below is an evolving collection of my annotations, and I invite you to annotate with me using the same tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/images/article_images/hypothesis.html&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; src=&#34;https://hypothes.is/search?q=tag:%22ValueAnnotation%22&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a Hypothesis annotation I created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/images/article_images/h-annotation.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;phase-2&#34;&gt;Phase 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an emerging process. The next step, as I see now, is to make sense of generated annotations and update this post with summaries and new ideas that &amp;lsquo;rise above&amp;rsquo; existing ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; (2018-7-20): In preparation for an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aera.net/Events-Meetings/Annual-Meeting/2019-Annual-Meeting-Theme&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AERA 2019&lt;/a&gt; submission, I wrote a research summary describing what I hope to do next. The summary &amp;ndash; embedded below &amp;ndash; is informed by Hypothesis annotations above. However, I found it difficult to demonstrate the &amp;lsquo;moves&amp;rsquo; from annotations to writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/e/2PACX-1vR2KgWL47pKHyfDr_YRnIbJEutWQynICTNxusVrsVXHFjyiTODXxU06mihU6kaHrqUJR8haky2kL3q-/pub&#34; frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Textbooks and Open Educational Practices</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-04-24-open-textbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-04-24-open-textbooks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I was included in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mndaily.com/article/2018/04/n-university-of-minnesota-professors-use-their-free-time-to-write-free-textbooks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an &lt;em&gt;MN Daily&lt;/em&gt; story about open textbooks&lt;/a&gt; last week. It was actually a bit embarrassing as I thought a few other colleagues would ‘co-star’ with me in this story because there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://research.cehd.umn.edu/otn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;exciting work on open textbooks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.umn.edu/elearning/partnership/showcase&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;affordable content&lt;/a&gt; going on at UMN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;University of Minnesota professors use their free time to write free textbooks: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/iCgMCxC3qf&#34;&gt;https://t.co/iCgMCxC3qf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mndailynews?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@mndailynews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@bod0ng&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dernst?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@dernst&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UMNews?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@UMNews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/UMNproud?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#UMNproud&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CEHD?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#CEHD&lt;/a&gt; Learn more: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/eydHtKE8Em&#34;&gt;https://t.co/eydHtKE8Em&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/open_textbooks?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@open_textbooks&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/oer?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#oer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LTMediaLab?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@LTMediaLab&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UMN_CI?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@UMN_CI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/zweg5n1FB5&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/zweg5n1FB5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; U of Minnesota CEHD (@UMN_CEHD) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UMN_CEHD/status/986960692468178944?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I’d like to share some personal thoughts that were not included in the news story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-textbooks-personal-reasons-of-using-them&#34;&gt;Open textbooks: Personal reasons of using them&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price of textbooks in the US (and Canada) is ridiculous. I am not knowledgeable enough to explain why. But I had lived experiences with buying bulky textbooks for $200 and using them as laptop stands after a single use. They are from respected textbook publishers (like SAGE) and are indeed well-written. But &amp;hellip; there could be 100 reasons why a textbook should not cost that much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, the notion of ‘a textbook’ has evolved, at least for some disciplines. In many fields that are fast-evolving, textbooks written today will become dated in two years. Also, one textbook can rarely fulfill needs of a course, making it necessary to introduce fresh texts and multimedia content from the ‘open world’. Digital tools, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://h5p.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;H5P&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.google.com/colaboratory/faq.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Colaboratory&lt;/a&gt;, offer richer modalities, interoperability, and interactivity for learning in comparison with traditional paper books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More profoundly, &lt;strong&gt;the conceptualization of a textbook as a container of knowledge to be acquired by students is challenged by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newcultureoflearning.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;‘new cultures of learning’&lt;/a&gt; that de-emphasize ‘knowledge as stocks’ and value learning as &amp;lsquo;participating in a flow of knowledge production&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/strong&gt; Instructors can surely do inspiring things with a traditional textbook, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencontent.org/blog/archives/3221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;grounding principles of Open Educational Resources (OER)&lt;/a&gt; almost automatically make a philosophical statement that draws one’s teaching closer to new cultures of learning. It’s the (promised) paradigm shift behind OER (and open textbooks) that attracts me, besides cost concerns mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, by the way, these changes are not limited to textbooks, but also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/04/the-scientific-paper-is-obsolete/556676/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;scholarly knowledge production in general&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-educational-practices&#34;&gt;Open educational practices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my thinking on OER are tilted towards &lt;a href=&#34;http://catherinecronin.net/research/openness-and-praxis/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;‘open educational practices’&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to making my course content open (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/meefen/la-spring16&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on Github for example&lt;/a&gt;), I am also interested in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open participation&lt;/strong&gt; — that does not limit participation within a socially, spatiotemporally, and technologically bounded environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Student agency and voice&lt;/strong&gt; — that give students a say about what to learn and how to learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connected learning&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.veletsianos.com/digital-scholarship-social-media-use-and-networked-participatory-scholarship/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;networked scholarship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; opportunities — that present a fuller picture of learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/324611447_Designing_for_Networked_Collaborative_Discourse_An_UnLMS_Approach?_sg=PGJY4wgTJg5Cww01tBKT9c1Oo_ePJeI3nSHLFeyQAsJYUyWE6Dv8Ht-S2ofF60vy_b67vRe8oXJxu6xQB2SNhAYX7z7suxd3eW7PBIWm.En9a-PTggG7Kycn1iq4BewoyxPdNV69K57JZI_E-88MS-xc7YknPZ-7TE0_MzyhxrXSwZsC0Z8nUguDTKMBjTQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a design case I recently published in &lt;em&gt;TechTrends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, an EdTech journal, I introduce in great details about a course I designed with these ideas in mind. I wrote a course handbook, which is essentially a compilation of OER, and incorporated tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypothes.is/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hypothes.is&lt;/a&gt; and Slack to facilitate collaborative discourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be fun to integrate more ‘open pedagogy’ ideas in the next iteration of this course. Maybe asking students to rewrite the handbook. Maybe setting up open Jupyter Notebooks for students to fork, remix, and redistribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-this-mean-for-faculty-members&#34;&gt;What does this mean for faculty members?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;use their free time&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;on top of their day-to-day work, often only receiving relatively small grants as compensation&amp;quot; 🤔 Bit problematic framing of OER production, as if it&amp;#39;s done by amateurs, out of love.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ewout ter Haar (@ewout) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ewout/status/987005352402137088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a good critique. Free-time is an unfamiliar word for many academics. The idea of &lt;a href=&#34;https://er.educause.edu/articles/2014/2/conjecture-tension-and-online-learning&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;teaching online is already facing push-backs&lt;/a&gt; over the years. Structural supports for faculty members are needed to make OER production sustainable. Supporting broader acceptance of OER and open educational practices also requires cultural shifts within an institution, which is often hard to bring about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episodes from my trip in China</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-04-05-china-episodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-04-05-china-episodes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am not an ethnographer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there were a few episodes from my trip to/in China last month that caught my attention, or &amp;lsquo;gaze&amp;rsquo;. To put these episodes into perspective, my most recent trip to China took place &lt;a href=&#34;http://bodong.ch/blog/2016-11-03-trip-to-asia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in October 2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-the-escalator&#34;&gt;On the Escalator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As more subways are built underground, I encountered more of those super long escalators in mega cities. On one escalator in Shanghai, I heard its accompanying &amp;lsquo;voice reminder system&amp;rsquo; saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please hold the handrail firmly and attend to your steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not lean on the handrail. &lt;strong&gt;Do not look at your phone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last sentence of the voice system was new. The intimate connection between us with screens has been built into another piece of technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sns-img.b0.upaiyun.com/dunzd/1710/2621/53/151240667855781509026035.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cdsb.com/Public/cdsb_offical/2017-10-26/148418749157279040888484000860608264626.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Image Source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;say-something-in-english&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Say Something in English&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a workday, my pre-schooler son and I were playing in a playground in Shanghai. There were a bunch of other kids &amp;ndash; mostly younger &amp;ndash; also playing there. My son always prefers talking with me in Mandarin but may entertain with a few English words from time to time. Then there was a dad with his young daughter (approximately 2 years old). It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long for him to make a request to his daughter: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Baby, can you say something in English?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;  The same thing happened again the next day in a park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days later when I was in my hometown, a small town in Western China, I visited a newly built factory where an uncle works. This factory manufactures food supplements with nutritions extracted from traditional Chinese herbs. I somehow ended up meeting with their young sales team, which was made of four fresh college graduates. They were in their early 20s, and two of them graduated from the same high school I attended. Then I began to learn about their goals of taking over their international sales from intermediaries located in costal areas. They were not confident in their English capabilities though and showed tremendous interests in Western culture(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest dream while growing up in my hometown was to go to college in Shanghai or Beijing. Now it seems people living in my hometown are aspiring to ride the tide of globalization. It may be still difficult to attract or retain necessary talents. But they have lofty goals. The new factory aims to become a listed company in 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/images/article_images/shanghai_yuechi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-accept-both-wechat-and-zhifubao&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;I accept both WeChat and Zhifubao&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Riding on a taxi from Shanghai Pudong Airport to a hotel, I noticed two QR codes attached to the dashboard of the taxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I accept both WeChat and Zhifubao,&amp;rdquo; said the driver when we arrived. And he taught me how to use them on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time around, I could basically &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/2110118/going-cash-free-why-china-light-years-ahead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;go cash-free everywhere in China&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn2.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/images/methode/2017/09/11/1b7d1df6-8ef9-11e7-9f40-4d9615941c08_1320x770_114008.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-still-don-t-see-the-point&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;I still don&amp;rsquo;t see the point.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my stay at Beijing Normal, I taught a few classes on topics such as MOOCs and learning analytics. In a graduate-level class, a professor introduced to us a project aiming to build a recommender engine to help highschool students choose subjects in &lt;a href=&#34;http://gaokao.eol.cn/news/201710/t20171027_1562295.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the newly reformed college entrance exam&lt;/a&gt;. The recommender engine will be based on a wide range of factors, including previous performance, personality traits, competitiveness of the student&amp;rsquo;s aspired college, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One student said, &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I still don&amp;rsquo;t see the point.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; Her argument was this choice is too high-stake and too personal. She would like to make the choice on her own even if the recommendation is meant to be informational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She had a point. A very good one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>天宝趣谈</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2018-04-01-tianbao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2018-04-01-tianbao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ---
date: &#39;2018-04-01&#39;
title: 天宝趣谈
categories: zh
tags: [China, rural]
slug: tianbao
--- --&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;按：这是我受邀为天宝小学写的一篇文章。人生头13年在天宝乡度过。现如今，因为乡镇合并，它已经从地图上消失。好在记忆还一直存留。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/images/article_images/tianbao.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我是一个从天宝走出的孩子。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在人生的头13年里，我很少走出天宝，有关我的一切，都在这里。因为父母在天宝小学教书，从一出生我就和天宝小学联系在了一起。从四岁入学到初中毕业，我在天宝小学度过了九年时光。离开后的十几年，从岳池到北京、再到加拿大和美国，我离这片故土渐行渐远，却永远走不出她的羁绊。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;小学的头五年，我在石狮子村小就读。父亲是我的启蒙老师，至今印象很深的是每天和他从家到学校的&amp;rdquo;艰辛跋涉&amp;rdquo;。跋涉中我经历了夏天的暴雨、秋天的稻子、冬天结冰的水田、春天的莺飞草长。在这条弯弯曲曲的小路上，有我对每个时令的特殊记忆。几年里，我已熟知每块石板，每块青苔，每个泥坑，每片竹林。而我那时最童真的幻想就是能沿这条小路，搭起一片遮天蔽日的葡萄架，一边帮我躲避夏日炎炎，一边奉上葡萄的甘甜。五年间，这条葡萄长廊终究没能搭起来，摸爬滚打中我的双膝却留下了许多伤疤。在这条小路上，我沐浴在天宝温润丰富的四季里，从幼稚的孩童成为坚毅的少年。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在村小的这五年，我们换了多次教室。最初的泥胚房里，只有讲台后方的一扇小窗。阴雨天里，两盏昏暗的白炽灯似乎在努力往我们书本上撒满光亮，却终究力不从心。后来用几条竹竿挂起了三排电灯，书本上的字才终于能看清。因为翻修校舍，我们的教室好几次被搬到附近的村落。并不宽大的民宅里，竖起黑板便成为我们的教室。我们失去了熟悉的操场，但从来没少半点乐趣。我们在泥泞的地坝上滚着铁环，在教室的墙角里挤起&amp;rdquo;油糟&amp;rdquo;。我们从未抱怨过学习条件，一个20多人的班级，在一起度过几年时光就是最大的恩赐。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;小学六年级时，因为父亲工作调动我和他一起到了乡小。更严格的班级管理似乎让我失去了更多的自由。因为离家更远，刚开始的几天我总是迟到，最后决定住校。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;和父亲住进了学校一角的一个教师宿舍后。我逐渐结实了一批玩伴，校园生活又多了许多新乐趣。十岁出头的男孩总是无聊，脑子里总是有各种怪主意。比如去附近的山坡上探险、比如把桔子放到电炉里煮、比如结队去偏远的学校厕所里讲鬼故事把自己吓得半死。那时的我痴迷于乒乓球，却不太明白为何课后还要看书。放学后的夜里，我们在校园里闲逛，从未探讨过天宝地理位置之所在，却大谈着各自遥远的梦想。而那无数梦想之中，最大的无外乎是上大学。除此之外，似乎想象不到更远大的理想了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;初三的毕业季里，似乎总是在下雨。我们的教室在当时新校舍三楼拐角的位置，下起雨来风灌满整个教室。我们开始忙于应付各种模拟考试、会考、和中考。记得会考后根据成绩只有一部分同学能参加中考，竞争升入重点中学的机会。迎战中考的教室里，剩下为数不多的同学，繁忙备考中又多了一份忧伤。而那些空座位上的同学，大多我再也没能见过。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;时光流转，我也渐渐明白人生就是偶然、幸运和遗憾编织的画卷。1999年夏天，我从天宝小学毕业去了岳池一中读高中。三年后我从繁忙的县城中学毕业，去了更繁忙的北京上大学。北师大本科毕业后保送去了北大读硕士，再申请奖学金到了加拿大多伦多大学攻读博士学位。博士毕业后，2015年我顺利成为了明尼苏达大学的助理教授，至今仍是系里最年轻、唯一来自中国的教授。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一笔带过的这十几年间，我无数次地回想在天宝小学的时光。大一时，我一次在寝室奋笔疾书写下了一篇关于对天宝的记忆。或许因思成疾，写完发现自己发着高烧，去校医院打针。后来到了异国他乡，埋头苦读中偶然抬头，眼中映入异国他乡的大楼，心中却常忆起天宝多彩的四季和简洁的生活。我时常回想起孩童时听来的一句话：&amp;rdquo;天宝，天然的一块宝地&amp;rdquo;；会想起老师训导我们时提到的天宝小学&amp;rdquo;三宝&amp;rdquo;：雨伞、筒靴、手电筒；还会想起童年里做过的一个梦，梦见自己翻过一直横亘在天边的那座山，看到了山那边的世界。那时的我，深沉地爱着这片土地，又多么想离开她，去看看山那边的世界。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;后来，我翻过了那座山，攀上了泰山，飞越了太平洋、大西洋。曾经最大梦想是上大学的我，现在在一所全球知名大学里任教，教着来自世界各地的学生。而今，在天宝和天宝小学的时光，成了永远珍藏的记忆，激励我继续前行。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>火车</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2018-03-20-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2018-03-20-train/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ---
date: &#39;2018-03-20&#39;
title: 火车
categories: zh
tags: [China]
slug: trains
--- --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;上次在中国坐硬座火车可能需要追溯到十年前。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;还记得大一寒假回家，学校给我们订到了最慢的“绿皮车”。从北京到四川老家，摇摇晃晃坐了40多个小时，感觉像坐到了地老天荒。后来的7年里，再也没坐上绿皮车，但当时最快的特快车到四川也要24小时。学生穷，不舍得买卧铺，每次都坐硬座。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;现在想来，每年寒暑假的往返列车上也有不少有趣的记忆。大一坐绿皮车的那次，和隔壁寝室电子系几位重庆的同学一起。40小时里我们聊的天，或许比整个大学四年都多。睡梦中突然醒来，火车又停了，窗外是白雪皑皑的大山，自己不知身在何处，似乎从刚才的梦境进入了另一个梦境。后来一次寒假在北京-&amp;gt;成都的特快车上，打了一场人生至今最过瘾、惊心动魄的双升。车票号码神奇地把我们安排到一起，在密闭拥挤的空间里相处一整天，一起煎熬，不问姓名，然后各奔东西。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在同一个车厢里的还有只买到站票的农民工朋友。他们托着编织袋和塑料桶，偶尔相互传递一瓶浓烈的白酒，用手机大声放着新进流行的歌曲。在特殊的季节里，学生和农民工这两个平时交集不大的群体聚集在这个车厢，相互照顾地交替着坐，分享着归家的急切和漫漫长路的煎熬。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;这次回国，我又有机会坐了一次长途火车。其中最长的一次旅行是从成都到郑州的高铁。以前大半天的旅程，高铁在6小时内就能完成。车厢里每个人都有位置，没有了站票。双向的座位也变成了单向。车厢整洁、舒适、安静。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;但在这趟快速列车上，向前我只能看到前排人的头顶，再也不会经历那么多和陌生人的谈话，再也找不到当年“同车共济”的情怀。这些，被文明、国际化、高速度一并埋葬掉。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;但对于快4岁的儿子来说，这会是他对火车的第一次记忆。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/images/article_images/train2018.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fostering student engagement in online discussion through social learning analytics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-mc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-mc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using differentiated feedback to improve performance in introductory statistics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/cai2018-za/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/cai2018-za/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Annotation of Research Articles in Learning Sciences</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-12-08-jls-web-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-12-08-jls-web-annotation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- comments: true
image: https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2453/3973300988_824ec066a9_b.jpg --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a member of the Outreach Advisory Board of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tandfonline.com/loi/hlns20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Journal of the Learning Sciences (JLS)&lt;/a&gt;, I was really glad to see the journal putting together a web annotation event during December 11-22, 2017. This activity is yet another move made by the editorial team to engage its readership on various social media venues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Coming Soon: Web annotation of JLS articles in Hypothes.is.&lt;br&gt;The first article is a study by Akkerman and Bruining published in 2016 in Volume 25 (2).Read the full article at &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/tGoOiQKLUR&#34;&gt;https://t.co/tGoOiQKLUR&lt;/a&gt;  and visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/2dYOBe15L8&#34;&gt;https://t.co/2dYOBe15L8&lt;/a&gt;  for instructions for using &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hypothes_is?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@hypothes_is&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/z5oSHleIKB&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/z5oSHleIKB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; JrnlLearningSciences (@JLearnSciences) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JLearnSciences/status/937719563390672896?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 4, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this web annotation event, participants are invited to annotate a recently published open-access article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10508406.2016.1147448&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multilevel Boundary Crossing in a Professional Development School Partnership&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, using an open web annotation tool named &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypothes.is/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hypothes.is&lt;/a&gt;. Hats off to the authors for their support of this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The editorial team has put together &lt;strong&gt;detailed instructions&lt;/strong&gt; in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1Cmoz22xEY8QjHBiYC-H2oU0YHJSTLCBhWelbusSXbKM/edit#slide=id.g2b48df0836_0_10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During and after the event, in addition to the Hypothes.is sidebar, a participant can either use &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypothes.is/search?q=url%3Ahttp%3A%2F%2Fwww.tandfonline.com%2Fdoi%2Ffull%2F10.1080%2F10508406.2016.1147448&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hypothes.is&amp;rsquo; advanced search functionality&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://jonudell.net/h/facet.html?facet=uri&amp;amp;mode=documents&amp;amp;search=http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10508406.2016.1147448&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an aggregation tool&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;review existing annotations&lt;/strong&gt; made on this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am excited for this move JLS is making, not only because &lt;strong&gt;scholarship could be more networked and discursive&lt;/strong&gt;, but also because I see great opportunities of using web annotation to bridge learning spaces in classrooms. To me, making an annotation is forming a relationship with an idea. As educators, &lt;strong&gt;we ought to think deeply and design smartly to value such relationships as students are traversing various treks of life&lt;/strong&gt;. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://cligr.github.io/projects/discow.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;our ongoing NSF project&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forest</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-10-13-at-what-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-10-13-at-what-price/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/c/c5/Mordecai_MOREH_-_Tree_of_Knowledge_%28Initiation%29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Photo Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Mordecai_MOREH_-_Tree_of_Knowledge_(Initiation).jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The universe is expanding&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Milky Way is a beauty&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Sun is shining&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Earth looks blue&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All continents are moving&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Civilizations boom&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A wall defends &amp;lsquo;us&amp;rsquo;&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Pyramids are built tall&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boats cross the ocean&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Nets get casted&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
People dine and leave bones behind&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;lsquo;Research&amp;rsquo; gets conducted&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We Uber to the airport&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Google guides the way&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Peppa Pig speaks in the house&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A.I. is figuring things out&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coffee smells delicious&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Muscles stretch to the cup&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Neurons are fired up&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Joy spills over&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keys are stroked&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Bits get sent&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Photons dash through a fiber&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Particles become entangled&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A leave is dancing&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Stones get erected&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
People are farming animals&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A king is crowned&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The statue is pushed over&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A wall falls down&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Another country rises&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Humans step on the moon&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Earth is half-dark&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Sun has spots&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
All stars are spinning in the &amp;lsquo;Dark Forest&amp;rsquo;&lt;span style=&#34;color: white&#34;&gt;, but at what price.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Until the universe collapses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now, please hit Ctrl+A / Cmd+A and read again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: This is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a poem. Just some musings translated to sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours in struggle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AERA-NSF Workshop: Data Sharing and Research Transparency (Part II)</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-07-27-data-sharing-workshop-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-07-27-data-sharing-workshop-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!-- comments: true
image: /assets/article_images/3574677912_85d6543c27_b.jpg

_(Photo Credit: [Zachary Veach](https://www.flickr.com/photos/labguest/3574677912/in/photostream/))_ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story continued, after &lt;a href=&#34;http://bodong.ch/blog/2017/07/25/data-sharing-workshop-1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Part I&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 2.5 days of the workshop, the group continued to deepen the discussion on Data Sharing to more concrete and practical items. In Part II of my personal reflection, I summarize key Data Sharing resources/initiatives to be aware of, possible action items, and some personal random thoughts on future directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The 3-day workshop on &amp;quot;Data Sharing and Research Transparency at the Article Publishing Stage&amp;quot; comes to a close today in D.C. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/XpXIKp459g&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/XpXIKp459g&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; AERA (@AERA_EdResearch) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AERA_EdResearch/status/890598718914924544&#34;&gt;July 27, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-sharing-in-education-science-the-status-quo&#34;&gt;Data Sharing in Education Science: The Status Quo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second day of the workshop, scholars working at the frontiers of data sharing and open science presented their insights and experiences, together with officers from funding agencies (IES, NSF, NIH) and journal editors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arthurlupia.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Skip Lupia&lt;/a&gt; (UMich), a political scientist and the Chairman of the Board of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cos.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for Open Science&lt;/a&gt;, gave a talk about &lt;em&gt;Why Share, Why Now, What for?&lt;/em&gt;. He helped us unpacking two important criteria of scientific research: &lt;em&gt;credibility&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;legitimacy&lt;/em&gt;. Equally helpful was a recognition that &lt;em&gt;transparency&lt;/em&gt; encompasses &lt;em&gt;production transparency&lt;/em&gt; (the production of data) and &lt;em&gt;analytic transparency&lt;/em&gt; (how a scholar goes from data to knowledge claims). He shared important resources from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dartstatement.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DA-RT: Data Access and Research Transparency&lt;/a&gt; initiative and its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dartstatement.org/2016-da-rt-journal-policy-archive&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TOP Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;, supported by 29 top journals across disciplines. He shared preliminary evidence of &amp;ldquo;small&amp;rdquo; things like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cos.io/our-services/open-science-badges/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CoS Badges&lt;/a&gt; can effectively spur the adoption of data sharing &amp;amp; research transparency practices. Finally, it was so refreshing to hear that those data sharing initiatives have been and are being championed by &lt;em&gt;qualitative&lt;/em&gt; researchers. Data sharing is indeed doable for qualitative researchers and how qualitative researchers perceive data (and I guess more specifically their ontological and epistemological commitments) are of great value to data sharing practices. This is a very important and mindbolging message that I did not expect before this workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.cos.io/media/images/badges_chart.original.png&#34; alt=&#34;Source: CoS&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three recognized &lt;strong&gt;data sharing repositories&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Inter‐university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR)&lt;/a&gt; (UMich), &lt;a href=&#34;https://nyu.databrary.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Databrary&lt;/a&gt; (PSU &amp;amp; NYU), and &lt;a href=&#34;https://qdr.syr.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Qualitative Data Repository (QDR)&lt;/a&gt; (Syracuse) &amp;mdash; and their leaders/PIs presented as a panel. &lt;strong&gt;It was encouraging&lt;/strong&gt; to see: 1) ICPSR&amp;rsquo;s long record of data sharing/archiving since 1962; 2) QDR as a repository focusing on qualitative data; and 3) &amp;ldquo;even&amp;rdquo; research videos are also sharable on Databrary. AERA is partnering with ICPSR to set up a dedicated repository for AERA journals, in line with AERA&amp;rsquo;s forthcoming policies on data sharing. Important questions were asked about possible impact on international researchers &amp;mdash; and non-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apa.org/monitor/2010/05/weird.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WEIRED&lt;/a&gt; populations &amp;mdash; who are automatically excluded by some data repositories&amp;rsquo; requirements of IRB approvals that are nonexistent in some countries/regions. For me, it was encouraging to learn &lt;strong&gt;existing templates and guidelines&lt;/strong&gt; made available by data sharing repositories that I could refactor for IRB protocols of my projects. Together with emerging policies made by funding agencies, professional associations, and journals, I can feel more confident about pursuing data sharing (as much as possible) when proposing a study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was exiting to hear from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-personal.umich.edu/~maggiel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Maggie Levenstein&lt;/a&gt; (Director of ICPSR) about work on &lt;strong&gt;researcher credential building blocks&lt;/strong&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s under way. Their framework of credentials includes a researcher&amp;rsquo;s status (incl. academic, geographic, demographics), affiliation, training (e.g., in data sharing), access level, prior contributions, and violations of data stewardship. While companies like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ResearchGate&lt;/a&gt; are inventing scores to determine researchers&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;status,&amp;rdquo; why not build a non-proprietary system to enable positive feedback loop for data sharing? A researcher credentialing system with an emphasis on data sharing could raise awareness of data sharing, give credits to those who share, and maintain reputation of data users. Exciting stuff!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are still so many issues to be sorted out, especially from an editor&amp;rsquo;s standpoint, who may constantly face work overload and not wish to add another layer to a journal&amp;rsquo;s production pipeline. Extremely legitimate. As an early career scholar, I&amp;rsquo;m quite blind to many challenges an editor or an association&amp;rsquo;s president might be thinking about. Fortunately colleagues running data repositories may have a lot to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was helpful to hear from Lupia on the third day about &lt;em&gt;multiple levels&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;multiple dimensions&lt;/em&gt; a journal can consider when implementing data sharing practices. Check out this &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/4kdbm/?_ga=2.219522076.428476302.1501263281-1395141731.1501019040&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;one-pager&lt;/a&gt; explaining 8 modular standards and 3 levels. From the lowest level, for example, a journal could &lt;em&gt;encourage&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; instead of &lt;em&gt;requiring&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; authors to put data into a repository. In terms of dimensions, a journal could consider change of &lt;em&gt;citation practices&lt;/em&gt; to reinforce secondary datasets being cited, require &lt;a href=&#34;http://egap.org/content/registration&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;preregistration&lt;/a&gt; of (causal-inferential) research, encourage replication studies, nurture analytic transparency by asking authors to share code, and so forth. As our JLS co-editor-in-chief &lt;a href=&#34;scholar.gse.upenn.edu/yoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Susan Yoon&lt;/a&gt; nicely worded, &amp;ldquo;it seems the train has already departed, and we need to catch it.&amp;rdquo; I was thinking about a slightly different metaphor based on my experiences playing &amp;ldquo;Real-Time Strategy Games&amp;rdquo;: there are multiple pathways towards winning a game (e.g., defeating an opponent), and &lt;strong&gt;doing one thing&lt;/strong&gt; (such as collecting a lot of lamber) &lt;strong&gt;may unlock other components of winning&lt;/strong&gt;; further, in a game that requires teamwork, one player (e.g., a journal editor) could focus on one component (e.g., collecting lamber) and share to teammates, while other teammates (e.g., community advocates, data repositories) could handle other parts. We should not drain an editorial team&amp;rsquo;s limited resources to achieve everything overnight; rather, &lt;strong&gt;maybe we could create a roadmap that involves multiple types of contributors&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; authors, editors, data sharing services, funders, and maybe also publishers (for-profit or not).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funding agencies have been actively looking into data sharing. For instance, discussions on data and data stewardship are central to NSF Programs such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/news/news_summ.jsp?cntn_id=136253&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;smart and connected communities and Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nlm.nih.gov/NIHbmic/nih_data_sharing_repositories.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NIH has 71 data repositories&lt;/a&gt; and is very active in Genomic data sharing. To a great extent, broader impacts sought by funding agencies could become more achievable if research data &amp;mdash; collected with support from tax-payer dollars &amp;mdash; are not sitting in one team&amp;rsquo;s private server for 10 years but instead shared carefully, ethically, and with proper restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a colleague nicely said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data sharing is not a thing in addition to doing science. Data sharing is doing science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;action-items&#34;&gt;Action Items&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A collective resolution has been reached near the end of the workshop and is likely to be shared by AERA soon. Below are action items that seem to me thinkable &amp;mdash; if not yet feasible &amp;mdash; for different players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Disclaimer: These items are in many cases my personal takeaways and do not represent official policies from funding agencies or professional associations. Some ideas are based on group discussion but may not accurately reflect what was originally said.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual researchers.&lt;/strong&gt; Study issues related to research transparency, reproducibility, replicability, etc. Get familiar with terms like &lt;a href=&#34;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/science-isnt-broken/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;-hacking&lt;/a&gt;, preregistration, reproducible research, preprints, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.researchobject.org/overview/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Research Objects&lt;/a&gt;, etc. Take a hard look at our own research workflows and think about potential transparency/reproducibility hazards &amp;mdash; which could be related to how we name files, store research memos, document R codes, backup data, etc. Stay current with existing data sharing guidelines from funders, journals, and research societies &amp;mdash; as the train has ignited its engine if not yet departed. Seek support from our institutions, libraries, data stewards, etc. For those ahead of the game, publish your codes in Github, package algorithms in an R package, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very important point made by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/robyn_read&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Robyn Read&lt;/a&gt; (an early career peer &amp;amp; also an OISE alumnus): academia has been quite intolerant of failures and mistakes. We get afraid of missteps at every stage of a research project. How about making &lt;a href=&#34;http://home.frontiersin.org/about/review-system&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;peer-review more collaborative&lt;/a&gt;? How about putting drafts/preprints out there early on for open discussions (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.atmos-chem-phys.net/16/3761/2016/acp-16-3761-2016-discussion.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this paper originally shared as a draft&lt;/a&gt;)? There are certain norms in academia possibly ripe for &lt;em&gt;disruption&lt;/em&gt; (a word I typically don&amp;rsquo;t like using).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faculty members.&lt;/strong&gt; Engage students in conversations, in our labs or methodology courses. Point them to training resources on campus or online (webinars, MOOCs, manuals). Help them stay calm, even when we aren&amp;rsquo;t :-). Maybe even develop new courses about research transparency and reproducible research &amp;mdash; typically nonexistent in colleges of Education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Reproducibility Guide from the R and rOpenSci communities &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/e7DA5PP16h&#34;&gt;https://t.co/e7DA5PP16h&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/DataSharing?src=hash&#34;&gt;#DataSharing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/openscience?src=hash&#34;&gt;#openscience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bodong Chen (@bod0ng) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng/status/890277065051734016&#34;&gt;July 26, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional associations and their journals.&lt;/strong&gt; Convey messages to association members and share exemplars. Expect non-supportive reactions and resistance. Treat resistance as good opportunities of conversations, as a colleague said. Engage members &amp;mdash; esp. international members &amp;mdash; in conversations about data sharing at board meetings, conferences, webinars, doctoral consortia, etc. Talk with other journals under a same society, journals in a same field by &amp;ldquo;reside&amp;rdquo; somewhere else, and journals from other fields. Identify early-starters of data sharing and engage them in training and conversations. Maybe consider a new award category for data sharing or research transparency/reproducibility (suggested by Skip).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data repositories.&lt;/strong&gt; I look forward to digging into datasets already living in those repositories and studying their resources for IRB preparation. For example, to me knowing data sharing is not the same as making data totally open to anyone was helpful (see the tweet below). It would be very useful if data repositories could further provide dataset exemplars. A 3-minute video walkthrough about the process of depositing a dataset will also help. These resources would help us get a more concrete understanding of data sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;One example ICPSR dataset showing ways to protect data: the words &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/DataSharing?src=hash&#34;&gt;#DataSharing&lt;/a&gt; sound scary but there are strategies &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/MfZqqUSWxf&#34;&gt;https://t.co/MfZqqUSWxf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/FUpfc3SZNh&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/FUpfc3SZNh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bodong Chen (@bod0ng) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng/status/890211031720611842&#34;&gt;July 26, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universities and research institutions.&lt;/strong&gt; IRB practices are evolving as well. My institution, the University of Minnesota, hosted IRB Town Halls last academic year discussing the changing landscape of Compliance &amp;amp; Ethics. Engage IRB offices in data sharing conversations, if not yet. Also important is a university&amp;rsquo;s willingness to back up its researchers&amp;rsquo; ethical data sharing practices and stand with them against possible vicious attacks. Just like many universities are backing up their faculty members&amp;rsquo; fair-use claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;towards-my-dream-world&#34;&gt;Towards My Dream World&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop was so helpful in getting me to think more deeply about data sharing and possible actions I can take as a researcher, faculty member, new investigator, author, international person whose home country&amp;rsquo;s ethical review practice is still emerging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below I explore a few other components touched upon (implicitly) during the workshop. I am quite excited about them even though they are still vague and paradoxical to me, or are totally against our current norms and routines. So I&amp;rsquo;m now throwing them out there for further discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control.&lt;/strong&gt; Before attending the workshop, I thought data sharing is to put data out there &amp;mdash; totally public and totally beyond one&amp;rsquo;s control after data get shared. That is a scary scene for many of us. As researchers, we can still remain a certain level of control over a shared dataset &amp;mdash; not based on whether we like a data requester or whether a requested usage contradicts our published findings.. But it seems &lt;strong&gt;controls pre- and post-sharing&lt;/strong&gt; are areas that could be further discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I&amp;rsquo;m especially curious about possible controls after data sharing (&lt;em&gt;post-sharing&lt;/em&gt;). Linked to work on researcher credentials, data repositories could have an opportunity to think twice about a data request from someone with many previous violations. For data sharers, they may wish to be able to track who are accessing my shared data, how, and where results are published; so are data repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related to post-sharing controls, we also image a shared dataset to keep evolving after secondary analysts invest time to recode, reshape, or link them. When we allow a new version of a dataset to appear? Or do we allow a dataset to fork? Who can make these judgements? Intriguing questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about research participants? While our currently practices seek clearcut delimiters of data ownership/stewardship in a lifecycle of project. For example, when an informed consent is made, we say data ownership is transferred from a participant to a researcher; similarly, when a dataset gets submitted to shared to a repository after de-identification, we see another change of data ownership and stewardship. However, &lt;strong&gt;in a deeply connected world, should research participants remain control of their own data?&lt;/strong&gt; Would it be more ethical if participants have the choice to stay aware of work conducted on data they contributed &amp;mdash; while remaining hidden from data users? This may seem totally quite counter-intuitive. But see yourself the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kavlifoundation.org/kavli-human-project&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kavli HUMAN project&lt;/a&gt;, the shift &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iftf.org/techfutureslab/?utm_content=buffer27233&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;from an Internet of Information to an Internet of Actions&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2017/03/the-potential-for-blockchain-to-transform-electronic-health-records&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a move to store medical records on blockchains&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubiquitous networking has transformed cyberspace into a pervasive layer atop our physical reality.  (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iftf.org/techfutureslab/?utm_content=buffer27233&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;re the implications on research data? What does it mean to data sharing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linked data and maintained contexts.&lt;/strong&gt;  Information loss accompanies the lifecycle of research data &amp;ndash; from collection, cleansing, transformation, analysis, synthesis, publication, to meta-analysis&amp;hellip; We are increasingly losing the context where data were originally collected. In a &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; connected world, as described above, how about data sharing is not too distant from where data originally reside? &lt;strong&gt;Data sharing is just like adding faces and masks to data and selectively expose data to secondary users?&lt;/strong&gt; In my experiences with secondary data, I saw data shared in forms PDFs, CSVs, Excels, JSONs, and XMLs. How about we say those data formats or shapes all suck, and we wish to (safely &amp;amp; ethically) maintain possible connectivity when sharing data instead of cutting connections?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broader conceptions of value and incentives.&lt;/strong&gt; I shared an idea in a breakout group discussion about crediting data sharers with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptocurrency&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;crypto- or digital currency&lt;/a&gt;, with which they can &amp;ldquo;purchase&amp;rdquo; other data. Like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethereum&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ethereum blockchain&lt;/a&gt;, data sharers share data with &amp;ldquo;smart contracts&amp;rdquo; attached to them and users &amp;ldquo;pay&amp;rdquo; a price in a digital currency based on their status (e.g. free for a student or a researcher without funding, a fair amount for someone having funding, expensive for someone with many prior violations). One colleague said this &amp;ldquo;monetization&amp;rdquo; was against the spirit of data sharing. Probably. But is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My intention of mentioning digital currencies was simply &lt;strong&gt;to recognize value generated by research work&lt;/strong&gt;. For data sharing, if citations to a shared dataset with DOIs provide an &amp;ldquo;alternate currency&amp;rdquo; worth considering for tenure promotion. What else mechanisms could be created to promote and facilitate data sharing and &amp;mdash; research integrity, in general? I would argue citations might be too narrow, and not &lt;em&gt;enabling&lt;/em&gt; enough. My citation count may signal my prior achievements and help me get funded. But how many grant proposals can I possibly write each year? And a citation count does not represent my reputation in research collaboration, data sharing, peer review, conference organization, etc. &lt;strong&gt;As academics, what values do we generate from our work? How to give ourselves credit (not until once in a lifetime tenure promotions)?&lt;/strong&gt; Crazy? Maybe. But academia is outsourcing &amp;mdash; if not losing &amp;mdash; values generated by us to others &amp;ndash; for-profit publishers, data-rich startups, etc. See the fight for Open Access against the &amp;ldquo;paywall&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2017/07/sci-hub-s-cache-pirated-papers-so-big-subscription-journals-are-doomed-data-analyst&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;sometimes in dramatic unlawful manners&lt;/a&gt;. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencemag.org/news/2016/07/hate-journal-impact-factors-new-study-gives-you-one-more-reason&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;our love-hate relationship with the Impact Factor&lt;/a&gt; or other algorithms like &lt;em&gt;h&lt;/em&gt;-index that influence who get jobs, tenure, and grants. We can stay proud of those nicely formatted PDFs published in high Impact-Factor journals. But what other things can we care more about? If we&amp;rsquo;re not standing with various types of value generated by our work &amp;mdash; during data collect, data analysis, peer review, journal editing, etc. &amp;mdash; it&amp;rsquo;s probably a matter of time another startup or rich company to claim ownership of a piece of our work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If ten years later &lt;strong&gt;learning is earning&lt;/strong&gt; (see the video below), &lt;strong&gt;I predict data sharing, and other value generation or value sharing activities in scholarly research, will also be recognized &amp;mdash; not necessarily with money but with something that can more holistically represent the value of our work and can be used/transacted to enable further scholarly activities.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DcP78cLPGtE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, my heartfelt thanks to our leaders &amp;mdash; esp. Dr. Felice levine from AERA and Drs. Susan Yoon, Jan van Aalst &amp;amp; Bill Sandoval from &lt;a href=&#34;isls.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ISLS&lt;/a&gt; &amp;mdash; in engaging me in this exciting and rewarding journey. I look forward to working further on data sharing and in various inter-related areas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AERA-NSF Workshop: Data Sharing and Research Transparency (Part I)</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-07-25-data-sharing-workshop-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-07-25-data-sharing-workshop-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!-- image: /assets/article_images/data-repository.png

_(Photo Credit: [Roche et al. 2014](https://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.1001779.g001))_ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an honor to be invited to attend the AERA-NSF Workshop on &lt;em&gt;Data Sharing and Research Transparency at the Article Publishing Stage&lt;/em&gt; in Washington, D.C. during July 25‐27, 2017. I am attending as an early career scholar from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://isls.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;International Society of the Learning Sciences&lt;/a&gt; &amp;mdash; my academic home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s only a half-day into the workshop but I&amp;rsquo;m already amazed by so many great thoughts from a full room of journal editors, program officers from funding agencies, and early career peers. Below I&amp;rsquo;m sharing some general (not necessarily representative) themes of ideas discussed so far at the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-sharing-where-are-we&#34;&gt;Data Sharing: Where Are We?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In preparation for the conference, Dr. Felice J. Levine, the workshop convener from AERA, shared out the classic National Academies Report on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nap.edu/catalog/2033.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sharing Research Data&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that was released in 1985. I read it on my flight into D.C. and it was a worth read. What stroke me was: many thoughts I compiled in preparation of the workshop were already elaborated in this 32-year-old report. The value of data sharing is not newly recognized. Many challenges have persisted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before reading this report, I happened to read a much newer article titled &lt;em&gt;Administrative social science data: The challenge of reproducible research&lt;/em&gt; published in &lt;em&gt;Big Data &amp;amp; Society&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; a journal I reviewed for. There are some clear advancements the social science communities (and scholarly communities in general) have made since 1985. For instance, we have various research tools and platforms available these days to facilitate data management, sharing, and publishing. &lt;em&gt;Git&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; a version control system highly recommended by this article &amp;mdash; was nonexistent when the National Academies Report came out; neither were platforms and initiatives such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Science Framework&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataverse.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Harvard Dataverse Network&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://figshare.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Figshare&lt;/a&gt;. However, when juxtaposing challenges discussed in both pieces, what stroke me &amp;mdash; again &amp;mdash; was how slow it has been to shift academic cultures to promote data sharing. Indeed, developing tools are easier, whereas changing cultures at many levels &amp;mdash; e.g., in research labs, departments and colleges, institutions, associations, funding agencies &amp;mdash; are much much more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;discussion-themes&#34;&gt;Discussion Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perspectives from these two pieces were echoed in a round of self-intros at the workshop this afternoon. Below are some keywords I noted, which again, reflect my own bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data.&lt;/strong&gt; One important point was made about what we mean by &lt;em&gt;data&lt;/em&gt;. This is not only about the traditional dichotomy of qualitative vs. quantitative data, but also &amp;mdash; purposes of data, power relations in data and data systems (e.g., whom are served by data), &lt;a href=&#34;http://learning-analytics.info/journals/index.php/JLA/issue/view/405/showToc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shapes of data&lt;/a&gt;, etc. I recently wrote in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/317586037_Unpacking_Learning_Analytics_An_Attempt_to_Tilt_the_Iceberg_in_Chinese&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an invited think piece in Chinese&lt;/a&gt; about how the term &lt;em&gt;data (数据)&lt;/em&gt; originally meant punishing people in ancient Chinese. In the same vein, one colleague commented on the word &lt;em&gt;research&lt;/em&gt; being dirty to Indigenous peoples. These views apply here in educational research data as well and therefore in data sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contexts&lt;/em&gt; of research data are also extremely important. Data shared without sufficient information about their context are useless. This fact places burden on both initial investigators who share data (because they need to explain the context in prep for data sharing) and secondary analysts who need to understand the context (often based on insufficient documentation). More work is probably needed to further unpack &lt;em&gt;data&lt;/em&gt;, and to articulate data that are shareable, situations where data are meaningful to be shared, and constituents of shared data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Culture and practices.&lt;/strong&gt; I believe this topic was mostly discussed so far. Subtopics include &lt;em&gt;incentives&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;disincentives&lt;/em&gt; related to data sharing, which are explored in depth in the National Academies Report. For an assistant professor like me, for example, the current tenure process does not credit my investment in data sharing or data publishing. Even if I publish a dataset with a DOI attached to it, it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t carry the same weight as an empirical piece in a top journal. An editor mentioned it&amp;rsquo;s also considered &amp;ldquo;suboptimal&amp;rdquo; for someone&amp;rsquo;s tenure case to publish a study based on secondary data. While there is currently less credit given to data sharing practices, disincentives abound, which are also elaborated in the National Academies Report. Therefore, data sharing does not only need a few mavericks but systematic investments to incentify and sustain culture changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ethics.&lt;/strong&gt; Another major concern was ethical challenges related to data sharing. It was refreshing to hear from one senior colleague sharing that patients whose data were collected for medical research were eager to have their data shared, because they wished to contribute to the quest for a cure, while laws and ethics guidelines prohibit sharing of personal health data. For me as an early career scholar, I tend to make &amp;ldquo;the minimal ask&amp;rdquo; when preparing my IRB protocols &amp;mdash; only because the IRB work with an IRB office and a school district is already so daunting for someone who&amp;rsquo;s still navigating the systems. I worry that being ambitious in data sharing would undermine the likelihood of getting research protocols approved. In addition to putting a sentence to a journal&amp;rsquo;s homepage saying &amp;ldquo;you should share your data&amp;rdquo;, we need additional resources to help scholars deal with ethical challenges even before a study is conducted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure.&lt;/strong&gt; Numerous initiatives have emerged to support data sharing, and open science in general. I look forward to experts who are in the forefront of these matters to share their work. For example, colleagues from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cos.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for Open Science&lt;/a&gt;, which has developed systems like the Open Science Framework and OSF Preprints, will present tomorrow. As an advocate of open science, I am also intrigued by recent work by writing &amp;amp; preprint platforms like &lt;a href=&#34;authorea.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Authorea&lt;/a&gt; and code sharing platforms like &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeocean.com/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Code Ocean&lt;/a&gt; which do not only allow sharing of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.researchobject.org/overview/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Research Objects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; but more interactive forms of scholarly discourse &amp;amp; content consumption (e.g., interactive visualizations linked with shared data and directly embedded in publications). So, technically we are (almost) there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value.&lt;/strong&gt; At the dinner table, it was refreshing to hear from senior scholars how they had to mail out their manuscripts when submitting to a journal and how they needed to fax their reviews to a journal/conference. At that time, the manuscript was almost the only thing others can see from someone&amp;rsquo;s work. We talked about how we can now assign &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt; to so many &amp;ldquo;middle-products&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;byproducts&amp;rdquo; of academic research in addition to an article as an end-product. This is linked to a point made in &lt;a href=&#34;http://bodong.ch/blog/2017/07/24/value-in-education.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my last blog&lt;/a&gt; post about the need to expand &lt;em&gt;valuation&lt;/em&gt; in education to include artifacts generated in learning processes. After reading emerging, draft guidelines that encourage and, in some cases, enforce citations of shared data, I&amp;rsquo;m increasingly optimistic about new cultures of research and publishing that are yet to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fienberg, S. E., Martin, M. E., &amp;amp; Straf, M. L. (Eds.). (1985). Sharing Research Data. Washington, D.C.: National Academy Press. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nap.edu/catalog/2033.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.nap.edu/catalog/2033.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Playford, C. J., Gayle, V., Connelly, R., &amp;amp; Gray, A. J. G. (2016). Administrative social science data: The challenge of reproducible research. Big Data &amp;amp; Society, 3(2), 2053951716684143. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/2053951716684143&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/2053951716684143&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Value and Valuation in Education</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-07-24-value-in-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-07-24-value-in-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- image: /assets/article_images/apple-1757528_1920.jpg --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his arguments against the &lt;em&gt;Common Core&lt;/em&gt;, Prof. Yong Zhao, a known educational thinker, &lt;a href=&#34;http://zhaolearning.com/2011/09/11/if-lady-gaga-can-be-useful/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;referred to his home village&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was growing up, the most valued talent was the ability to handle water buffalos used to plow the rice field, other than physical strengths to carry things such as newly harvested rice or sweet potatoes. I don’t know for sure how good a water buffalo handler she [Lady Gaga] could be, but I am quite sure she will not be able to run on bumpy muddy paths with 200 pounds of sweet potatoes dangling on each end of a bamboo pole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(See &lt;a href=&#34;http://zhaolearning.com/2011/09/11/if-lady-gaga-can-be-useful/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If Lady Gaga Can be Useful&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The village I grew up happens to be only ~20 miles away from Zhao&amp;rsquo;s. And the situation was the same. As a matter of fact, my grandparents never learned to handle a water buffalo. When it came the season to plow the fields, they had to hire experts &amp;mdash; a situation that could be tough when the only buffalo became fully booked. And as picky farmers, they didn&amp;rsquo;t want to hire any random, potentially lousy buffalo handlers, who might plow shallowly (to save the buffalo&amp;rsquo;s energy) and jeopardize the harvest of a whole year. Indeed, for my grandparents&amp;rsquo; generation in the village, knowing how to handle a water buffalo was valuable, more valuable than going to schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things changed for my parents&amp;rsquo; generation. They saw growing value of formal education. My dad became the first one of his generation in the family to enter a &amp;ldquo;teacher&amp;rsquo;s school&amp;rdquo; (equivalent to high school) and to land a teaching job with a monthly paycheck. My mom went to high school but narrowly missed college. What became remarkable in their careers was the value of &lt;strong&gt;a diploma&lt;/strong&gt;, with which my dad went on to work as a teacher, received additional training, and is now leading a small team in a local educational department. My mom, with &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; a high-school diploma, has been teaching for decades but is not recognized as a formal member of the teaching force. The differences a diploma could make came up a million times at our dinner table. So my parents&amp;rsquo; shared dream was to send me to college &amp;mdash; to get an even better diploma from a much bigger place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pursuit for advanced degrees became exactly what my generation was all about. While my parents could not fully invest in schoolwork because they had to take care of their families, my generation was generally sucked into homework and crazy amounts of standardized tests. I did get a high-school diploma like my mom and ventured 2,000 miles to Beijing for &lt;strong&gt;a college degree&lt;/strong&gt;, which led me to opportunities of doing what I&amp;rsquo;m doing &amp;mdash; a huge privilege for a kid whose dream was as big and as far as going to college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From handling a water buffalo to holding a respected diploma/degree, what is seen as &lt;em&gt;valuable&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;having value&lt;/em&gt;, has dramatically shifted across three generations in my family. If formal education is conceptualized as an activity leading to an outcome. For my grandparents, the outcome was not as valuable as being able to handle a water buffalo. For my parents and myself, the outcome was a diploma, certificate or degree, which accreditates knowledge as &amp;ldquo;entities&amp;rdquo; passed onto us through education and entitles us to work on certain jobs or to pursuit new goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now, what will happen for my son&amp;rsquo;s generation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be possible when my son graduates from college, there is no or very few jobs. This is not being pessimist about the economy, but a reality check given the rise of &lt;strong&gt;automation and artificial intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;. As a report published by McKinsey claims, automation and artificial intelligence could readily carry out 45% of paid activities across the U.S. economy, influencing about 60% of all occupations. While routine tasks in manufacturing, transportation and food service is already being automated, &lt;strong&gt;jobs requiring creativity and emotions are where humanity will be seeking meaningful work in the foreseeable future&lt;/strong&gt; [1]. Even if technical feasibility of automation does not guarantee adoption, education &amp;mdash; which has been (partially) charged with workforce preparation &amp;mdash; is facing hard questions. What if an education does not lead to a job, because there is no, or not enough, jobs? Are curriculum standards limiting the scope of education to areas that would be soon automated? How the &amp;ldquo;achievement gap&amp;rdquo; will be re-lived (not relieved) in an era when the meaning of achievement will be fundamentally redefined?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are enduring another &amp;mdash; and maybe even bigger &amp;mdash; shift in &lt;em&gt;valuation&lt;/em&gt; in education and learning.&lt;/strong&gt; For my grandparents, formal education was irrelevant and learning in schools was too detached from their daily lives. What mattered for them was learning knowledge &lt;em&gt;in-use&lt;/em&gt; and of practical value, like handling a water buffalo, which was not valued in education. This situation changed for my parents&amp;rsquo; and my generation, as formal accreditations from educational institutions are not only relevant but connected to &lt;em&gt;social mobility&lt;/em&gt; more than ever before. Degrees, certificates and transcripts given by respected institutions are trusted accreditation of acquired knowledge and skills valued by curriculum standards. With a teaching certificate, my dad became eligible to teach. With a university degree, many doors opened for me. &lt;strong&gt;These credentials carry great amounts of value and trust&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; not determined by learners and educational institutions, but the broader changing societal landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;one issue with this model is these credentials mark the endpoints of educational experiences which are put in a &amp;ldquo;black box&amp;rdquo; for outsiders&lt;/strong&gt; and are not consistently regarded by the credentialing process in different societies, institutions, departments, or even different iterations of a same course. And yet a same GPA from a same school is equivalently valued, because it is the only thing that gets valued and remains visible after a learning journey is &amp;ldquo;done.&amp;rdquo; Things that get produced in learning towards these credentials are largely disregarded and discarded during credentialing; in most cases, they are not seen as generating value at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is only quite recently in &lt;em&gt;new cultures of learning&lt;/em&gt; [2], where artifacts generated in learning are more recognized. Exciting projects are emerging, e.g., &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.badgealliance.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Badges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and the newer &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://utx.edu/chainscript-iti-present/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Transcripts on blockchain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, which open up new ways to credit learning. Specifically, we can now credit a broader range of learner achievements, democratize the practice of credentialing, and give learners stronger control over their credentials. &lt;strong&gt;However, in many cases a new technology is adopted to embrace an old educational model &amp;mdash; or more precisely an old valuation model that disregards learning in-situ or knowledge that exists in &lt;em&gt;flows&lt;/em&gt; of participation, collaboration, and authentic problem-solving.&lt;/strong&gt; If automation and artificial intelligence are taking away jobs, and if future generations can only find meaningful work at the &amp;ldquo;creative end,&amp;rdquo; some larger questions regarding value and valuation need to be discussed. In the newer context of broad and deep automation, and after decades of discussing &lt;em&gt;21st century competencies&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should be seen as having value in learning processes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who are entitled to the act of valuation, if not (only) traditional institutions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After valuation, how would value be presented? And to whom?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will future learners get paid to learn? Or for what they produce &amp;mdash; such as artifacts, meaningful social connections, something contributing to public goods &amp;mdash; in learning processes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the roles of a curriculum?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How equatable opportunities could be ensured given existing gaps and new divides introduced by any new valuation model?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am curious about your responses to these bizarre or maybe unanswerable questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[1] Sources from McKinsey Quarterly: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/digital-mckinsey/our-insights/where-machines-could-replace-humans-and-where-they-cant-yet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Where machines could replace humans—and where they can’t (yet)&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/digital-mckinsey/our-insights/four-fundamentals-of-workplace-automation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Four fundamentals of workplace automation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2] Thomas, D., &amp;amp; Brown, J. S. (2011). A new culture of learning: Cultivating the imagination for a world of constant change. Lexington, KY: CreateSpace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphing the Reddit Place Sensation with Neo4j</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-04-10-graphing-reddit-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-04-10-graphing-reddit-place/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!-- image: /assets/article_images/ajWiAYi.png --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ver never liked the April Fool&amp;rsquo;s Day, until this year when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; decided to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/announcements/comments/62mesr/place/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;launch a social experiment&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/place/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reddit Place&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is simple. The whole world &amp;ndash; or all Reddit users &amp;ndash; were given a 999 x 999 blank canvas to draw on. Some simple rules apply:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each user could choose one pixel from 16 colors to place anywhere on the canvas. They could place as many pixels of as many colors as they wanted, but they had to wait a few minutes between placing each one. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudoscript.com/reddit-place/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the following 72 hours, amazingly interesting things happened on this 999 x 999 canvas. Below is a gif that gives you a glimpse into what had happened. Numerous accounts of this event have been posted. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://sudoscript.com/reddit-place/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; for a good overview, and more posts can be found at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/place&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reddit Place&lt;/a&gt; itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.redd.it/5p68ukzkwdpy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;graphing-the-reddit-place-with-neo4j&#34;&gt;Graphing the Reddit Place with Neo4j&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reddit Place as a web-based social phenomenon will be remembered and studied by many people. I didn&amp;rsquo;t follow this event at all but was amazed by the various types of participating users, sub-communities who self-organized to achieve certain goals, clashes and fights, evolving rules, impressive artworks, and so on &amp;ndash; all that happened on this little canvas. I&amp;rsquo;m especially intrigued by the emergent, self-organizing processes of constructing, destructing, negotiating, and re-constructing among numerous users and user networks supported by all kinds of communication tools (mostly Reddit itself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/PlaceDevs/comments/637ynq/a_datadump_but_from_a_different_scraper/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a data dump&lt;/a&gt; that captured the history of this event, I could not resist myself from playing with it using &lt;a href=&#34;https://neo4j.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Neo4j&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;importing-data&#34;&gt;Importing data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin with, I wrote the following Cypher scripts to import the csv dump into Neo4j:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% highlight cypher %}
// Set constraints
CREATE CONSTRAINT ON (p:Point) ASSERT p.location IS UNIQUE;
CREATE INDEX ON :User(name);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;// Insert data
USING PERIODIC COMMIT 1000
LOAD CSV FROM &amp;ldquo;file:///export.csv&amp;rdquo; AS l
WITH l, [toInt(l[1]), toInt(l[2])] AS loc
WHERE l[3] IS NOT NULL
MERGE (p:Point {location: loc})
  ON CREATE SET p.location = loc, p.count = 1
  ON MATCH SET p.count = p.count + 1
MERGE (u:User {name: l[3]})
  ON CREATE SET u.name = l[3], u.count = 1
  ON MATCH SET u.count = u.count + 1
MERGE (u)-[r:PAINT]-&amp;gt;(p)
  ON CREATE SET r.count = 1, r.ids = [toInt(l[0])],
    r.colors = [toInt(l[4])], r.times = [toInt(l[5])]
  ON MATCH SET r.count = r.count + 1,
    r.ids = r.ids + toInt(l[0]),
    r.colors = r.colors + toInt(l[4]),
    r.times = r.times + toInt(l[5]);
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure below demonstrates the &lt;em&gt;graph model&lt;/em&gt; of the created Neo4j graph database. The model is quite simple and intuitive, including two node types named &lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Point&lt;/code&gt; and one relationship type named &lt;code&gt;Paint&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/assets/article_images/r-place-graph-model.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took my computer ~22 minutes to create 1.6 million labels, 1.6 million nodes, 28.8 million properties, and 4.13 million relationships in this graph database, the size of which ended up to be 4.30 GB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-queries&#34;&gt;General queries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After data were loaded, I did some quick queries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, who were the most active users?&lt;/strong&gt; User &lt;code&gt;itsnotlupus&lt;/code&gt; won the game as s/he painted for 177 times. This may not sound much but if you multiple 177 by 5 minutes (the &amp;lsquo;cooldown&amp;rsquo; time), you will find the user spent roughly 15 hours painting or contemplating the next pixel on the canvas. This time amount does not include activities in other communication tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where did &lt;code&gt;itsnotlupus&lt;/code&gt; paint?&lt;/strong&gt; Below is a graph showing this user (in the center) and 100 pixels s/he painted on. Note that each pixel is identified by its coordinates in the 2D canvas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/assets/article_images/top-user.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed this user painted a whole lot near &lt;code&gt;Point [380, 880]&lt;/code&gt;. By clicking on the [380, 881] Point node, see below, I could check who else have painted on that spot. 16 other users have painted there. Maybe there were some interesting collisions on that single pixel?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/assets/article_images/top-user-clashes.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which colors did &lt;code&gt;itsnotlupus&lt;/code&gt; use?&lt;/strong&gt; It appeared &lt;code&gt;itsnotlupus&lt;/code&gt; painted &lt;span style=&#34;background-color:#e59500&#34;&gt;#E59500&lt;/span&gt; for 104 times, and &lt;span style=&#34;background-color:#e50000&#34;&gt;#E50000&lt;/span&gt; for 70 times. Do those two colors belong to specific clans &lt;code&gt;itsnotlupus&lt;/code&gt; was affiliated with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% highlight cypher %}
MATCH (u:User {name: &amp;ldquo;itsnotlupus&amp;rdquo;})-[r:PAINT]-&amp;gt;()
WITH collect(r.colors) as colors
UNWIND colors as array
UNWIND array as color
RETURN color, count(color) as count
ORDER BY count DESC LIMIT 10
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-blue-corner&#34;&gt;The Blue Corner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://sudoscript.com/reddit-place/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;, the lower-right corner was occupied by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/BlueCorner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blue&lt;/a&gt;. So I checked the corner pixel [999, 999]. The following Cypher query returned a total of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;10,121&lt;/code&gt; user actions on that single pixel&lt;/strong&gt;. The figure that follows shows 100 of those users who painted at [999, 999].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% highlight cypher %}
MATCH (p:Point {location: [999, 999]})&amp;lt;-[r:PAINT]-()
RETURN count&amp;reg;
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/assets/article_images/999x999-users.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top painters in that corner&lt;/strong&gt; are listed in the figure below. Querying the top [999, 999] painter &lt;code&gt;MrMeltJr&lt;/code&gt; I found him painting &lt;span style=&#34;text-shadow: 4px 4px 2px #0000EA&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;blue (#0000EA)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt; predominantly (105 out of 116 times). He was clearly a member of the Blue Corner sub-community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/assets/article_images/999x999-top-users.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the most used color in that corner?&lt;/strong&gt; The following query found the most dominant color to be &lt;span style=&#34;text-shadow: 4px 4px 2px #0000EA&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#0000EA&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, which appeared for 7400 times, followed by &lt;span style=&#34;text-shadow: 4px 4px 2px #820080&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#820080&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;rsquo;s 2055 times. This finding could be confirmed by the gif above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% highlight cypher %}
MATCH (p:Point {location: [999, 999]})&amp;lt;-[r:PAINT]-()
WITH collect(r.colors) as allColors
UNWIND allColors as array
UNWIND array as color
RETURN color, count(color) as count ORDER BY count DESC LIMIT 10
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-fun-to-come&#34;&gt;More Fun to Come&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These queries are far from even scratching the surface of the complex social phenomenon. Two aspects I&amp;rsquo;m especially interested in exploring (if I have time) are the &lt;code&gt;temporal&lt;/code&gt; aspect of user actions on single pixels and the &lt;code&gt;spacial&lt;/code&gt; aspect of changes with neighboring pixels. In addition, it would also be useful if we could connect communication and coordination among users and communities external to the canvas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, now I see the April Fool&amp;rsquo;s Day could be fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A biased introduction to Learning Analytics: Kicking-off #UMNLACoP</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-03-23-umn-lacop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-03-23-umn-lacop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- image: /assets/article_images/community.jpg

![](/images/article_images/community.jpg)

*(Photo Credit: [Blue Diamond Gallery](http://www.thebluediamondgallery.com/wooden-tile/c/community.html))* --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we kicked off our &lt;a href=&#34;https://cei.umn.edu/courses-programs/learning-analytics-community-practice&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Learning Analytics Community of Practice at UMN&lt;/a&gt; (#UMNLACoP)! Launching this CoP has been a joint effort among the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cei.umn.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for Educational Innovation&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.umn.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;College of Liberal Arts&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.umn.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Libraries&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cehd.umn.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;College of Education and Human Development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During today&amp;rsquo;s kick-off event, I spent 15 minutes presenting a quick introduction to the field of Learning Analytics. Below is an audio recording of my presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/314202983&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next event will be hosted on April 10, 2:30-4:00pm, in Anderson 110. If you are interested in joining #UMNLACoP, sign up via &lt;a href=&#34;http://z.umn.edu/lacop&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://z.umn.edu/lacop&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fostering scientific understanding and epistemic beliefs throughjudgments of promisingness</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-kl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-kl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two tales of time: uncovering the significance of sequentialpatterns among contribution types in knowledge-buildingdiscourse</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-il/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-il/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Learning in General Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/project/adaptive-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/project/adaptive-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this research project is to find better learning and instructional practices utilizing an adaptive learning environment focused on 1000-level chemistry courses. The study is looking to predict outcomes and develop interventions based on student learning behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Building: Theory and Design</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/project/knowledge-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/project/knowledge-building/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networked Learning Environments and Analytics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/project/networked-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/project/networked-learning/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics for knowledge creation: Towards epistemic agency anddesign-mode thinking</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-kn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-kn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schools as knowledge-building organizations: Thirty years ofdesign research</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-od/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-od/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>哲学性的婴儿之二：因果链接</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2014-12-26-philosophical-baby-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2014-12-26-philosophical-baby-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ---
date: &#39;2014-12-26&#39;
title: 哲学性的婴儿之二：因果链接
categories: zh
tags:
- baby
comments: true
--- --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;锵锵，在我写&lt;a href=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/cn/2014/05/27/哲学性的婴儿一婴儿并非弱弱的人类/&#34;&gt;系列之一&lt;/a&gt;时，你刚刚半个月。如今整整七个月过去了，你已经长成一个眼睛四处观察、嘴里牙牙乱语的机灵小伙儿。之所以现在才写第二篇，一方面是因为繁忙，另一方面则因为时常被一个问题叨扰：“眼前这个常无理取闹的家伙真的是充满哲学性的婴儿吗？”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;此时，七个月大的你，正在一旁拨弄着妈咪给你买的圣诞礼物——三个不同样式的小球。这三个小球各有特点：一个五颜六色、带有圆点图案，刺激视觉；一个表面凸凹带有颗粒、抓握方便，刺激触觉；一个内部套有一个装有小颗粒的小球，摇动时会沙沙着响，刺激听觉。当圣诞清晨和你一起拆开礼物时，你拿到每个小球时的第一反应都是拿到嘴边咬一咬、尝尝味道，让我们乐了半天。如今两天过去了，你拿到第一个球时会翻来覆去地看，碰到第二个时会尝试用一只手抓起来，拿到第二个时会不停地摇出声响。我为你不经意的行为有些惊讶——有限的探索，你已经认识了每个球，建立起了有关他们的各种关联。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/81paItJgAVL._SL1500_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;其实我并不应该惊讶。回想起来，从你刚出生被立马放到妈妈胸前时，你已经在建立各种因果关系了。那时的你是那么努力地抬起头，试图看清妈妈的面容。那一刻你是不是已经感受到了妈妈慈爱的眼神、温暖的体温？是不是听到了你妈妈肚子里一直就在听的熟悉的心跳？这一切，是不是都让你觉得可以依靠？如同那些诗句塑造的那样，妈妈于你就意味着“依靠”——无论因为什么原因嚎啕大哭时，妈妈的怀抱是你最好的安慰（当然，爸爸的也不赖哦）。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;你开始识别生活中的不同的人，见到平时就和自己亲近的人会放松，遇到慈祥的老太太时会高兴，碰到陌生的大胡子叔叔时会害怕。这些都并不是简单的如吮吸式的条件反射了，而是你长期的分析判断、概率统计后形成的对人际关系、对爱的理论。一个有趣的心理学实验发现：当小婴儿从一个装有更多白色球的盒子里抓出红色球时，他/她会注视实验人员更长时间，表达困惑。婴儿小小年纪就对概率有清晰的感知。而概率是建立因果关系的重要基础。你小脑袋里建立起的这些理论就藏有你习得各种的因果连接——按动玩具钢琴上的琴键就会播放音乐；拨动蹦椅上的机关就会听到大象的叫声；你用某种眼神看着妈妈、用某种声音喊着妈妈时妈妈会喂你；爸爸把快要睡着的你轻轻放在床上时，代表他要溜走；奶奶和妈妈在厨房忙活是要给你开饭了；我们拍着手喊“一二三”时，是叫你在蹦椅上跳；夜里你吵闹时把你抱起你就知道停止哭泣甚至露出得意的微笑……这些因果关系里，与人相关的来得更加重要，因为你作为婴儿凡事依赖“他人”。通过精确拿捏你和其他人的关系，你就能轻松地把亲人们玩弄于股掌之间，又避免陌生人带来的潜在危险。人际关系上，你可以说已经是个小人精了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;这几个月里，你除了睡觉、吃饭、锻炼身体之外，没干别的——就在忙于织一张&lt;strong&gt;因果关系网&lt;/strong&gt;。手里的球掉了要到地下去找；奶奶给你剥桔子的时候你就张开了嘴；爸爸把你放到床上给你摸香香时就开始兴奋；睡前把你放到妈妈身旁你就知道要开吃了。更重要的是，你的学习不带任何目的——因为这个世界的一切几乎都是新的。我读一篇论文常会带着目的去读，或许时常忽视掉论文里本来更有价值的部分。而你不然，对&lt;strong&gt;所有事物&lt;/strong&gt;（尤其是新事物）都全盘关注，一点都不落下。昨天，我们散步偶然路过一间教堂，进去体验他们的礼拜。你好奇地看着周围的人和事物。每当唱诗班音乐响起，你就欢腾地跳个不停。今天，我们在参观吃饭，你被一台电脑上不时闪烁的蓝色指示灯吸引，默默观察了好久。你其实就像是一位真正的&lt;strong&gt;旅行者&lt;/strong&gt;，把自己的全部感官都交给身处的环境，全身心地去感受身边的人、事、文化、风景。感受得多了，你就积累起了对各种事物的经验推断，自己小脑袋里就装了好多好多小小理论。和我相同的是，你时常可以熟练地运用这些理论进行逻辑推断；和“迂腐顽固”的我不一样的是，当你遇到反例时，短暂的困惑后你会更乐意去修改这些理论，而不是抱着成见不放。凭借你这个建立起来并不断更新的因果网，你似乎已掌握“生存之道”了——当然，目前还是建立在操控大人的基础上 :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;写到这里时，你又在那里开始用力地敲击玩具琴键。每敲击一下，你就能听到一小段音乐，一直敲击音乐就能串联起来成一首曲子。但是对你来说最有意思的是琴键上方的那一小排分别标有小动物头像的按钮，敲击他们会发出各种动物的叫声。你顾不了音乐，乐此不疲地敲击小动物们。或许你正在建立动物和他们叫声的联系吧。像你的“同类们”一样，你有何尝不是充满哲学性的婴儿呢？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://meefen.github.io/assets/babypiano.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>仰视的力量</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2014-06-04-%E4%BB%B0%E8%A7%86%E7%9A%84%E5%8A%9B%E9%87%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2014-06-04-%E4%BB%B0%E8%A7%86%E7%9A%84%E5%8A%9B%E9%87%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ---
date: &#39;2014-06-04&#39;
title: 仰视的力量
categories: zh
tags:
- baby
comments: true
--- --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不知从何时开始，网上开始流传各种卓略的父母如何机智地教育自己孩子的段子。段子的模式通常是这样的：孩子犯了个错误，父亲或母亲机智点拨，孩子人生观瞬间升华。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不知是因为个人对小孩创新的研究兴趣、还是个性批判和叛逆，每每我听到这类段子总会起一身鸡皮疙瘩。我不禁会问：有多少父母这样俯视自己的孩子？有多少父母一生都如此俯视自己的孩子？让父母像大人的学习的段子去哪里了？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;《圣经》的马太福音中有个小故事：有一天，门徒们问耶稣，在天国里谁最伟大？耶稣找来了一个小孩子，指着孩子对门徒们说：你们若不变得像小孩子那样天真，就进不了天国。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;而事实上，孩子能让父母学习的地方远非“很傻很天真” 这一项。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;人的学习绝非传统认识里的知识传输，而是一个复杂、多样的社会化过程。因为身处环境的不同，孩子学到的东西注定和父母是很不一样的。虽然历史中有亘古不变的道理，但一味地让孩子接受自己观念的做法注定是短视的。除开父母之外，孩子在发展过程中不断地在和老师、同伴、亲友、以及媒体交流，他们在很多想法上一定会超越父母。父母需要更多地蹲下来，好好向自己的孩子学习一二才对。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;当父母只想着用他们的观念来控制孩子，教育就已经失败了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;请把“父为子纲”、“不听老人言，会长牛皮癣” 这样的话都扔进历史的窠臼里吧。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>哲学性的婴儿一：婴儿并非弱弱的人类</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2014-05-27-philosophical-baby-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2014-05-27-philosophical-baby-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ---
date: &#39;2014-05-27&#39;
title: &#39;哲学性的婴儿一：婴儿并非弱弱的人类&#39;
categories: zh
tags:
- baby
comments: true
--- --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;既希望你不凡，又希望你无异。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;既希望你超常，又希望你普通。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;既希望你自控，又希望你不羁。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;……&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;你——我们的小婴儿——从降生就就引来了我无限的好奇。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;你是人们常说的那个来讨债的“恶魔”吗？出生后的第二个夜晚，你哭闹了整夜，惊动着同屋的那个安静的小妹妹，害得我抱着你在医院走廊里来回游荡。回到家的头几天，你还是很哭闹——睡觉前、换尿布时、洗澡中、胀气时……有时，你的哭闹声震耳欲聋，让已经十分耐心的我也不禁烦躁。这还不够，你不时地给正在给你换尿布的我来个惊喜，让全家忙不迭地帮你清理。是的，你似乎就是那个传说中的恶魔。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;可后来，你在吃完奶后笑了。微微地，嘴角上扬了一下。这让大家乐开了花。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;有人为你辩护，哭闹是你唯一的表达方式，而解读你的哭闹是我们大人的义务和责任。又有人说，这一切都是进化的结果：人类高级之处是需要在下一代上倾注大量心血、以传递更多知识。然后你伸了个懒腰，又笑了，你成了我们心里的小天使。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;其实我知道，你那一笑或许并非真心。出生的这几天，你大脑在疯长。大量的神经元在连接。别骗我，你那一笑或许就是某根神经触发的结果，让你脸部肌肉抽搐了一下而已。可是你还是卖萌成功博得了家人的欢心，用这么一点点投入换来了十足的回报。我都懒得戳穿你了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;你是一个和我一样的人类吗？对，我是说一个正常的人类。有人说，婴儿是人一种未发育完整时的状态，通过生长逐渐变得完善和复杂。又有人说，婴儿和成人其实是两种完全不同的人类。婴儿其实和成人一样复杂，只是设计有不同的进化功能而已。因此人的发展并非线性，而更像“化茧为蝶”。你到底复杂在哪里？这让我对你更加感兴趣，想从你那里学到新的东西——那些在我还是个婴儿时被遗忘掉的东西。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;第一个我需要向你学习的是你的大脑的开放性和可塑性。这是从婴儿到成人发展过程中丢掉的东西。是的，你现在没有自控能力，因为你大脑负责自控的“前额皮质”还没完全发育。但你因此而变得开放而充满想象。你可以瞪着一个玩具小鸟很久很久。我也不知道你在想些什么，这个世界上还没人知道。但我知道你的大脑现在充满无限可能。它里面连接通畅，就像一个交通良好的城市，往哪里走都可以。而我就自愧不如了，多年的磨砺，我大脑已经被植入了很多程序，让我不自觉地选择更“便捷”的通路。换句话说，你不歧视你大脑里的任何一条链接，而我为了高效已经废弃了很多链接，以致它们日益萎缩了。因此，你大脑不如我高效，却比我更有想象力。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;有一天，你还开始学会注视我的眼睛了。好久，足足有十秒。虽然你没笑着讨好我，但似乎你知道我的存在。你似乎不是那个只顾表达自己需求的“恶魔”，你原来充满社会性。你哭闹时我会给你唱歌，有时你会安静下来，看看我，哪怕一小会。有时你从睡梦中惊醒，我轻轻拍拍你，你睁开眼睛瞥见了我，然后长舒一口气后又睡着了。现在只有两周的你，还没有掌握用声音和动作和我交互，但似乎你已经学会了用眼神和我交流了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;你黑黑的眼睛里，我看到了我的轮廓，还有我身边的事物。你的眼睛是那么的黑，那么的大，那么的透彻，似乎从中我能把事物看得更透彻。此刻，我已经越发期待向你学习更多的关于这个世界的一切。“世界是什么？我们怎么认识世界？我们是什么？世界有什么可能性？”你——充满哲学性的婴儿——似乎是目前为止最能帮我思考这些问题的人了。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“盛宴”还是“深渊”？——反思教育技术现状</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2011-12-04-edtech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2011-12-04-edtech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ---
date: &#39;2011-12-04&#39;
title: &#39;“盛宴”还是“深渊”？——反思教育技术现状&#39;
categories: zh
--- --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;从微博上读到白杨同学的博文“学术盛宴”与自我反思，很有意思。我本科时也顶礼膜拜地聆听过大牛们的教诲，只是我没有她那么幸运，至今还没有遇见我一直敬重的南国农先生。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;文章给我一个很强烈的感受——南先生的讲话在这个会议里似乎有些格格不入。他的惭愧和谦虚映衬着其他的欣欣向荣，他困惑和苦口婆心的对面是其他的牛B哄哄和创造力无限。在这里我也困惑了——困惑的是为什么只有南先生提出困惑。因为我读到的是第二手信息，或许只是因为信息失真了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;但愿真的是信息失真了！在过去的几年时间里，我已经很多次地听到一个急切而自信满满的声音，“中国教育学者不能只跟在西方学者后面亦步亦趋……老外那一套没什么了不起……我们应该在学习理论上自主创新……”作为一个初出茅庐的后生，在听到这种声音时还是很激动的。但再仔细看一看创新出来的东西，又有些失落。回头再看看那句话，分不清那到底是自信还是自卑？位轻言微，我的失落算不得什么，我甚至为在盛宴之际感到失落还有一种罪孽深重之感。可既然说了，就不妨冒天下之大不韪地说下去。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;研究教育技术要扎根教育问题，回归课堂、关注具体学科。本科时听到不少教育技术学人和教育、心理学学者掐架的段子，听得义愤填膺、同仇敌忾。后来发现，人家生气也是由原因的。你教育技术一上来，首先认为自己是一个孤儿，到处找自己的理论基础。逮到了教育学、心理学，却冷不防把人家数落一番，把皮亚杰、布鲁姆的理论给否定了。后来枝叶“繁茂”了，还有人说要升辈份，弄个一级学科，和教育学平起平坐。有那么一些不可思议。后来我想，这种对立有必要吗？或许经历这些年的发展，我们已经改观了许多。但读到学界的一些“理论创新”时，又发现它们没在展现出多少对教育的理解。缺乏对教育问题的思考、脱离课堂和学科教育，让我们丢失了一大片领地和与其他领域合作的机会；欠缺教育研究方法的修为，让一些研究缺乏应有的效力。翻看我们的杂志，有多少研究走出了我们的传统视界？在那些走出去了的研究中，有多少采用了严格合理的研究方法？困住手脚坐在井里，如何不引发如南先生那样的忧虑？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;与教育技术研究相联系的是一些教育技术项目的匆忙上马。一个教育技术产品在一个地区内的广泛推行，经过了多少论证？有多少研究结果发现这个产品对学生的学习是有帮助的？这里边的水不去量也罢，但为什么我们听不到多少别的声音？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;理论创新是一件好事，尤其对中国教育技术界。但唐突和没有研究支撑的理论创新是苍白和短命的。达尔文的自然选择是在经历了几十年的观察和思考后得来的。我们不是不可以挑战西方理论，可我们更不可以在没有深入了解现有理论的基础上去提自己的理论，不然说出去只会闹笑话。从科学史看，一个新理论要站得住需要几个重要的标准：准确、稳定、宽阔的适用范围、简单、富有成效[1]。其中需要强调的是，理论创新不都是踩在别人身上往上爬，其中很重要的一点是建立新理论与现有理论之间的稳定性。在教育领域尤其如此，如果教育技术理论把教育、心理以及社会学里一些成熟的理论都给否定了，那么这样的理论多半也只会是个笑话。此外，理论应该是富有成效的，能解释现有理论解释不了的东西，能为某一问题的研究打开不一样的视角。这样理论才能有后续的研究力量注入，进一步论证、发展和完善这些理论。这些基本条件，我们提的新理论满足了吗？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;教育技术的发展是大家都希望看到的，但有些问题从我9年前进入这个领域时就有却现在还在困扰着我们。是积重难返，还是可以亡羊补牢？南先生在反思，我们能一起反思吗？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;参考文献：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kuhn, T. S. (1977). Objectivity, Value Judgment, and Theory Choice. In M. Lange (Ed.), Philosophy of Science An Anthology (pp. 320-339). University of Chicago Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>《中县干部》 vs. 学术伦理</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2011-11-30-zhongxian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2011-11-30-zhongxian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ---
date: &#39;2011-11-30&#39;
title: &#39;《中县干部》 vs. 学术伦理&#39;
categories: zh
--- --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;两月前从南方周末上读到有关《中县干部》的报道时首先是眼前一亮，并为其作者北大社会学系博士生冯军旗能写出这么有社会价值的论文而深表羡慕。可读完报道时我心底不禁出现一丝疑虑——这样的社会学研究有悖于“学术伦理道德”吗？此时心底另一个声音响起——在一个很多地方（尤其是这篇论文中的研究对象）都缺乏道德的社会，是否真的能去要求研究者遵从学术伦理道德？在一番激烈交锋之后，第一个声音在我这里获胜了。不管别人有没有道德，“斯文人”应该带头讲一讲伦理。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;或许我就是“消夏湾人”在他/她的为《中县干部》辩护中嗤之以鼻的“喜欢高举学术中立大旗、挟洋自重、迂腐不化”之人。消某的文章直指之人即是对《中县干部》在学术伦理环节提出质疑的旅美学者程海华。程海华认为，“学者是研究人员，而不是新闻记者或执法者，并不肩负揭黑打黑的责任。‘卧底式’研究是违反学术道德而绝对禁止的。社会科学伦理审查制度不仅保护了被采访研究对象，也防止研究者超越身份的研究遭受被采访者的报复。”但在消某看来，美国的学术伦理审查对于社会学研究是摆设，因为社会学、政治学和人类学这类研究对研究对象造不成像医学研究那样的直接伤害，而审查的目的更重要的是保证研究的公信力，在众多耗资巨费的大样本研究中剔除那些没价值的研究。消某的信口开河其实不值得一驳。翻看任何一所研究型大学的学术伦理审查委员会网站（如多伦多大学REB）都可以看到，维持研究的正当性和保护研究对象的正当权利是学术伦理审查的基本目的，而这远非论文成文时的匿名处理所能保障的。通常情况下，研究者需要收集研究对象的书面同意书，否则从研究对象那里获得的数据是不应该被分析和写入论文的。《中县干部》显然触犯了这一基本准则。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;站在消那边的还有媒体评论人“鱼竹舟”。他的基本论点是美国那一套不适合我们的国情。他的观点在环球网的投票中也得到了更多的支持，这一民意在程海华文章及朱迅垚分别的一篇文章的评论留言里也能体现。大众对学术伦理存在价值的不认可，是让我最担心的地方。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;《中县干部》这个案例中冯军旗似乎是为侠士。侠士精神在中国似乎一直以来很受爱戴，这多少干扰了我们在这个案例里对学术伦理的判断。换一个目前被推上风口浪尖的校车问题。针对资金困难的问题，北师大某位教授另辟溪径，提议我们让学生们乘坐校车时刷卡，同时记录下学生的身高、体重等数据，转手把这些数据卖给有需要的机构，从而弥补一部分校车运营成本。试问全国中小学学生的此类隐私数据，谁可以随意去收集和专卖？这种提议从研究者口里提出来，可以反映出学术伦理在我们很多研究者心里几乎可有可无。研究者尚且如此，况大众乎？《中县干部》的研究在很多人眼里是在“除暴安良”，但社会民愤不应掩盖其不符合伦理的研究行为。假如研究的对象是如农村留守儿童、残疾人等容易受到伤害的人时，大家还会觉得伦理道德不重要吗？对研究对象的伤害可能在无意间造成，仅仅依靠研究者的自律是不够的。如果没有一个经验丰富、可靠的机构去审查研究提案，在研究之前如果没有充分考虑研究可能给研究对象带来的伤害，被研究者就容易受到伤害。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;研究（research）这个词蕴含着研究者和被研究者之间不平等的权力关系。当欧洲殖民者对北美土著进行研究，并把研究结果用来指导新的殖民政策制定时，研究是一个十分肮脏的词汇。如今，纵使研究这个词早已变得神圣了许多，研究和被研究的关系仍然使得被研究者处在弱势的地位。通过伦理审查保证研究的正当性是对被研究者的保护，其实也是对研究者的保护。在此呼吁包括政策制定者、大学和科研单位等相关部门重视起来，虽然我知道你们一直都忙得很。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;相关链接：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;南方周末——中县“政治家族”现象调查，&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infzm.com/content/62798&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.infzm.com/content/62798&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;程海华：《中县干部》有悖学术伦理，&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.douban.com/group/topic/23631020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.douban.com/group/topic/23631020/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;环球——《中县干部》有悖学术伦理？ &lt;a href=&#34;http://opinion.huanqiu.com/pk/2011-11/2143434.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://opinion.huanqiu.com/pk/2011-11/2143434.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;朱迅垚：《中县干部》纯属炒作，&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.tianya.cn/blogger/post_read.asp?BlogID=1217970&amp;amp;PostID=36828899&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://blog.tianya.cn/blogger/post_read.asp?BlogID=1217970&amp;amp;PostID=36828899&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;消夏湾人：为《中县干部》辩护 &amp;mdash;-学术伦理和学术创新应符合中国国情，&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chinaelections.org/newsinfo.asp?newsid=217591&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.chinaelections.org/newsinfo.asp?newsid=217591&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>教育改革成效的影响因素</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2010-11-29-education-reforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2010-11-29-education-reforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ---
date: &#39;2010-11-29&#39;
title: &#39;教育改革成效的影响因素&#39;
categories: zh --&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;这是一个极其复杂和难辩的题目，不过最近有幸读了一些有关教育改革的文章，索性也胡乱说一说。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“现代课程理论”和“现代教学测量”之父泰勒在接受一个采访时提到，他很庆幸他所在的国家的联邦政府、州政府把大量有关课程的教育决策权“下放”到通常以学区为单位的学校委员会（school board），学校委员会有时还会进一步把修改课程的权力进一步下放到学校。这里用下放这个词在一些人眼里是不正确的，因为课程理论研究了这么多年，对于课程应该源于哪里，教育的目的应该是什么从未有定见。泰勒眼里的教育是通过让个人接受普世价值而让这个社会粘合在一起，因此强调教育的社会功能。而研究权力理论的人会把教育看作是掌权者用来继续维持他们权力的工具。后现代思潮中的学者或许会更强调教育的多重性和文化相关性，认为课程要融入目标群体的文化特性。相比这种分散式的教育/课程决策体系，集中式的、至上而下的教育决策体系也在一些国家存在，如俄罗斯、中国、法国和二战前夕的德国。泰勒在上个世纪六七十年代分别到访过莫斯科和北京，他描述的情形和我经历的教育完全是吻合的。看来在我们经历的自上而下的教育体系中，教育变革的幅度是比较小的，速度是比较慢的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;那么如泰勒描述的那种分权、去中心化模式是否能带来大量的变革呢？另一位学者库班在1988年的一篇文章里给出了否定的答案。他分析美国20世纪的教育改革，发现依然只有少量的成功的教育变革。对于教育改革，他做了一个类比。美国航天局1986年1月28日发射的“挑战者号”航天飞机在发射后73秒后坠毁，7名航天员全部遇难。在之后的调查中，美国航天局主要从“飞船设计失误”和“质量控制”两个方面找原因，试图找到改善现状的方法。库班认为教育改革通常也是如此。与“飞船及发射质量控制”和“飞船基本设计”两个方面相对应，他把教育变革分为两类：“一级变革”和“二级变革”。一级变革指的是在不对现有系统伤筋动骨的基础上，尝试去让现有系统更有效、更具效率。对于飞船事故来说，就是去看是否在某些细小环节上存在瑕疵，并努力去修正它。二级变革则不同，它通常是去寻找整个系统设计的缺陷，是对系统的大幅度的修正。对于飞船来说就是去看是否是因为整体设计上的失误导致了这次事故。对应到教育领域中，库班认为之所以过去一个世纪里的教育在工业时代建立起来的学校体系的基础上没有大的变化，是因为这个世纪里取得成功的教育改革大多多是“一级变革”，而只有很少的“二级变革”取得了成功。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;那么为什么那么多的教育改革失败了呢？他认为一个很重要的原因是大量教育变革都把改变教师行为作为一个重要的目标，而很多改革的主导者却并没有真正去理解一个教师在学校里每天最基本的实践是什么，没有去认真分析改革情境里的一些现状，最后遭到了包括很多教师和学校领导在内的抵抗。几天前读到深圳一位一线教师转发的一篇叫做“教师很疲惫”的文章，描述教师对于一些社会部门“进校园活动”疲于奔命，而不能把更多精力投入到教学思考的现状。文中提到这些社会部门的进校园活动为学校安排了多达18门在国家课程计划规定之外的课程，其中有很多重复和冗余，耗费了师生的大量精力。暂不谈这些“进校园活动”的动机到底是某些部门的面子工程，还是真的是在响应“校本课程”的号召，单就教师的反应来看，这个变革就已经失败了。或许这不是一个关于改变教师行为的例子，但却体现了目前我们在进行的一些如火如荼的变革中，在我们的自上而下的模式里缺少一种对现实情境的具体分析。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;另一个决定“二级变革”是否成功的关键是改革是否能获得社会、立法和政府部门的支持。从2002年麻省理工大学（MIT）尝试开放该校的课程开始，开放教育资源运动已经席卷全球。中国也有我们自己的全国范围内巨大规模的“精品课程”项目。开放教育资源运动除了有广泛的社会需求（让更多的人获得名牌高校的教育资源）之外，还有大量科研基金会及政府政策导引的支持。因此这是一个目前来看取得很大成功的“二级变革”。同时，几天前我也读到了南方人物周刊上有关国内教育技术界的大师、北师大何克抗教授的“跨越式项目”的报道。根据报道，虽然项目在研究上获得了很多数据去证明它的成功，却因迟迟不能获得高层领导的支持而陷入困境。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;比库班更早的一篇发表于1972年的文章分析了在那之前75年内美国发生的各种教育改革。有别于库班的那篇思辨性文章，这篇文章从分析这些教育改革的多项特性出发去分析影响教育改革成败的因素。这些特性包括改革的年代（1950年前还是后）、起因来自教育系统内部还是外部、变革关注什么领域（教学/课程/组织和管理）、以及对改革成效的打分。文章通过一系列分析得出的结果与库班的论点有很多吻合之处。比如，这篇文章的作者也认为如果一个教育改革要求教师抛弃现有的实践方式而接受一种全新的时间方式，那么这项改革就有更大失败的危险。同时，一项改革给人们带来的认知负担会影响这项改革的成效能否长期维持下去。他们也发现由外部发起的变革比从教育内部发起的变革成功率更高。此外他们还提到如果缺少一个扩散系统，改革也很容易流产。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;了解这些现实或许会让迫切希望变革的人被关起来。但与此同时，理解这些因素对于教育改革又是十分重要的。我也发现，无论是在一种自上而下还是自下而上的体系中，获得包括立法、社会和政府等各种力量的支持对于教育改革的成败起着巨大的作用（对于中国，这三个因素的顺序应该倒过来——政府、社会和立法，因为我们目前是一种大政府小社会的体系）。我们一直在抱怨教育，我们也有很多如何教授那样一心想要改变教育的人在努力，可现实是我们由中央组织教育专家制定的改革纲要通过“粗壮”但却“笨重”的自上而下的渠道传播逐级失真，而“纤细瘦弱”的自下而上的渠道经常会被切断。这也解释了为什么把2001年的颁布的基础教育课程改革纲要拿到现在来看，你会以为是今年刚颁布的新的改革纲要，因为里边的很多内容在10之后去看还只能是理想。到头来，对教育改革的认识，还是要回到对“教育是什么”的问题上来。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>五月的天</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2009-05-12-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2009-05-12-may/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;北京五月的天不属于与茁壮的玉米苗笑脸相迎的白云朵朵，而属于漫天飞舞张牙舞爪的杨树的生殖细胞。印象中的五月不应当如此炎热，因为炎热往常在校园里聚起各种巫师模样衣服的人群，也该意味着楼下西门鸡翅每晚绵延到深夜的喧闹的酒瓶声。是的，炎热就意味着一群人该离开了，无论是在曾经师大的京师广场，还是如今燕园的各个角落。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;岁月在无情地变迁。一年后，废墟不远的地方已经是笙歌四起。印象中四川五月的天特别美，或许是因为在我眼里四川的天就没有不美的时候。春意散去带来的是漫山遍野的葱翠，天也显得格外清新。一年前的现在还在焦急地给亲人和朋友联系，守着BBS，看着新闻报道暗自着急。一年前的震动唤起了人的巨大的力量让人心潮澎湃，感动和流泪之后对遇到的每一个人似乎都有了新的一份亲近。一年了，生活在坚强地继续，而生活也渐渐回归了原貌。地震掩埋了千千万万的人民，而“希望重建不要倒下一批一批的干部”。生存的需要得到满足时，人们的需求变成了更好地生存。生命受到威胁的一瞬间人人是平等的，但是当生命警报消除时，一切又渐渐回归原位。读了野夫的《余震绵延的大地》，对震动后的现实多了一点了解，同时也多了各种忧虑。地震不可能让北川、让灾区瞬间变成中国精神文明的示范区，那里是人均收入和人均图书拥有量远远低于北京的地方，广大的农民大众对生活的需求还是最大化对自己的补偿。ZF和人民，人民和利益群体，利益群体与ZF，又有了更多新的博弈。余震延绵的大地上，一切都还远未平息。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;五月天空下的798比预想的要炎热得多，而今天却比预想的要冷清。去早了等不上下午的5.12纪念艺术展，只遇到了展示3000名北川学生大头贴和几本日记的小展厅。似乎这里的人们遗忘得更快。其实我真不懂艺术，更不懂绘画、雕塑、陶艺……但当走完几个展厅之后，突然觉得我好喜欢这里。荒诞和夸张，抽象和朦胧，戏谑和调侃，对人和事物的细致描绘，对生活和意识的深刻反讽，对内心和人性的投影和揭露……纵使自己看不懂艺术，但也这样喜欢着艺术。同时也开始羡慕起了玩艺术的人，虽然心头还是觉得不如玩学术靠谱，但十分妒忌他们拥有的肆意洒脱的心灵，而我一玩洒脱却可能立马遭到各种学究的无情挑剔。生活啊，多么的不同！如果再给我个机会，也一定要洒脱一把。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;五月，这个城市已经占有了我生命中的7大个五月，够了。在期许绵延的心里，又在勾画着就要新开始的一切。回想起来自己还只经历过两种五月，四川的五月葱绿自然，北京的五月明亮躁动。下个五月呢？据说多伦多的五月是值得期待的——因为那里五月时冬天刚刚结束。。。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>自习室</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2006-06-20-zixishi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2006 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/zh/2006-06-20-zixishi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ---
date: &#39;2006-06-20&#39;
title: &#39;自习室&#39;
--- --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;喜欢教二楼，因为靠近繁忙的街道。喜欢教二楼，因为它给我带来宁静。累了，我喜欢靠着临近街道的窗户，看着过往的车辆和天桥上的行人。看着外面的繁忙，我的心里一片宁静。有时，会瓢泼大雨，透过雨帘，汽车疾驰的声音传来，清脆的、悦耳的。下雪了，一片白色，寒冷，冷风袭来。这时只能透过厚厚的玻璃和薄薄的雾气观赏这一切，犹如一个旁观者，看着来往过客。现在想来，我本也是教二楼的过客，匆匆，不留下痕迹（因为我不在课桌上刻字），保洁员用拖把抹去了我的脚印，后来着占据了我以前习惯的位置。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;大二的日子，白天上本专业的课，晚上辅修课。有时会感到累了，于是去窗边看看，或者看一两句宋词。总之枯燥的自习室里也有乐趣，现在想来那时的我是稚嫩和自我满足的。就像下面这首词那样，些许调侃，但仅是百无聊赖者的自娱罢了。这就是大学学习的基调，我的蓝色的基调！&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;杂词&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
一夜秋风，&lt;br /&gt;
叶尽黄，&lt;br /&gt;
小径踏满。&lt;br /&gt;
颓树缺月，&lt;br /&gt;
幽人望，&lt;br /&gt;
别恨心间。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/slides/example-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/slides/example-slides/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-slides&#34;&gt;Welcome to Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = \;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
