<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bodong Chen on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>https://meefen.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bodong Chen on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Bodong Chen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>#LAK19 Conference Report [Part 1]: Pre-Conference Workshops</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-03-08-lak19-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 21:45:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2019-03-08-lak19-part1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I just came back from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lak19.solaresearch.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2019 &lt;em&gt;Learning Analytics and Knowledge (LAK)&lt;/em&gt; conference&lt;/a&gt; hosted by Arizona State University. This conference, surely one of my favorites, is inching to its 10th anniversary next year. I still remember when I was in the 2nd year of my PhD in 2010, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.si.umich.edu/people/chris-teplovs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chris Teplovs&lt;/a&gt; told me about &lt;a href=&#34;https://tekri.athabascau.ca/analytics/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an exciting, upcoming gathering&lt;/a&gt; of 60~ people in Banff, Canada to discuss a thing called &amp;ldquo;learning analytics.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After nearly a decade of development, we see clear progress this community has accomplished. The growth of the conference size itself, from 60 to  500+ attendees, while impressive, does not speak to the international sensation around this topic. As someone who first attended LAK as a doctoral student in 2014 and now work on a tenure-track position to grow this area at my institution, I can speak to my lived experiences of observing the rise of local interests in this topic (e.g., the &amp;ldquo;R1&amp;rdquo; university I&amp;rsquo;m part of, the state&amp;rsquo;s Department of Education), as well as an international passion for learning analytics when I travel to Singapore, Manila, Beijing, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rise of learning analytics (the field), LAK (its conference) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://solaresearch.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SoLAR&lt;/a&gt; (its society), coincides with many other things. In education, there is a push for &amp;ldquo;evidence-based practice&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;data use&amp;rdquo; in schools (however we mean by evidence or data). In EdTech, words like A.I., adaptive learning, personalization are mentioned in board rooms, websites of philanthropist foundations, and news headlines. Of course, an earlier surge of MOOCs and an ongoing rise of online, lifelong learning demand analytic supports while also offering fertile arenas for the field of learning analytics to grow. In many cases, learning analytics are truly needed and making impossible things possible. But in others, it&amp;rsquo;s scooped up to be a tag on a product to drive sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realities, for better or worse, just like many other fields we can think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overall-impression-of-lak19&#34;&gt;Overall impression of LAK19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, many thanks to the amazing organizing team who has done a wonderful job to make everything real and enjoyable! The program is cohesively organized; conference amenities are thoughtfully arranged; student volunteers are amazing. These are on top of myself escaping -20C weather in Minnesota for the 20C dessert temperature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; Defrosting in progress. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/C1lPgc52XE&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/C1lPgc52XE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Bodong Chen (@bod0ng) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng/status/1102575805559758849?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 4, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the community grows bigger, I always found multiple concurrent sessions/talks I hoped to check out. So my impression and report of this conference are surely biased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday-full-day-workshop-on-connectivism&#34;&gt;Monday: Full-Day Workshop on Connectivism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to this workshops mainly for jokes among Canadians, Aussies, and Serbians :). I was sorted of disappointed because &lt;a href=&#34;https://vitomir.kovanovic.info/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vita&lt;/a&gt; was clearly jet-lagged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jokes aside, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Connectivism&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Connectivism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, George Siemens, and Stephen Downes for years. Many ideas under Connectivism resonate with me, as my research is grounded in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_building&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Knowledge-Building Community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; model created by Scardamalia and Bereiter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George kicked off the workshop by briefly explaining its 15-year history. Connectivism emerged in the early stage of the Read/Write web (Web 2.0) and grew out of a dissatisfaction with existing frameworks of learning that were not very helpful in explaining the construction of &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo; knowledge in a networked world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core arguments made by Connectivism are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge is networked&lt;/strong&gt;. This idea is in line with works from Rosen (2012), combinatorial creativity, Nielsen (2013), and Borner (network of science).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning is the process of developing those networks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These two ideas apply beyond learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this workshop, George challenged us to work on &lt;strong&gt;three domains where learning is networked: Neural; Cognitive/Conceptual; and Social/External&lt;/strong&gt;. Future work on Connectivism should try to deliver quality empirical research about networked learning at these levels, detail how things fit together, integrate networks across levels, and articulate human and artificial cognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critiques of Connectivism as a learning theory were mentioned for multiple times. It&amp;rsquo;s probably accurate to say George found these critiques fair and highlighted that Connectivism meant to provide a framework (or paradigm) to think about knowledge and learning differently. There is a vast empty space left by Connectivism, including pedagogy, learning analytics, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Downes joined the workshop remotely and shared a very informative review* of recent work on connectivism. His review looked at scholars&amp;rsquo; various interpretations of connectivism, criticisms, connectivism as pedagogy (e.g., &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irrodl.org/index.php/irrodl/article/view/3269&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wang, Anderson, &amp;amp; Chen 2018&lt;/a&gt;), connectivism as a theory of learning, and properties of a successful network. He offered a number of future directions, including critical thinking and deep learning (not the ML sense), rhizomatic learning, social networking, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/303894484_What_Are_Cognitive_Cities&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cognitive cities&lt;/a&gt;. Listening to such a review from one of the creators was helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(*: &lt;em&gt;As a strong advocate of open scholarship, Stephen may have chosen to focus this review on open-access publications.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming into this workshop, I was looking for two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conceptually, I was wondering why many research papers on cMOOCs used frameworks such as the &lt;em&gt;Community of Inquiry&lt;/em&gt; to examine connectivist learning instead of connectivism itself. I was curious about further articulation of connectivism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In terms of design &amp;ndash; of both connectivist learning environments and analytics &amp;ndash; I was looking for design principles and design ideas to inform some of our ongoing projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Four principles&lt;/strong&gt; of connectivism Stephen laid out later was quite useful. These principles include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomy&lt;/strong&gt; of learners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diversity&lt;/strong&gt; of learners, ideas, information, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Openness&lt;/strong&gt; of the environment and process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactivity&lt;/strong&gt; within the network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found these principles valuable even though more work is needed to further unpack and articulate them. Stephen predicted a shift is going to happen (if not yet) even if it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily tagged with connectivism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the workshop, there were several interesting research talks as well, including analyzing group communication, assessing idea development using &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compartmental_models_in_epidemiology&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;epidemiological modeling&lt;/a&gt;, and modeling network dynamics. They represented promising directions to further advance connectivism, especially in the areas of analyzing connective learning processes and developing automated indices about connective learning. More details can be found on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://connectivism.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;workshop website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I very much appreciated the multi-level network view laid out by George and his urge for us to connect levels. These ideas are informative for my recent thinking, tinkering, and design (since 2017) to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Represent, describe, and model learning (at multiple levels) as complex networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design tools for &lt;em&gt;personal, connectivist learning&lt;/em&gt; that give learners agency to maintain their networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brainstorm an analytical infrastructure that maintains complexity of all sorts of learning processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attending this workshop was a treat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday-workshop-on-fairness&#34;&gt;Tuesday: Workshop on Fairness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an honor to give an invited talk about &lt;em&gt;Value-Sensitive Design&lt;/em&gt; in learning analytics at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/fairlak&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FairLAK workshop&lt;/a&gt; organized by Kenneth Holstein and Shayan Doroudi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a timely workshop that deals with a topic that&amp;rsquo;s critical for our work in this community and beyond. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know there are 21 fairness definitions (Narayanan, 2018; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jIXIuYdnyyk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Youtube video&lt;/a&gt;). During my limited time spent at the workshop, it is refreshing to see multiple approaches to consider fairness, ranging from creating new metric based on slice analysis to evaluate fairness in predictive models (Josh Gardner), to applying the Socio-Technical Integration Research approach to design processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program and slides of the FairLAK workshop can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/fairlak&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;its website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday-workshop-on-curriculum-development-in-la-programs&#34;&gt;Tuesday: Workshop on Curriculum Development in LA Programs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephanie Teasley and John Stamper asked to stop by another workshop about curriculum development in learning analytics. It was half-way through after coming from the FairLAK workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charles Lang and Leah Macfadyen showed us their informative reviews of degree programs related to learning analytics. John Stamper showed us &lt;a href=&#34;https://hcii.cmu.edu/masters-educational-technology-and-applied-learning-science-program-overview&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CMU&amp;rsquo;s Master&amp;rsquo;s Educational Technology and Applied Learning Science program&lt;/a&gt; that interestingly integrates courses from different disciplines and connects deeply with the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following Charles&amp;rsquo; lead, we even got a chance to co-design a class activity to engage students to consider and experience themselves as data &lt;em&gt;producers&lt;/em&gt;, data &lt;em&gt;analysts&lt;/em&gt;, and analytics &lt;em&gt;consumers&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;I believe nurturing criticality in all course of a learning analytics program is critical.&lt;/strong&gt; Interesting activities like this could be very helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed collectively mapping out a learning analytics curriculum. Workshop leaders will be working on compiling a list of courses and syllabi to be shared on the SoLAR website. I look forward to being part of this important work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-pre-conference-workshops&#34;&gt;Other Pre-Conference Workshops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many interesting workshops happening at LAK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Writing Analytics workshop&lt;/strong&gt; has generously shared &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1cwd90hDVQgDwK_wODCfuA7SXti9pufjWIGU1cV_gDCU/edit#heading=h.lq1iijue859q&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;their notes&lt;/a&gt; that I look forward to dig into. Mladen Rakovic from SFU channeled some &amp;ldquo;knowledge telling vs. knowledge transforming&amp;rdquo; wisdom I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Writing analytics for helping students move from knowledge telling to knowledge transforming in writing &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/WaLAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#WaLAK19&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MladenRakovic?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@MladenRakovic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/TIb20hWbRl&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/TIb20hWbRl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Shibani Antonette (@ShibaniAntonett) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ShibaniAntonett/status/1102637203748876288?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 4, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Doctoral Consortium seemed to be going strong as well! I chatted with a couple of student participants during the conference. I&amp;rsquo;m sure they received great advice from this panel. As you may find out from a SoLAR 10-year anniversary video, I feel in debt to this community especially because we&amp;rsquo;re invested in emerging scholars. Way to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LAK19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#LAK19&lt;/a&gt; Doctoral Consortium careers panel with special guests  ⁦&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aekrumm?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@aekrumm&lt;/a&gt;⁩ &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sasha?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@sasha&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/whitmer?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@whitmer&lt;/a&gt; joining the co-chairs to share the pros and cons of future trajectories After The PhD&amp;hellip;! &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/RheoO3IOH2&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/RheoO3IOH2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Simon Buckingham Shum (@sbuckshum) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sbuckshum/status/1103071063141838848?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 5, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for later parts of the LAK19 conference report&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Value-Sensitive Learning Analytics Design</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 21:08:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-lak/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Use in K-12 Schools: Cases from North America</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-mingda-institute-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-mingda-institute-lecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the Google Slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotation as Infrastructure for Next Generation Digital Learning Environments</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-educause/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-educause/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the Google Slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#OAWeek 2018: My Personal Journey</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-10-oa-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 19:48:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-10-oa-week/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This week is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openaccessweek.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Access Week 2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Yesterday we spent some time during a student advising meeting talking about the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; of Open Access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Access Week website has provided &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openaccessweek.org/profiles/blogs/researchers-ideas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a great list of ideas for researchers to get involved in Open Access&lt;/a&gt;. My own institution does have an &lt;a href=&#34;https://policy.umn.edu/research/scholarlyarticles&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Access policy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.umn.edu/openaccess&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Our univeristy library system&lt;/a&gt; also provides support for Open Access including &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.umn.edu/openaccess/open-access-publishing-fund&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an Open Access Publishing Fund&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://conservancy.umn.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a Digital Conservancy system&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://conservancy.umn.edu/handle/11299/166578&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a Research Data Repository&lt;/a&gt;, etc. Not to mention my college is spearheading the &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.cehd.umn.edu/otn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Textbook Library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I am writing up a few vignettes based on my humble journey with Open Access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-aware&#34;&gt;Being Aware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009, I became aware of Open Access during a talk at Beijing Normal (probably given by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/houshuang&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stian Haklev&lt;/a&gt;). At that time, he was finishing up his master&amp;rsquo;s thesis on &amp;ldquo;top-quality open courses in China,&amp;rdquo; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://p2pu.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;P2PU&lt;/a&gt; he co-founded was still an emerging thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Open access, Open license, &amp;quot;Free Speech/Beer&amp;quot;, Peer production, Yochai Benkler, P2PU, CMU OLI, Stephen Downes, SLL&amp;hellip; (May 31th in BNU)&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; ʙᴏᴅᴏɴɢ ᴄʜᴇɴ (@bod0ng) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng/status/1981115328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;May 31, 2009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, I participated in an Open Access Week event at OISE of the University of Toronto. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.utsc.utoronto.ca/acm/leslie-chan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Leslie Chan&lt;/a&gt;, a professor from University of Toronto at Scarborough, and Stian were running a panel in the OISE library. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember what they were presenting but I&amp;rsquo;m quite sure their arguments were so eloquent that I became invested in Open Access on that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sharing-drafts-posting-preprints&#34;&gt;Sharing Drafts, Posting Preprints&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I participated in a fun discussion with colleagues from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ai.umich.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Office of Innovation&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Michigan about my paper about &lt;a href=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-tw/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;unLMS&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. Interestingly, this paper has yet to be included in a formal, printed issue of the journal &lt;em&gt;TechTrends&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Great turnout for brown bag lunch with guest  &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@bod0ng&lt;/a&gt; on networked collaborative discourse &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UMichiganAI?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@UMichiganAI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rebquintana?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@rebquintana&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/fwe2thdsJE&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/fwe2thdsJE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Nobuko Fujita (@nobukofujita) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nobukofujita/status/1055855364405526528?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;October 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the timeline of this particular piece of work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In April 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, I started an open manuscript on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.authorea.com/users/4746/articles/169983-designing-for-collaborative-discourse-in-an-online-class-an-unlms-approach&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Authorea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;authorea.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In June 2017&lt;/strong&gt;, before submitting this paper to &lt;em&gt;TechTrends&lt;/em&gt;, I openly invitated colleagues on Twitter to comment on this manscripts. I received a bunch of comments from Stian, which I incorporated into the submitted version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;authorea-hy.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Jan 2018&lt;/strong&gt;, I uploaded &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/ebjfp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a &lt;em&gt;preprint&lt;/em&gt; on the Open Science Framework&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dr_jdean&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jeremy Dean&lt;/a&gt; from Hypothes.is chimed in on Authorea later in Jan 2018 and we eventually met in June 2018 at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://iannotate.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I Annotate&lt;/a&gt; conference in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;osf.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On April 22, 2018&lt;/strong&gt;, after going through two rounds of revisions (with great comments from reviewers and the editor), the article was publised &amp;ldquo;Online First&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;TechTrends&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till now, &lt;strong&gt;October 2018&lt;/strong&gt;, this article is still in its &amp;ldquo;Online First&amp;rdquo; status and may get included in an issue next year. However:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;its first version on Authorea has been annotated 24 times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;its OSF preprint has been downloaded 89 times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;its Springer &amp;ldquo;Online First&amp;rdquo; version has been downloaded 89 times, shared 14 times, and annotated 43 times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From its inception in 2017 to its &amp;ldquo;formal&amp;rdquo; appearance in a printed issue in 2019, a whole lot has happened to this particular work.&lt;/strong&gt; Indeed, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent extra hours to make things work (e.g., converting between document formats, uploading to OSF). But this journey, which I did not anticipate in the beginning, has been extremely rewarding. This article may not be my seminal work, but &lt;strong&gt;it is reassuring that by doing bits and pieces related to Open Access, we as researchers can (1) receive feedback from a broader audience, (2) make valuable connections with colleagues, and (3) get our work read and discussed &amp;ndash; much earlier than its formal publication&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;voicing-the-stance&#34;&gt;Voicing the Stance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the power of Open Access &amp;ndash; and more broadly, &lt;a href=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/notes&#34;&gt;Open Scholarship&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced so far, &lt;strong&gt;it is unfortunate some disciplines and some tenure committees (&lt;em&gt;not mine&lt;/em&gt;) would bluntly equate Open Access with &amp;ldquo;lesser quality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.sciencemag.org/books/2018/01/30/the-tyranny-of-metrics/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tyranny of metrics&lt;/a&gt; is worth a separate post. But here I want to share a statement related to Open Access I decided to include in my dossier (as a tenure-track professor):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an interdisciplinary scholar, I seek to publish in refereed journals from various fields of research, including learning sciences, educational technology, educational psychology, and learning analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an advocate of Open Scholarship, I also attempt to balance my publication venues between “traditional” journals and quality open-access alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a scholar with Chinese heritage, I also write for audiences who speak my mother tongue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite 10 years of #OpenAccessWeek, we still have a long way to go to make &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Invisible Labour&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; in Open Scholarship visible and valued. This is a sudden realization I had this year, thanks to the tweet below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-cards=&#34;hidden&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/OAweek?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#OAweek&lt;/a&gt; event in Vancouver BC Canada: Open but not free: Invisible Labour in Open Scholarship. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/aNz8txzD1c&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/aNz8txzD1c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Christina Hendricks (@clhendricksbc) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/clhendricksbc/status/1055265533765926912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;October 25, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I will continue to do those &amp;ldquo;bits and pieces,&amp;rdquo; I will especially try to be a strong adavocate for: (1) valuing work published in many quality open-access journals, and (2) crediting labor put into Open Scholarship &amp;ndash; including &lt;a href=&#34;https://sparcopen.org/why-open-matters/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Access, Open Education, and Open Data&lt;/a&gt; (according to SPARC) &amp;ndash; in tenure or performance review committees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More broadly, we need &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irrodl.org/index.php/irrodl/article/view/2523/3877&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;changes with institutional culture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;re-imagined writing and publishing practices&lt;/strong&gt; (like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pubpub.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PubPub&lt;/a&gt;), and &lt;strong&gt;better Open Scholarship infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt; (like &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the Open Science Framework&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icpsr.umich.edu/icpsrweb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ICPSR&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-07-public-scholarly-annotation&#34;&gt;Open Web Annotation&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder how things may look like in 2028!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Magnets</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/project/idea-magnets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 15:42:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/project/idea-magnets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orchestration Graphs for Collaboration</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/project/frog-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 15:42:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/project/frog-online/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated STEM learning in an idea-centered knowledge-building environment</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/hong2018-ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/hong2018-ch/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ongoing Experiment: Public Scholarly Annotation</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-07-public-scholarly-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-07-public-scholarly-annotation/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-stories&#34;&gt;Background stories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I value &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Open Scholarship&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and have been practicing it for years &amp;ndash; both in terms of &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt; it and &lt;em&gt;learning to do&lt;/em&gt; it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/houshuang&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stian Haklev&lt;/a&gt;, an OER and Open Access champion, introduced me to this idea. He built a wiki-based workflow system, named &lt;em&gt;researchr&lt;/em&gt;, and convinced a few OISE friends, including &lt;a href=&#34;http://cresenciafong.com/blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cresencia Fong&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://alisaacosta.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Alisa Acosta&lt;/a&gt;, to share our annotations publicly, in a well-organized manner. For us, the benefits of using researchr are obvious: the system scaffolds the scholarly process of reading and annotating articles, as well as summarizing and organizing our notes. Its openness adds another important piece that&amp;rsquo;s a bit murkier. &lt;strong&gt;What does it mean to share out annotations publicly &amp;ndash; to academics who annotate, to authors of an annotated article, and to academia?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pratim&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pratim Sengupta&lt;/a&gt;, whose work was &lt;a href=&#34;http://bodong.ch/notes/2015-12-17-sengupta2015/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;annotated by myself&lt;/a&gt; when running a journal club with a dozen grad students, just gave me a chance to really ponder on these questions. He and his team&amp;rsquo;s work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/computing-in-public-computing-for-public-b722f60c9f98&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;public computing&lt;/a&gt; inspires my evolving thinking on the value of openness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thinking is also contextualized in my recent attendance to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://iannotate.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I Annotate&lt;/a&gt; conference and the idea of creating &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.hypothes.is/blog/a-coalition-of-scholarly-annotators/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;A Coalition for Scholarly Annotation&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; shared by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/judell&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jon Udell&lt;/a&gt;. My key takeaway from the conference was that the web annotation community has been thinking deeply about web information, knowledge and workflows. Their work has generated nascent web standards, tools and practices that are making an impact on publishing, information &amp;lsquo;consumption&amp;rsquo;, and human collaboration on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;now-enters-this-blog-post&#34;&gt;Now enters this blog post&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will be an evolving document reflecting my ongoing thinking on &lt;em&gt;open scholarly annotation&lt;/em&gt;. Writing this blog post is a new experiment. I admit my bias upfront. That is, &lt;strong&gt;I strongly believe scholarly annotations generated at various stages of the scholarly process are of great value&lt;/strong&gt;. However, these annotations have become part of the &amp;lsquo;dark data&amp;rsquo; generated by scholars and are rarely talked about. While &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/news/1-500-scientists-lift-the-lid-on-reproducibility-1.19970&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;research reproducibility&lt;/a&gt; has been embraced by many disciplines and scholarly communities, how we actually &amp;lsquo;annotate&amp;rsquo; each other&amp;rsquo;s ideas into new ones remains opaque. Remaining in the dark is not doing justice to hidden value we produce as scholars and is not helping with the training of emerging scholars. Further enriching openness in scholarly practices &amp;ndash; even beyond open data and analysis reproducibility &amp;ndash; would be a meaningful next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;phase-1-of-writing-this-post&#34;&gt;Phase 1 of writing this post&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Phase 1, I will publicly annotate web documents about &lt;em&gt;open scholarly annotation&lt;/em&gt;, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypothes.is/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hypothes.is&lt;/a&gt; and a tag &lt;code&gt;ValueAnnotation&lt;/code&gt;. Below is an evolving collection of my annotations, and I invite you to annotate with me using the same tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/images/article_images/hypothesis.html&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; src=&#34;https://hypothes.is/search?q=tag:%22ValueAnnotation%22&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a Hypothesis annotation I created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/images/article_images/h-annotation.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;phase-2&#34;&gt;Phase 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an emerging process. The next step, as I see now, is to make sense of generated annotations and update this post with summaries and new ideas that &amp;lsquo;rise above&amp;rsquo; existing ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; (2018-7-20): In preparation for an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aera.net/Events-Meetings/Annual-Meeting/2019-Annual-Meeting-Theme&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AERA 2019&lt;/a&gt; submission, I wrote a research summary describing what I hope to do next. The summary &amp;ndash; embedded below &amp;ndash; is informed by Hypothesis annotations above. However, I found it difficult to demonstrate the &amp;lsquo;moves&amp;rsquo; from annotations to writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/e/2PACX-1vR2KgWL47pKHyfDr_YRnIbJEutWQynICTNxusVrsVXHFjyiTODXxU06mihU6kaHrqUJR8haky2kL3q-/pub&#34; frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Textbooks and Open Educational Practices</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-04-24-open-textbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-04-24-open-textbooks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I was included in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mndaily.com/article/2018/04/n-university-of-minnesota-professors-use-their-free-time-to-write-free-textbooks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an &lt;em&gt;MN Daily&lt;/em&gt; story about open textbooks&lt;/a&gt; last week. It was actually a bit embarrassing as I thought a few other colleagues would ‘co-star’ with me in this story because there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://research.cehd.umn.edu/otn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;exciting work on open textbooks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.umn.edu/elearning/partnership/showcase&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;affordable content&lt;/a&gt; going on at UMN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;University of Minnesota professors use their free time to write free textbooks: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/iCgMCxC3qf&#34;&gt;https://t.co/iCgMCxC3qf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mndailynews?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@mndailynews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bod0ng?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@bod0ng&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dernst?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@dernst&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UMNews?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@UMNews&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/UMNproud?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#UMNproud&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CEHD?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#CEHD&lt;/a&gt; Learn more: &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/eydHtKE8Em&#34;&gt;https://t.co/eydHtKE8Em&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/open_textbooks?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@open_textbooks&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/oer?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#oer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LTMediaLab?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@LTMediaLab&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UMN_CI?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@UMN_CI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/zweg5n1FB5&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/zweg5n1FB5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; U of Minnesota CEHD (@UMN_CEHD) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UMN_CEHD/status/986960692468178944?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I’d like to share some personal thoughts that were not included in the news story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-textbooks-personal-reasons-of-using-them&#34;&gt;Open textbooks: Personal reasons of using them&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price of textbooks in the US (and Canada) is ridiculous. I am not knowledgeable enough to explain why. But I had lived experiences with buying bulky textbooks for $200 and using them as laptop stands after a single use. They are from respected textbook publishers (like SAGE) and are indeed well-written. But &amp;hellip; there could be 100 reasons why a textbook should not cost that much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, the notion of ‘a textbook’ has evolved, at least for some disciplines. In many fields that are fast-evolving, textbooks written today will become dated in two years. Also, one textbook can rarely fulfill needs of a course, making it necessary to introduce fresh texts and multimedia content from the ‘open world’. Digital tools, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://h5p.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;H5P&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.google.com/colaboratory/faq.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Colaboratory&lt;/a&gt;, offer richer modalities, interoperability, and interactivity for learning in comparison with traditional paper books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More profoundly, &lt;strong&gt;the conceptualization of a textbook as a container of knowledge to be acquired by students is challenged by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newcultureoflearning.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;‘new cultures of learning’&lt;/a&gt; that de-emphasize ‘knowledge as stocks’ and value learning as &amp;lsquo;participating in a flow of knowledge production&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/strong&gt; Instructors can surely do inspiring things with a traditional textbook, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencontent.org/blog/archives/3221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;grounding principles of Open Educational Resources (OER)&lt;/a&gt; almost automatically make a philosophical statement that draws one’s teaching closer to new cultures of learning. It’s the (promised) paradigm shift behind OER (and open textbooks) that attracts me, besides cost concerns mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, by the way, these changes are not limited to textbooks, but also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2018/04/the-scientific-paper-is-obsolete/556676/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;scholarly knowledge production in general&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-educational-practices&#34;&gt;Open educational practices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my thinking on OER are tilted towards &lt;a href=&#34;http://catherinecronin.net/research/openness-and-praxis/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;‘open educational practices’&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to making my course content open (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/meefen/la-spring16&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on Github for example&lt;/a&gt;), I am also interested in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open participation&lt;/strong&gt; — that does not limit participation within a socially, spatiotemporally, and technologically bounded environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Student agency and voice&lt;/strong&gt; — that give students a say about what to learn and how to learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connected learning&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.veletsianos.com/digital-scholarship-social-media-use-and-networked-participatory-scholarship/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;networked scholarship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; opportunities — that present a fuller picture of learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/324611447_Designing_for_Networked_Collaborative_Discourse_An_UnLMS_Approach?_sg=PGJY4wgTJg5Cww01tBKT9c1Oo_ePJeI3nSHLFeyQAsJYUyWE6Dv8Ht-S2ofF60vy_b67vRe8oXJxu6xQB2SNhAYX7z7suxd3eW7PBIWm.En9a-PTggG7Kycn1iq4BewoyxPdNV69K57JZI_E-88MS-xc7YknPZ-7TE0_MzyhxrXSwZsC0Z8nUguDTKMBjTQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a design case I recently published in &lt;em&gt;TechTrends&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, an EdTech journal, I introduce in great details about a course I designed with these ideas in mind. I wrote a course handbook, which is essentially a compilation of OER, and incorporated tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypothes.is/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hypothes.is&lt;/a&gt; and Slack to facilitate collaborative discourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be fun to integrate more ‘open pedagogy’ ideas in the next iteration of this course. Maybe asking students to rewrite the handbook. Maybe setting up open Jupyter Notebooks for students to fork, remix, and redistribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-this-mean-for-faculty-members&#34;&gt;What does this mean for faculty members?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;use their free time&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;on top of their day-to-day work, often only receiving relatively small grants as compensation&amp;quot; 🤔 Bit problematic framing of OER production, as if it&amp;#39;s done by amateurs, out of love.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ewout ter Haar (@ewout) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ewout/status/987005352402137088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a good critique. Free-time is an unfamiliar word for many academics. The idea of &lt;a href=&#34;https://er.educause.edu/articles/2014/2/conjecture-tension-and-online-learning&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;teaching online is already facing push-backs&lt;/a&gt; over the years. Structural supports for faculty members are needed to make OER production sustainable. Supporting broader acceptance of OER and open educational practices also requires cultural shifts within an institution, which is often hard to bring about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episodes from my trip in China</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-04-05-china-episodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2018-04-05-china-episodes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am not an ethnographer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there were a few episodes from my trip to/in China last month that caught my attention, or &amp;lsquo;gaze&amp;rsquo;. To put these episodes into perspective, my most recent trip to China took place &lt;a href=&#34;http://bodong.ch/blog/2016-11-03-trip-to-asia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in October 2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-the-escalator&#34;&gt;On the Escalator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As more subways are built underground, I encountered more of those super long escalators in mega cities. On one escalator in Shanghai, I heard its accompanying &amp;lsquo;voice reminder system&amp;rsquo; saying:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please hold the handrail firmly and attend to your steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not lean on the handrail. &lt;strong&gt;Do not look at your phone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last sentence of the voice system was new. The intimate connection between us with screens has been built into another piece of technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://sns-img.b0.upaiyun.com/dunzd/1710/2621/53/151240667855781509026035.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cdsb.com/Public/cdsb_offical/2017-10-26/148418749157279040888484000860608264626.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Image Source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;say-something-in-english&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Say Something in English&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a workday, my pre-schooler son and I were playing in a playground in Shanghai. There were a bunch of other kids &amp;ndash; mostly younger &amp;ndash; also playing there. My son always prefers talking with me in Mandarin but may entertain with a few English words from time to time. Then there was a dad with his young daughter (approximately 2 years old). It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long for him to make a request to his daughter: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Baby, can you say something in English?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;  The same thing happened again the next day in a park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days later when I was in my hometown, a small town in Western China, I visited a newly built factory where an uncle works. This factory manufactures food supplements with nutritions extracted from traditional Chinese herbs. I somehow ended up meeting with their young sales team, which was made of four fresh college graduates. They were in their early 20s, and two of them graduated from the same high school I attended. Then I began to learn about their goals of taking over their international sales from intermediaries located in costal areas. They were not confident in their English capabilities though and showed tremendous interests in Western culture(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest dream while growing up in my hometown was to go to college in Shanghai or Beijing. Now it seems people living in my hometown are aspiring to ride the tide of globalization. It may be still difficult to attract or retain necessary talents. But they have lofty goals. The new factory aims to become a listed company in 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://meefen.github.io/images/article_images/shanghai_yuechi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-accept-both-wechat-and-zhifubao&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;I accept both WeChat and Zhifubao&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Riding on a taxi from Shanghai Pudong Airport to a hotel, I noticed two QR codes attached to the dashboard of the taxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I accept both WeChat and Zhifubao,&amp;rdquo; said the driver when we arrived. And he taught me how to use them on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time around, I could basically &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/2110118/going-cash-free-why-china-light-years-ahead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;go cash-free everywhere in China&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn2.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/images/methode/2017/09/11/1b7d1df6-8ef9-11e7-9f40-4d9615941c08_1320x770_114008.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-still-don-t-see-the-point&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;I still don&amp;rsquo;t see the point.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my stay at Beijing Normal, I taught a few classes on topics such as MOOCs and learning analytics. In a graduate-level class, a professor introduced to us a project aiming to build a recommender engine to help highschool students choose subjects in &lt;a href=&#34;http://gaokao.eol.cn/news/201710/t20171027_1562295.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the newly reformed college entrance exam&lt;/a&gt;. The recommender engine will be based on a wide range of factors, including previous performance, personality traits, competitiveness of the student&amp;rsquo;s aspired college, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One student said, &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I still don&amp;rsquo;t see the point.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; Her argument was this choice is too high-stake and too personal. She would like to make the choice on her own even if the recommendation is meant to be informational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She had a point. A very good one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fostering student engagement in online discussion through social learning analytics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-mc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-mc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing for Networked Collaborative Discourse: An UnLMSApproach</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-tw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-tw/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using differentiated feedback to improve performance in introductory statistics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/cai2018-za/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/cai2018-za/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Annotation of Research Articles in Learning Sciences</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-12-08-jls-web-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2017-12-08-jls-web-annotation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- comments: true
image: https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2453/3973300988_824ec066a9_b.jpg --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a member of the Outreach Advisory Board of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tandfonline.com/loi/hlns20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Journal of the Learning Sciences (JLS)&lt;/a&gt;, I was really glad to see the journal putting together a web annotation event during December 11-22, 2017. This activity is yet another move made by the editorial team to engage its readership on various social media venues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Coming Soon: Web annotation of JLS articles in Hypothes.is.&lt;br&gt;The first article is a study by Akkerman and Bruining published in 2016 in Volume 25 (2).Read the full article at &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/tGoOiQKLUR&#34;&gt;https://t.co/tGoOiQKLUR&lt;/a&gt;  and visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/2dYOBe15L8&#34;&gt;https://t.co/2dYOBe15L8&lt;/a&gt;  for instructions for using &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hypothes_is?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@hypothes_is&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/z5oSHleIKB&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/z5oSHleIKB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; JrnlLearningSciences (@JLearnSciences) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JLearnSciences/status/937719563390672896?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 4, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this web annotation event, participants are invited to annotate a recently published open-access article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10508406.2016.1147448&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multilevel Boundary Crossing in a Professional Development School Partnership&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, using an open web annotation tool named &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypothes.is/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hypothes.is&lt;/a&gt;. Hats off to the authors for their support of this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The editorial team has put together &lt;strong&gt;detailed instructions&lt;/strong&gt; in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1Cmoz22xEY8QjHBiYC-H2oU0YHJSTLCBhWelbusSXbKM/edit#slide=id.g2b48df0836_0_10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During and after the event, in addition to the Hypothes.is sidebar, a participant can either use &lt;a href=&#34;https://hypothes.is/search?q=url%3Ahttp%3A%2F%2Fwww.tandfonline.com%2Fdoi%2Ffull%2F10.1080%2F10508406.2016.1147448&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hypothes.is&amp;rsquo; advanced search functionality&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://jonudell.net/h/facet.html?facet=uri&amp;amp;mode=documents&amp;amp;search=http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10508406.2016.1147448&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an aggregation tool&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;review existing annotations&lt;/strong&gt; made on this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am excited for this move JLS is making, not only because &lt;strong&gt;scholarship could be more networked and discursive&lt;/strong&gt;, but also because I see great opportunities of using web annotation to bridge learning spaces in classrooms. To me, making an annotation is forming a relationship with an idea. As educators, &lt;strong&gt;we ought to think deeply and design smartly to value such relationships as students are traversing various treks of life&lt;/strong&gt;. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://cligr.github.io/projects/discow.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;our ongoing NSF project&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
