<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Text mining on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/text-mining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Text mining on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/text-mining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Carley. (2012). Data-to-model: a mixed initiative approach for rapid ethnographic assessment</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-30-carley2012-xn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-30-carley2012-xn/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Carley2012-xn
Carley, K. M., Bigrigg, M. W., &amp;amp; Diallo, B. (2012). Data-to-model: a mixed initiative approach for rapid ethnographic assessment. Computational &amp;amp; Mathematical Organization Theory, 18(3), 300–327. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10588-012-9125-y
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Rapid ethnographic assessment is used when there is a need to quickly create a socio-cultural profile of a group or region. While there are many forms such an assessment can take, we view it as providing insight into who are the key actors, what are the key issues, sentiments, resources, activities and locations, how have these changed in recent times, and what roles do the various actors play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyze Text Similarity with R: Latent Semantic Analysis and Multidimentional Scaling</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-03-11-analyze-text-similarity-in-r-latent-semantic-analysis-and-multidimentional-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-03-11-analyze-text-similarity-in-r-latent-semantic-analysis-and-multidimentional-scaling/</guid>
      <description>Background One of the most pressing questions I have been pondering upon when redesigning Knowledge Forum is how to represent the knowledge space of a community to better support idea improvement. Many people think Knowledge Forum as another discussion forum (or learning management system) with a 2-D interface (see below). This notion lead people to treat a Knowledge Forum view merely as a container of notes. The reason why this happens is because users usually fail to recognize one important principle behind the design of Knowledge Forum view: to support multiple perspectives of community knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo of Using twitter-hashtag-analytics to Analyze Tweets from #LAK13</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-02-26-demo-of-using-twitter-hashtag-analytics-package-to-analyze-tweets-from-lak13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-02-26-demo-of-using-twitter-hashtag-analytics-package-to-analyze-tweets-from-lak13/</guid>
      <description>Building on Ben Marwick, Martin Hawksey and Tony Hirst&amp;rsquo;s work on analyzing tweets with R, I started an R project for tweet analysis, namely twitter-hashtag-analytics. This project is hosted on Github and welcomes anyone who&amp;rsquo;s interested to contribute. It is my very first attempt to write a package in R, so I admit the capabilities of it is still limited and its structure may be not properly planned. Any advice will be highly appreciated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>