<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Methodology on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/methodology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Methodology on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/methodology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Berliner2002-jo- Comment: Educational research: The hardest science of all</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-07-berliner2002-jo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-07-berliner2002-jo/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Berliner2002-jo
Berliner, D. C. (2002). Comment: Educational research: The hardest science of all. Educational Researcher, 31(8), 18–20. https://doi.org/10.3102/0013189X031008018
Notes Summarize: An argument against the sole promotion / endorsement of randomized control trials / experiments in the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001. Nicely argued.
Highlights The “evidence-based practices” and “scientific research” men- tioned over 100 times in the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001 are code words for randomized experiments, a method of re- search with which I too am much enamored (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Clark - 2014 - Quantitative research designs: recognizing the overall plan for a study</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-28-clark2014-nn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-28-clark2014-nn/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Clark2014-nn
Clark, V. L. P., &amp;amp; Creswell, J. W. (2014). Understanding research: A consumer’s guide. Pearson Higher Ed. (Chapter 6)
Notes Highlights This chapter first introduces you to two major types of quantitative research. It then focuses on the characteristics of five quantitative research designs that you will likely encounter as you read research. Knowing about different quantitative research designs will help you read the Method sections of quantitative reports and understand and evaluate the research designs used in quantitative studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Design Research for Sustained Innovation</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-03-31-bereiter2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-03-31-bereiter2002/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @bereiter2002
Bereiter, C. (2002). Design Research for Sustained Innovation. Cognitive Studies, 9(3), 321&amp;ndash;327.
Clippings Although there is innovation in education it tends to be sporadic and discontinuous, with the result that innovative practices seldom win out against those with a long evolutionary history. (p. 1)
add a note here (p. 2)
The automobile engine is especially interesting, because the inherent drawbacks of the reciprocating piston engine were recognized early and there were periodic attempts at radical innovation, none of which has yet succeeded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Edelson. (2002). Design research</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-07-edelson2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-07-edelson2002/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Edelson2002
Edelson, D. C. (2002). Design research: What we learn when we engage in design. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 11(1), 105–121. doi:10.1207/S15327809JLS1101_4
Notes An important piece on design research articulating different types of theories in DR, as well as &amp;lsquo;twin intentions/goals&amp;rsquo; of advancing both design theories and domain theories in DR.
Highlights The emerging design research paradigm treats design as a strategy for developing and refining theories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Flyvbjerg, B. (2006). Five Misunderstandings About Case-Study Research</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-18-flyvbjerg2006-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-18-flyvbjerg2006-eu/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Flyvbjerg2006-eu
Flyvbjerg, B. (2006). Five Misunderstandings About Case-Study Research. Qualitative Inquiry: QI, 12(2), 219–245. https://doi.org/10.1177/1077800405284363
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights This article examines five common misunderstandings about case-study research: (a) theoretical knowledge is more valuable than practical knowledge; (b) one cannot generalize from a single case, therefore, the single-case study cannot contribute to scientific development; &amp;copy; the case study is most useful for generating hypotheses, whereas other methods are more suitable for hypotheses testing and theory building; (d) the case study contains a bias toward verification; and (e) it is often difficult to summarize specific case stud- ies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Kuhn2012-qo The structure of scientific revolutions</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-13-kuhn2012-qo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-13-kuhn2012-qo/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Kuhn2012-qo
Kuhn, T. S. (2012). The structure of scientific revolutions (4th ed.). Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press. Retrieved from https://books.google.com/books?id=3eP5Y_OOuzwC
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights A footnote encountered by chance led me to the experiments by which Jean Piaget has illuminated both the various worlds of the 2growing child and the process of transition from one to the next.2 One of my colleagues set me to reading pape rs in the psychology of perception, my colleagues set me to reading pape rs in the psychology of perception, particularly the Gestalt psychologists ; another introduced me to B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Yazan, (2015). Three Approaches to Case Study Methods in Education</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-18-yazan2015-wn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-18-yazan2015-wn/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Yazan2015-wn
Yazan, B. (2015). Three Approaches to Case Study Methods in Education: Yin, Merriam, and Stake. The Qualitative Report, 20(2), 134–152. Retrieved from http://nsuworks.nova.edu/tqr/vol20/iss2/12/?utm_source=nsuworks.nova.edu%2Ftqr%2Fvol20%2Fiss2%2F12&amp;amp;utm_medium=PDF&amp;amp;utm_campaign=PDFCoverPages
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Focusing on the landmark works of three prominent methodologists, namely Robert Yin, Sharan Merriam, Robert Stake, I attempt to scrutinize the areas where their perspectives diverge, converge and complement one another in varying dimensions of case study research. (p.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>