<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Motivation on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Motivation on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Psychometric Properties of the Alternative Form of the Education Participation Scale</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-18-boshier91psychometric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-18-boshier91psychometric/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @boshier91psychometric
Boshier R (1991). “Psychometric Properties of the Alternative Form of the Education Participation Scale.” Adult Education Quarterly, 41(3), pp. 150-167. , http://aeq.sagepub.com/content/41/3/150.full.pdf+html, .
Notes This article reports a reconstruction of the widely used Education Participation Scale (EPS) created by Boshier in 1970s. The &amp;lsquo;newly&amp;rsquo; created EPS, i.e., EPS (A form) in contrast with EPS (F form), is composed of a total of 42 items in 7 dimensions below (with each dimension having 6 items):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Reasons nurses participate in continuing education</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-18-oconnor1979reasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-18-oconnor1979reasons/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @oconnor1979reasons
O&amp;rsquo;Connor AB (1979). “Reasons nurses participate in continuing education.” Nursing Research, 28(6), pp. 354-359.
And this piece as well:
O’Connor, A. B. (1982). Reasons nurses participate in self-study continuing education programs. Nursing research, 31(6):371–374.
Notes Basically, these two studies used a revised version of the EPS (Education Participation Scale) to measure motivation of continuing education among nurses. Two studies were different in terms of sample size &amp;ndash; the 1982 study surveyed around 1800 nurses (twice as big as in the 1979 study).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: The Education Participation Scale--Modified: Evaluating a Measure of Continuing Education</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-18-dia05education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-18-dia05education/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @dia05education
Dia D, Smith CA, Cohen-Callow A and Bliss DL (2005). “The Education Participation Scale-Modified: Evaluating a Measure of Continuing Education.” Research on Social Work Practice, 15(3), pp. 213-222. , http://rsw.sagepub.com/content/15/3/213.full.pdf+html, .
Notes This article evaluates the Educational Participation Scale–Modified (EPS-M) developed by O’Connor (1979, 1982) in the context of social work.
It has a nice literature review of subversions of EPS.
Highlights Abstract
The purpose of this study was to evaluate the measurement model and theory underlying the Educational Participation Scale–Modified (EPS-M) using confirmatory factor analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>