<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multimodal on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/multimodal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Multimodal on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/multimodal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Blikstein - 2013 - Multimodal learning analytics</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-13-blikstein2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-13-blikstein2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Blikstein2013
Blikstein, P. (2013). Multimodal learning analytics. In Proceedings of the Third International Conference on Learning Analytics and Knowledge - LAK ’13 (p. 102). New York, New York, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;2460296.2460316
Notes Paulo Blikstein&amp;rsquo;s intro to a series of his preliminary work on multimodal learning analytics. I think he is credited as the creator of this line of work.
 I presented a series of proof-of-concept studies for what I termed “multimodal learning analytics:” a set of techniques that can be used to collect multiple sources of data in highfrequency (video, logs, audio, gestures, biosensors), synchronize and code the data, and examine learning in realistic, ecologically valid, social, mixed-media learning environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Choudhury - 2008 - The Mobile Sensing Platform: An Embedded Activity Recognition System</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-29-choudhury2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-29-choudhury2008/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Choudhury2008
Choudhury, T., Borriello, G., Consolvo, S., Haehnel, D., Harrison, B., Hemingway, B., … Wyatt, D. (2008). The Mobile Sensing Platform: An Embedded Activity Recognition System. IEEE Pervasive Computing, 7(2), 32–41. doi:10.1109/MPRV.2008.39
Notes A seemingly early work of mobile sensing leading to fitness products like Fitbit. The article introduces an iterative process of designing and testing generations of mobile sensing devices. It highlights the importance synergy between hardware and software (machine learning algorithms) in order to accurately detect and classify physical activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Worsley - 2012 - Multimodal learning analytics</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-13-worsley2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-13-worsley2012/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Worsley2012
Worsley, M. (2012). Multimodal learning analytics. In Proceedings of the 14th ACM international conference on Multimodal interaction - ICMI ’12 (p. 353). New York, New York, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;2388676.2388755
Notes Worsley&amp;rsquo;s brief description of his plan of dissertation work.
Highlights In order to develop a more appropriate measure and means for assessing SPBL I want to construct a complete picture of how learning takes place in SPBL environments through the use of multimodal learning interfaces and techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>