<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epistemic beliefs on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/epistemic-beliefs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Epistemic beliefs on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/epistemic-beliefs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Fostering epistemological beliefs and conceptual change in chemistry using knowledge building</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-10-04-lam2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-10-04-lam2008/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @lam2008
Lam, I., &amp;amp; Chan, C. K. K. (2008). Fostering epistemological beliefs and conceptual change in chemistry using knowledge building. In Proceedings of the 8th international conference on International conference for the learning sciences Volume 1 (Vol. 1, pp. 461–468). Utrecht, The Netherlands: International Society of the Learning Sciences. Retrieved from http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1599812.1599868
Clippings Abstract:
Various measures were collected at pre and posttests including epistemological beliefs, conceptual-change questions and online discourse and reflection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding students practical epistemologies and their influence on learning through inquiry</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-06-07-sandoval2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-06-07-sandoval2005/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @sandoval2005
Sandoval, W. A. (2005). Understanding students’ practical epistemologies and their influence on learning through inquiry. Science Education, 89(4), 634–656. doi:10.1002/sce.20065
Raw notes Page: 9 Page: 9 What the above studies and others show is that students at all age levels commonly have inarticulate ideas about the nature and role of scientiﬁc experimentation, and the relation between method and theory.
Page: 9 Methods of Science.
Page: 9 Although Deanna Kuhn has argued that most children, and even lay adults, fail to distinguish between theories and evidence (Kuhn, 1993; Kuhn et al.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>