<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Activity theory on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/activity-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Activity theory on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/activity-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Cowan, P., &amp; Butler, R. (2013). Using Activity Theory to Problematize the Role of the Teacher During Mobile Learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-10-cowan2013-ke/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-10-cowan2013-ke/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Cowan2013-ke
Cowan, P., &amp;amp; Butler, R. (2013). Using Activity Theory to Problematize the Role of the Teacher During Mobile Learning. SAGE Open, 3(4), 2158244013516155. https://doi.org/10.1177/2158244013516155
Notes Summarize: Interesting use of activity theory. There is an attempt to advance AT in this piece as well. The focus on &amp;lsquo;4 faces&amp;rsquo; of activity systems is interesting and may be combined with automated, network measures.
Highlights m-learning is a new peda- gogical option for teachers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sannino et al. (2016). Formative Interventions for Expansive Learning and Transformative Agency</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-10-sannino2016-lr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-10-sannino2016-lr/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sannino2016-lr
Sannino, A., Engeström, Y., &amp;amp; Lemos, M. (2016). Formative Interventions for Expansive Learning and Transformative Agency. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 25(4), 599–633. https://doi.org/10.1080/10508406.2016.1204547
Notes Summarize: A very nicely (and also densely written) paper presenting three cases of expansive learning. It highlights six theoretical lens to be used in analysis of expansive learning. The cases are from two schools and a university library. Formative interventions are also compared with design-based research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Yamagata-Lynch, L. C. (2010). Understanding Cultural Historical Activity Theory</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-10-yamagata-lynch2010-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-10-yamagata-lynch2010-eu/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Yamagata-Lynch2010-eu
Yamagata-Lynch, L. C. (2010). Understanding Cultural Historical Activity Theory. In Activity Systems Analysis Methods (pp. 13–26). Springer, Boston, MA. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4419-6321-5_2
Notes Summarize: This book chapter is a good &amp;lsquo;primer&amp;rsquo; for understanding activity systems analysis (as a methodology). It goes through the historical context of CHAT and AT back to Vygotsky, and provides useful guidance for researchers who wish to adopt activity systems analysis.
Highlights Reading and Understanding CHAT (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Engeström, Y., &amp; Sannino, A. (2011). Discursive manifestations of contradictions in organizational change efforts</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-04-engestrom2011-yr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-04-engestrom2011-yr/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Engestrom2011-yr
Engeström, Y., &amp;amp; Sannino, A. (2011). Discursive manifestations of contradictions in organizational change efforts: A methodological framework. Journal of Organizational Change Management, 24(3), 368–387. https://doi.org/10.1108/09534811111132758
Notes Summarize: This paper clarifies the concept of contradiction in activity theory and introduces a methodology for identifying contradictions reflected in discourse of an organization. &amp;ldquo;Four types of discursive manifestations, namely dilemmas, conflicts, critical conflicts, and double binds, could be effectively identified in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sannino et al. (2009). Activity theory between historical engagement and future-making practice</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-04-sannino2009-cg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-04-sannino2009-cg/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sannino2009-cg
Sannino, A., Daniels, H., &amp;amp; Gutiérrez, K. D. (2009). Activity theory between historical engagement and future-making practice. In A. Sannino, H. Daniels, &amp;amp; K. D. Gutiérrez (Eds.), Learning and expanding with activity theory (pp. 1–15). Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. Retrieved from https://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;id=pyY5EusnjBcC&amp;amp;oi=fnd&amp;amp;pg=PA1&amp;amp;dq=Activity+theory+between+historical+engagement+and+future-making+practice.+&amp;amp;ots=KRX_JACIwx&amp;amp;sig=Evh74CCwE-Yq92ecqQU_3XMgFJg
Notes Summarize: This chapter provides an interesting and thorough overview of the historical context of activity theory. Understanding the historical circumstance of this theory is important for any use of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Engestrom. (2009). The future of activity theory</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-04-04-engestrom2009-fq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-04-04-engestrom2009-fq/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Engestrom2009-fq
Engeström, Y. (2009). The future of activity theory: A rough draft. Learning and Expanding with Activity Theory, 303–328. Retrieved from https://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;id=pyY5EusnjBcC&amp;amp;oi=fnd&amp;amp;pg=PA303&amp;amp;dq=the+future+of+activity+theory&amp;amp;ots=KRW_JyuHpy&amp;amp;sig=mvpfOxH73y4RFSPYguo4CrM0LDY
Notes Summarize: A thoughtful piece that explains AT deeply and also explores its neighboring concepts.
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Recently Aaro Toomela has published two papers in which he critically assesses the contents and potential of activity theory. The first one is titled ’Activity theory is a dead end for cultural-historical psychology’ (Toomela, 2000), the second one ’Activity theory is a dead end for methodological thinking in cultural psychology too’ (Toomela, 2008).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Cole &amp; Engeström - 1993 - A cultural-historical approach to distributed cognition</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-03-24-cole1993-zt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-03-24-cole1993-zt/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Cole1993-zt
Cole, M., &amp;amp; Engeström, Y. (1993). A cultural-historical approach to distributed cognition. In G. Salomon (Ed.), Distributed cognitions: Psychological and educational considerations (pp. 1–46). New York: Cambridge University Press.
Notes Summarize: This is a seminal piece about the activity (system) theory as a cultural-historical view of learning. It touches on several important connections between AT and expansive learning, distributed cognition, etc.
Assess: I especially like the second example presented in this paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Engeström. (2000). Activity theory as a framework for analyzing and redesigning work</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-03-24-engestrom2000-yq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-03-24-engestrom2000-yq/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Engestrom2000-yq
Engeström, Y. (2000). Activity theory as a framework for analyzing and redesigning work. Ergonomics, 43(7), 960–974. https://doi.org/10.1080/001401300409143
Notes Summarize: Engeström expands on the notion of knotworking in this article, in comparison with the 1993 article. This is especially relevant to critical moments of knowledge creation. A bit surprising there has been not much uptake of this concept in KB research.
The notion of constant co-configuration is also interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Jonassen-1999-Activity theory as a framework for designing constructivist learning environments</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-03-10-jonassen1999-dz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-03-10-jonassen1999-dz/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Jonassen1999-dz
Jonassen, D. H., &amp;amp; Rohrer-Murphy, L. (1999). Activity theory as a framework for designing constructivist learning environments. Educational Technology Research and Development, 47(1), 61–79. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF02299477
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Activ- ity theory is a socio-cultural, socio-historical lens through which designers can analyze human activity systems. It focuses on the inter- action of human activity and consciousness within its relevant environmental context. (p. 1)
Activity the- ory posits that conscious learning emerges from activity (performance), not as a precursor to it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>