<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning sciences on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/learning-sciences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning sciences on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/learning-sciences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Beyond the Individual-Social Antinomy in Discussions of Piaget and Vygotsky</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-06-cole1996/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-06-cole1996/</guid>
      <description>References Cole, M., &amp;amp; Wertsch, J. V. (1996). Beyond the Individual-Social Antinomy in Discussions of Piaget and Vygotsky. Human Development, 39(5), 250–256. doi:10.1159&amp;frasl;000278475
Citekey: @Cole1996
Notes  This article affords a &amp;lsquo;fresh&amp;rsquo; look at the contrast between Piaget and Vygotsky&amp;rsquo;s constructivist theories. The authors highlight that Piaget has not denied the role of social interactions in knowledge construction, so hasn&amp;rsquo;t Vygotsgy excluded the role of individual thinking. While conventional contrast focuses on the individual vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Designing for Productive Failure</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-03-26-kapur2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-03-26-kapur2012/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @kapur2012
Kapur, M., &amp;amp; Bielaczyc, K. (2012). Designing for Productive Failure. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 21(1), 45&amp;ndash;83. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;10508406.2011.591717
Clippings the design principles undergirding productive failure (PF; M. Kapur, 2008). (p. 3)
(a) PF, in which students collaboratively solved complex problems on average speed without any instructional support or scaffolds up until a teacher-led consolidation; or (b) direct instruction (DI), in which the teacher provided strong instructional support, scaffolding, and feedback (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Why the Learning Sciences and Instructional Systems Need Each Other</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-01-hoadley2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-01-hoadley2004/</guid>
      <description>References Hoadley, C. M. (2004). Learning and Design: Why the Learning Sciences and Instructional Systems Need Each Other. Educational Technology, 3, 6–12.
Citekey: @Hoadley2004
Notes Highlights &amp;ldquo;While both analyses varied in their coverage and techniques, they came to similar conclusions, that the literatures identified with these two communities had surprisingly little overlap, and that a small number of individuals represented a large portion of what overlap did exist.&amp;rdquo; (p. 3)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>