<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Expansive learning on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/expansive-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Expansive learning on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/expansive-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sannino et al. (2016). Formative Interventions for Expansive Learning and Transformative Agency</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-10-sannino2016-lr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-10-sannino2016-lr/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sannino2016-lr
Sannino, A., Engeström, Y., &amp;amp; Lemos, M. (2016). Formative Interventions for Expansive Learning and Transformative Agency. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 25(4), 599–633. https://doi.org/10.1080/10508406.2016.1204547
Notes Summarize: A very nicely (and also densely written) paper presenting three cases of expansive learning. It highlights six theoretical lens to be used in analysis of expansive learning. The cases are from two schools and a university library. Formative interventions are also compared with design-based research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Engestrom. (2009). The future of activity theory</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-04-04-engestrom2009-fq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-04-04-engestrom2009-fq/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Engestrom2009-fq
Engeström, Y. (2009). The future of activity theory: A rough draft. Learning and Expanding with Activity Theory, 303–328. Retrieved from https://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;id=pyY5EusnjBcC&amp;amp;oi=fnd&amp;amp;pg=PA303&amp;amp;dq=the+future+of+activity+theory&amp;amp;ots=KRW_JyuHpy&amp;amp;sig=mvpfOxH73y4RFSPYguo4CrM0LDY
Notes Summarize: A thoughtful piece that explains AT deeply and also explores its neighboring concepts.
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Recently Aaro Toomela has published two papers in which he critically assesses the contents and potential of activity theory. The first one is titled ’Activity theory is a dead end for cultural-historical psychology’ (Toomela, 2000), the second one ’Activity theory is a dead end for methodological thinking in cultural psychology too’ (Toomela, 2008).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>