<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>https://meefen.github.io/authors/bodong-chen/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Bodong Chen.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:28:39 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://meefen.github.io/authors/bodong-chen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Where is Knowledge Building Analytics Headed?</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2020-11-15-kb-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:28:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2020-11-15-kb-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Knowledge Building Summer Institute (KBSI)&lt;/strong&gt; is going to be special. First, it&amp;rsquo;s held near the end of November, for the first time in summer for folks from the Southern Hemisphere. Second, the conference is going to be virtual, following a hybrid synchronous&amp;ndash;asynchronous model. Much work will be done in Knowledge Forum asynchronously before interactive sessions in Zoom on the conference days. Last but not least, this year&amp;rsquo;s conference will feature a global KB design experiment, &lt;em&gt;Saving the Planet, Saving Lives&lt;/em&gt;, led by colleagues from Ontario and Singpapore. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://ikit.org/summerinstitute2020/index.php/program/&#34;&gt;conference program here&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, it&amp;rsquo;s especially exciting to see a broadening interest in Knowledge Building (KB) Analytics in this intimate community. I still believe KB has a special place in learning analytics because its views on learning and education (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://learning-analytics.info/index.php/JLA/article/view/4552&#34;&gt;Chen &amp;amp; Zhang, 2016&lt;/a&gt;). KB&amp;rsquo;s attempt to refashion education into an effort aligned with knowledge societies can also help learning analytics find more common grounds with CSCW, HCI, knowledge analytics, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year, there are one theme and two sessions dedicated to Knowledge Building Analytics at KBSI. Here are my quick takeaways, before the conference, from reading papers in these sessions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;graphnetwork-based-approaches&#34;&gt;Graph/network based approaches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of contributions have adopted a graph/network approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xue, Zhang, &amp;amp; Xu (Nanjing Normal Unversity)&lt;/strong&gt; propose to construct &lt;strong&gt;dynamic knowledge graphs (DKG)&lt;/strong&gt; to assess and foster conceptual change. The DKG approach integrates a wide range of techniques from natural language processing (POS tagging, topic modeling, Word2vec), association rule mining, and graph visualization. With the constructed graph, centrality indices can be used to surface key concepts, which collectively provide indicators of a community&amp;rsquo;s current conceptual understanding. The DKG approach is an important technical advancement for KB analytics. It builds on a long-term interest in using network/graph approaches (e.g., KBDeX) in the KB community. It expands our KB analytics work by combining nascent graph database technologies, data mining techniques, and front-end web interfaces to deliver a complete analytics package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grounded in the &amp;ldquo;Good moves in knowledge-creating dialogue&amp;rdquo; framework by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ckbg.org/qwerty/index.php/qwerty/article/view/242&#34;&gt;Bereiter and Scardamalia (2016)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Feng, van Aalst, &amp;amp; Chan (University of Hong Kong)&lt;/strong&gt; propose to use the &lt;strong&gt;Idea-Friend Maps&lt;/strong&gt; to help students consider new ideas, meta-dialogue, high-level ideas, etc. The Idea-Friend Maps use the word networks extracted from KBDeX and enrich them with important information such as knowledge problems. A major contribution made by the Idea-Friend Maps project is it meaningfully connects sophisticated conceptual ideas (i.e. the Good Moves framework) and analytic tools (i.e., KBDeX) to student engagement. The Maps and their accompanying questions are actionable for students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hussein &amp;amp; Chen (Univeresity of Minnesota)&lt;/strong&gt; propose to use network-based text analysis to bridge gaps in knowledge-building discourse, by using network indices and network phenomena such as structural holes. This work is situated in the goal of connecting discourse across spaces but is applicable to meta-discourse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cross-cutting theme among three contributions (Hussein &amp;amp; Chen; Feng, van Aalst, &amp;amp; Chan; Xue, Zhang, &amp;amp; Xu) is the use of network/graph approaches in KB Analytics. Feng et al. use socio-semantic networks created by KBDeX; Hussein &amp;amp; Chen use text networks that rely on network analysis techniques for topic modeling and structural analysis; Xue et al. integrate a range of data science methods in a graph analysis scheme that leads to the identification of dominant terms. We collectively have an interesting mix of ideas about how to use graphs/networks in KB analytics. Graph/network analysis is a promising direction for our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-facing-analytics&#34;&gt;Student-facing analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides Feng, van Aalst, &amp;amp; Chan&amp;rsquo;s Idea-Friend Maps described above, &lt;strong&gt;Ma, Akyea, &amp;amp; Martin (University of Toronto)&lt;/strong&gt; have done some really interesting work engaging 8- to 11-year-olds to review and critique current analytic tools in Knowledge Forum. &amp;ldquo;[Students] demonstrated sophisticated interpretations of their online activities with the Knowledge Forum analytic tools. Not only were they honest and open about receiving feedback through novel forms of data visualization, they were also aware of the potential limitations of these tools and offered thoughtful and insightful feedback for our engineers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Xue et al.&amp;lsquo;s paper, they also mention that pilot studies of the DKG with teachers and students are also underway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not necessarily need more advanced analytical techniques. Work that scaffolds student sense-making and use of analytic information is equally (or even more) important. Trying to put more analytic tools &amp;ndash; good ones &amp;ndash; in the hands of students is a promising idea that&amp;rsquo;s aligned with Knowledge Building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bridge-technical-work-on-analytics-and-kb-conceptsprinciples&#34;&gt;Bridge technical work on analytics and KB concepts/principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tan &amp;amp; Teo (National Institute of Education, Singapore)&lt;/strong&gt; take a much-needed meta perspective. Based on a literature review of KB analytics, they propose two sets of guiding questions that are instrumental for future KB analytics design and development. These questions achieve two important goals: (1) to ground analytics design and use in KB ideals (e.g., students take high-level responsibility), and (2) to suggest areas to consider as we put KB analytics tools into practice. These questions are applicable to the other contributions mentioned above. Tan and Teo remind us that we should not forget what these KB analytics are developed for. They also distinguish augmented intelligence from artificial intelligence (AI) and argue the KB community may want to side with the augmented intelligence camp, which is also called intelligence augmentation (IA) by scholars (Engelbart, 1962).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a promising direction for the community to consolidate a set of such guiding questions for KB analytics and continue to refine them to bring technical work and KB concepts into alignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-on-future-work&#34;&gt;Thoughts on future work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyze KB discourse as a multidimensional phenomenon.&lt;/strong&gt; It is apparent that we as a community has quite impressive expertise in applying data science methods to KB discourse data (there is exciting work not covered here such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://gaoxiazhu.weebly.com/&#34;&gt;Dr. Gaoxia Zhu&amp;rsquo;s dissertation work on emotional dynamics&lt;/a&gt;).  We now need to push for integrated views of KB discourse by bringing various analytical perspectives together &amp;ndash; social, semantic, temporal, emotional, spatial, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Involve students and teachers to co-design analytics tools.&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple papers in these sessions have highlighted the need to look at human factors as we design and deploy KB analytics. This recognition is aligned with &lt;a href=&#34;https://learning-analytics.info/index.php/JLA/article/view/6627&#34;&gt;human-centered design sought by the learning analytics community&lt;/a&gt; in recent years. Feng et al. show us important work that needs to take place to move from analytical results to actionable insights. What&amp;rsquo;s useful is not determined by the researchers or analytical methods; instead, it&amp;rsquo;s determined by the students and teachers who sense-make and problem-solve with the provided information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Articulate conceptual groundings of measures and analytical decisions.&lt;/strong&gt; As mentioned above, the graph/network approach is a promising direction. However, we still need to do a better job at grounding network measures/indices in KB concepts or phenomena. What does betweenness centrality in the word network really mean? Why only nouns are retained in a knowledge graph? Why a certain threshold is chosen when trimming a network? We need to be mindful of these questions and analytical decisions in future work. As a community, we should consider mapping out measures we have, connect them with KB constructs, and examine conceptual congruence and incongruence. Actually, we may need to do a network analysis of our own KB analytics work to identify gaps and future directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for now. I will provide an updated view after the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teachers&#39; networked professional learning with MOOCs</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2020teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 21:06:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2020teachers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs) are used to support professional learning at scale in many countries. The present study examined a MOOC named Flipped Classrooms that was specially designed for in-service teachers in China. This MOOC was offered for seven consecutive iterations across three years and allowed teachers to re-take this course in connection with their teaching practice. Overall, 16% of all 105,370 learners enrolled in at least two iterations of the MOOC. To understand their learning motivations, their learning engagement within the MOOC, and the connections they forged between the MOOC and their teaching, we conducted a mixed-methods study using multiple data sources including course registration records, course entry surveys, learning performance data, click logs, and semi-structured interviews. Results indicated that teacher-learners re-took the MOOC for various reasons such as refreshing domain understanding, improving grades, and addressing practical problems. Click log analysis found MOOC re-takers with different performance trajectories demonstrated distinct learning patterns across iterations. Qualitative analysis of the interview data revealed additional insights into learning within the MOOC and connections forged by the re-takers between the MOOC and their teaching practice. This study contributes fresh insights into the MOOC literature by investigating MOOC re-takers and sheds light on the promise of using MOOC to support networked professional learning. Implications for future MOOCs and teacher learning opportunities are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and connecting: Using social annotation in online classes</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/zhu2020reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 10:45:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/zhu2020reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purpose: The COVID-19 pandemic has forced many instructors to rapidly shift to online/distance teaching. With a narrow preparation window, many instructors are at a loss of strategies that are both effective in responding to the crisis and compatible with their professional practices. One urgent need in classrooms at all levels is to support social reading of course materials. To fulfill this need, this paper aims to present a systematic literature review on using Web annotation in K-12 and higher education to provide practical and evidence-based recommendations for educators to incorporate social annotation in online teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design/methodology/approach: This paper presents a systematic literature review of the use of Web annotation in formal education. The authors reviewed 39 articles that met the inclusion criteria and extracted the following information from each article: level of education, subject area, learning theory, learning activity design, Web annotation technology, research methods and learning outcomes. Studies were further analyzed and synthesized by the genre of learning activity design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Findings: The authors identified five types of social annotation activity design: processing domain-specific knowledge, supporting argumentation and inquiry, improving literacy skills, supporting instructor and peer assessment and connecting online learning spaces. In addition, the authors developed practical recommendations on setting pedagogical goals, selecting annotation tools, deciding instructor involvement and developing evaluation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originality/value: This study provides a timely response to online/distance teaching under the COVID-19 pandemic. It is a hope that these identified application areas, in combination with four practical recommendations, would provide pragmatic and evidence-based support for educators to engage learners in reading, learning and connecting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting messy with data: Tools and strategies to help students analyze and interpret complex data sources</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/rosenberg2020getting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 10:52:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/rosenberg2020getting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoLAR Webinar: Analyzing Learning and Teaching through the Lens of Networks</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2020-solar-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2020-solar-webinar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Networks is a popular metaphor we use to make sense of the world. Networks provide a powerful way to think about a variety of phenomena from economic and political interdependencies among countries, interactions between humans in local communities, and to protein interactions in drug development. In education, networks give ways to describe human relationships, neural activities in brains, technology-mediated interactions, language development, discourse patterns, etc. The common use of networks to depict these phenomena is unsurprising given the variety of educational theories and approaches that are deeply committed to a networked view of learning. Compatible with this view, network analysis is applied as a method for understanding learning and connections involved in learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This webinar will explore the conceptual, methodological, and practical use of networks in learning analytics by presenting examples from real-world learning and teaching scenarios that cover the following areas. First, in learning analytics networks are a powerful tool to visually represent connections of all sorts in ways that are straightforward for humans to act upon. Second, network analysis offers a set of metrics that are useful for characterising and assessing various dimensions of learning. Third, the modelling of networks can help to develop explanatory theories about complex learning processes. We will present case studies in each area to demonstrate the utility of networks in learning analytics. By doing so, we argue for a wider conception of learning as a networked phenomenon and call for future learning analytics work in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;slideshttpsspeakerdeckcombodongsolar-webinar-analyzing-learning-and-teaching-through-the-lens-of-networks&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/bodong/solar-webinar-analyzing-learning-and-teaching-through-the-lens-of-networks&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;script async class=&#34;speakerdeck-embed&#34; data-id=&#34;7b0377c738ee4455b94d75207fe05b90&#34; data-ratio=&#34;1.77777777777778&#34; src=&#34;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-recordinghttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvged95ilsbjct1s&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gEd95ILsBjc&amp;amp;t=1s&#34;&gt;Video Recording&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gEd95ILsBjc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Socio-Temporal Dynamics in Peer Interaction Events</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2020-lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 12:19:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2020-lak/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Conditions for Knowledge Building for the Public Good</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-icce-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-icce-keynote/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Epistemic Cognition in Knowledge Building: Discourse, Tools, and Analytics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-pel-episteic-cultures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-pel-episteic-cultures/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating Collaborative Learning in a Teacher Professional Development MOOC</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-aera-mooc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-aera-mooc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IdeaMagnets: Towards Knowledge Building on the Open Web</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-ideamagnets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-ideamagnets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teachers as Co-designers of a Knowledge Building Environment</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-teacher/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is about timing: Network prestige in asynchronous online discussions</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-mu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 21:08:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-mu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Value-Sensitive Learning Analytics Design</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 21:08:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-lak/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing for Networked Collaborative Discourse: An UnLMSApproach</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-tw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-tw/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Value-Sensitive Learning Analytics Design</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-lak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the slides.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Use in K-12 Schools: Cases from North America</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-mingda-institute-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-mingda-institute-lecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the Google Slides.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotation as Infrastructure for Next Generation Digital Learning Environments</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-educause/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-educause/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the Google Slides.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated STEM learning in an idea-centered knowledge-building environment</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/hong2018-ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/hong2018-ch/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fostering student engagement in online discussion through social learning analytics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-mc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-mc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using differentiated feedback to improve performance in introductory statistics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/cai2018-za/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/cai2018-za/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fostering scientific understanding and epistemic beliefs throughjudgments of promisingness</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-kl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-kl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two tales of time: uncovering the significance of sequentialpatterns among contribution types in knowledge-buildingdiscourse</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-il/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-il/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics for knowledge creation: Towards epistemic agency anddesign-mode thinking</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-kn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-kn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schools as knowledge-building organizations: Thirty years ofdesign research</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-od/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-od/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
