<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>https://meefen.github.io/authors/bodong-chen/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Bodong Chen.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 12:31:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://meefen.github.io/authors/bodong-chen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Infrastructures: Initial Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2021-10-knowledge-infrastructures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 12:31:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2021-10-knowledge-infrastructures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-infrastructure&#34;&gt;What is infrastructure?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/infrastructure&#34;&gt;Merriam Webster&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infra-&lt;/em&gt; means &amp;ldquo;below;&amp;rdquo; so the infrastructure is the &amp;ldquo;underlying structure&amp;rdquo; of a country and its economy, the fixed installations that it needs in order to function. These include roads, bridges, dams, the water and sewer systems, railways and subways, airports, and harbors. These are generally government-built and publicly owned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This general notion of infrastructure is vividly illustrated by the recent &lt;em&gt;Infrastructure for Rebuilding America (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.transportation.gov/buildamerica/financing/infra-grants/infrastructure-rebuilding-america&#34;&gt;INFRA&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt; plan that aims at rebuilding the USA&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure. What is commonly understood by the public is the &lt;strong&gt;material&lt;/strong&gt; property of infrastructure, as physical objects, especially large objects, that allow human activities to be carried on on top of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Ea0EW9RXYAAE9xT?format=jpg&amp;name=4096x4096&#39; width=&#39;80%&#39; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-relational-property-of-infrastructure&#34;&gt;The relational property of infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is often less discussed, however, is the notion of infrastructure as a &lt;strong&gt;relational&lt;/strong&gt; property instead of a thing stripped of use (Star &amp;amp; Ruhleder, 1996). Fundamentally, &amp;ldquo;a relational definition of infrastructure means that infrastructure is only infrastructure when it serves an infrastructural function&amp;rdquo; (Read, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relational property of infrastructure can be best illustrated by the extra-low bridges built over the Southern State Parkway &amp;ldquo;to keep buses from the city away from Jones Beach—buses presumably filled with the poor blacks and Puerto Ricans&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-07-09/robert-moses-and-his-racist-parkway-explained&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). Robert Moses directed engineers to build these bridges extra-low so buses and people who could not afford a car cannot access the &amp;ldquo;park-way&amp;rdquo; and the beaches this parkway it connects to. Infrastructure is apparently &lt;strong&gt;relational&lt;/strong&gt; in this case. For bus riders who were/are excluded access to the parkway, the infrastructure becomes a structural obstacle for their movement through space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://assets.bwbx.io/images/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/iDNFHVKfudVc/v0/800x-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structures created by infrastructures can be less visible in today&amp;rsquo;s information society. In recent years, China has rolled out a massive digital payment infrastructure. QR codes are posted everywhere &amp;ndash; in taxis, street food stands, and luxury stores &amp;ndash; so that a payment transaction is made not by cash or card by scanning a QR code. While this new digital payment infrastructure has revolutionized the way people pay or receive payment. It has also posed barriers for those without smartphones, mobile internet, or basic information literacy. Elder citizens are especially suffering from the penetration of mobile payments in every sector of the society including transportation, medicare, and daily purchases (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scmp.com/lifestyle/family-relationships/article/3114225/elderly-left-behind-spread-digital-services-china&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). It becomes clear that while the digital payment infrastructure has made business more convenient and efficient, the impact is &lt;strong&gt;relational&lt;/strong&gt; as it has also left out many people from participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;img src=&#39;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/methode/2020/12/17/ad01311c-3f82-11eb-be63-b2d34bb06b66_1320x770_125014.jpg&#39; width=&#39;50%&#39; /&gt; --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/d8/images/methode/2020/12/17/ad01311c-3f82-11eb-be63-b2d34bb06b66_1320x770_125014.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that infrastructure is a &lt;strong&gt;relational&lt;/strong&gt; property instead of a thing stripped of use has analytical consequences. Bowker (1994) proposes to conduct &amp;ldquo;infrastructural inversion&amp;rdquo; as a methodology that de-emphasizes things and people and puts infrastructural relations at the center. By doing so, the analysis of an infrastructure is broadened from the things to include shifts in human practices and social configurations. This methodology reveals infrastructural technologies such as paper, clocks, public transit lines, and more recently electric charging networks are central factors in changes in people&amp;rsquo;s social life. Various components of the system (policies, narratives, capital, human agency) become more apparent, surfacing the structure that is &amp;ldquo;infra-&amp;rdquo; (aka. below) for closer analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on these ideas, Star and Ruhleder (1996) articulate several dimensions of infrastructure (p. 113).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Embeddedness&lt;/em&gt;. Infrastructure is &amp;ldquo;sunk&amp;rdquo; into, inside of, other structures, social arrangements and technologies;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transparency&lt;/em&gt;. Infrastructure is transparent to use, in the sense that it does not have to be reinvented each time or assembled for each task, but invisibly supports those tasks;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reach or scope&lt;/em&gt;. This may be either spatial or temporal—infrastructure has reach beyond a single event or one-site practice;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learned as part of membership&lt;/em&gt;. The taken-forgrantedness of artifacts and organizational arrangements is a &lt;em&gt;sine qua non&lt;/em&gt; of membership in a community of practice. Strangers and outsiders encounter infrastructure as a target object to be learned about. New participants acquire a naturalized familiarity with its objects as they become members;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Links with conventions of practice&lt;/em&gt;. Infrastructure both shapes and is shaped by the conventions of a community of practice, e.g. the ways that cycles of day-night work are affected by and affect electrical power rates and needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Embodiment of standards&lt;/em&gt;. Modified by scope and often by conflicting conventions, infrastructure takes on transparency by plugging into other infrastructures and tools in a standardized fashion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Built on an installed base&lt;/em&gt;. Infrastructure does not grow &lt;em&gt;de novo&lt;/em&gt;: it wrestles with the &amp;ldquo;inertia of the installed base&amp;rdquo; and inherits strengths and limitations from that base. Optical fibers run along old railroad lines; new systems are designed for backward compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Becomes visible upon breakdown&lt;/em&gt;. The normally invisible quality of working infrastructure becomes visible when it breaks; the server is down, the bridge washes out, there is a power blackout. Even when there are back-up mechanisms or procedures, their existence further highlights the now-visible infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These dimensions further illuminate areas infrastructural work (both design and research) could engage with. For instance, attending to embeddedness and transparency of infrastructure would allow us to not only &amp;ldquo;see through&amp;rdquo; things but also take moments to &amp;ldquo;see at&amp;rdquo; them, as phenomenologists may suggest (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://iep.utm.edu/phenomsc/&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). Recognizing the historical context in which an infrastructure is created, such as the EV (electric vehicle) charger shown below, could help us understand why it is designed in a certain way. The connection between infrastructure with community membership, conventions of practice, and broad spatio-temporal reach encourage us to consider &lt;strong&gt;epistemic cultures&lt;/strong&gt; (Knorr Cetina, 1999) that a particular infrastructure gives rise to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.avnet.com/wps/wcm/connect/onesite/7a654777-c63a-4f87-8dc5-190e59c7f1f8/EV-Charging-Station-EN-Image.jpg?MOD=AJPERES&amp;amp;CACHEID=ROOTWORKSPACE.Z18_NA5A1I41L0ICD0ABNDMDDG0000-7a654777-c63a-4f87-8dc5-190e59c7f1f8-n0vxVsO/&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.avnet.com/wps/portal/abacus/resources/article/intro-to-ev-charging-infrastructure-design/&#34;&gt;Photo Credit&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;knowledge-infrastructures&#34;&gt;Knowledge infrastructures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building on the notion of infrastructure, knowledge infrastructures are established to create and communicate &amp;ldquo;justified true beliefs,&amp;rdquo; and to refute and throttle &amp;ldquo;false beliefs.&amp;rdquo; The concern over knowledge production gives knowledge infrastructures a different focus than, for lack of a better word, material infrastructures. For example, a collider used in high-energy physics rely on energy provided by other infrastructures while it acts as an infrastructure for thousands of scientists (Knorr Cetina, 1999).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using climate science as an example, Edwards (2010) defined &lt;strong&gt;knowledge infrastructures&lt;/strong&gt; as &amp;ldquo;robust networks of people, artifacts, and institutions that generate, share, and maintain specific knowledge about the human and natural worlds.&amp;rdquo; As further explained in Edwards et al. (2013):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key to the infrastructure perspective is their modular, multi-layered, rough-cut character. Infrastructures are not systems, in the sense of fully coherent, deliberately engineered, end-to-end processes. Rather, infrastructures are &lt;em&gt;ecologies&lt;/em&gt; or complex adaptive systems; they consist of numerous systems, each with unique origins and goals, which are made to inter-operate by means of standards, socket layers, social practices, norms, and individual behaviors that smooth out the connections among them. This adaptive process is continuous, as individual elements change and new ones are introduced — and it is not necessarily always successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ecological and systems approach to knowledge infrastructures adds necessary richness. Rather than thinking about a single tool for thought or productivity, the systems approach foregrounds people and social configurations while also recognizing the political dimension of knowledge production (Edwards et al., 2013). While important work on technical systems and standards should continue, we also need to systematically consider the consequences of knowledge infrastructures for individual behaviors, social organization, and political mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the notion of a knowledge society is still fairly new, there is relatively little effort on knowledge infrastructures. While a society may quickly rally behind the creation of a more visible infrastructure such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/electric-power-and-natural-gas/our-insights/how-charging-in-buildings-can-power-up-the-electric-vehicle-industry&#34;&gt;the EV charging network&lt;/a&gt;, focused discussions of knowledge infrastructures remain rare at the societal level and are left in the hands of different disciplines and research areas. One example that has received societal attention is the Open Science movement. As explained by Brian Nosek from the &lt;em&gt;Open Science Framework&lt;/em&gt; in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/uF1AF20R5as?t=127&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;, infrastructure is created to enable open science practices such as pre-registration, data/code sharing, and replication. To change culture in science we need to change infrastructure. However, such work only involves a small fraction of people, and the society by and large does not have a strategy for creating knowledge infrastructures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;knowledge-infrastructures-for-all&#34;&gt;Knowledge infrastructures for all?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe prior definitions of knowledge infrastructures (e.g., by Edwards et al.) needs to be broadened up to include all members of the society so that knowledge infrastructures are created for all of us to become adequate producers, users, and stewards of knowledge. The Edwards et al. definition remains focused on people who are thought to be working on the frontiers of human knowledge. It may not be an intentional choice by &lt;a href=&#34;http://knowledgeinfrastructures.org/&#34;&gt;their working group&lt;/a&gt;, but due to inertia in prior work that is focused on scientists working in laboratories (e.g., Latour). While not every citizen needs to be involved in the design of the Large Hadron Collider, it is increasingly &lt;strong&gt;important for a society to involve more people in (1) the knowledge-creation enterprise that generates new knowledge and (2) the collective sensemaking of issues so that knowledge&amp;mdash;and quality knowledge practices&amp;mdash;are used in a reliable way for decision-making by various types of epistemic agents&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, while knowledge infrastructures have been historically tailored to experts, the democratization of knowledge creation demands for knowledge infrastructures that are accessible to the citizenry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- %%- While experts and laypeople share tools for thought (a note taking device either a notebook or a computer), and these tools will still be personal, there is a need to...%% --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &amp;ldquo;a world of abundant information, hyperlinked ideas, permission-free resources, highly public interaction, and massive, unresolved disagreement&amp;rdquo; (Weinberger), our collective attention needs to shift away from technocentric solutions toward epistemic performance of everyday citizens who are dealing with an increasingly complex, fast, and volatile information environment.  The combat with misinformation and infodemic rests on the society&amp;rsquo;s knowledge infrastructures, and in particular their relational properties for people.  While many information systems are engineered to maximize user attention, in some cases in sacrifice of the user&amp;rsquo;s information diet and epistemic performance, infrastructural work is needed to advance these dimensions pointed out by Star &amp;amp; Ruhleder (1996) so that everyone becomes stewards of human knowledge based on elevated epistemic performance instead of pre-existing convictions or simplistic affiliations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;consider-knowledge-infrastructures-in-knowledge-building&#34;&gt;Consider knowledge infrastructures in Knowledge Building&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knowledge Building&lt;/em&gt; (KB) as a distinct educational approach engages students in producing and improving ideas to solve authentic problems. It is synonymous with &lt;em&gt;knowledge creation&lt;/em&gt; that is discussed in organizational settings (Bereiter &amp;amp; Scardamalia, 2014). Similar to a team of knowledge workers, students work as a collective to produce something new and of interest to the collective. Designs &amp;ndash; both pedagogical and technological &amp;ndash; are put in place to empower students&amp;rsquo; epistemic agency, so that they could focus on improving ideas (vs. performing tasks), collaborate with each other (vs. focus on individual performance), see the big picture of their work (vs. finish small tasks assigned to them), and make high-level decisions (vs. outsourcing the decisions to an adult). In essence, the way students approach knowledge is very much in line with that in a research team, even though students (and the teacher) also need to meet curricular goals defined by relevant educational regimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the parallel between KB and knowledge creation, knowledge infrastructures designed for knowledge workers are also potentially useful for students in KB classrooms. For instance, Joel Chan argues there is a lack of proper infrastructure for researchers to make knowledge synthesis, motivating him to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1H1eS_YiPGP46eM-SduEhqhv3H--2Rzf4EMZ8HWLO75U/edit#slide=id.g530a8ea1fa_2_75&#34;&gt;design a new medium for knowledge synthesis&lt;/a&gt;. Students in KB classrooms face the same challenge (even though on a different magnitude) when they have put extensive effort in an area leading to a complex idea landscape. Students for sure also need a better infrastructure for knowledge synthesis in their community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While technological innovations are needed to design new knowledge infrastructures for KB, the &lt;em&gt;relational&lt;/em&gt; aspect of infrastructure elaborated above reminds us (again) of the importance of attending to community norms, knowledge practices, individual dispositions and behaviors, and complex interactions among these factors. &lt;strong&gt;At a minimum, the notion of infrastructure interweaves theoretical, pedagogical, and technological ideas in Knowledge Building together and (re)focus the discussion on each student&amp;rsquo;s relations with the infrastructure.&lt;/strong&gt; It reveals different relations between humans and infrastructures (such as contributing to collective work and celebrating individual growths) to be looked at, instead of being looked through; it brings out the relations held by different human agents (students, teachers) with knowledge infrastructures for dialogues; it connects challenges that are often dealt with in silos (such as UI design, teacher PD, student assessment) so that they could be looked at together and advanced in tandem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given today&amp;rsquo;s complex information landscape, &lt;strong&gt;another promising direction is to explicitly scaffold students&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;infrastructural agency&lt;/em&gt; as part of supporting their &lt;em&gt;epistemic agency&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Infrastructural agency in knowledge work is about being aware of the consequences of a particular infrastructure on one&amp;rsquo;s work and being able to deliberately select and engineer an infrastructure for particular knowledge processes. This idea may sound overreaching. But it seems increasingly clear that knowledge infrastructures and epistemic performance go hand-in-hand in today&amp;rsquo;s information ecology, when information systems are so intricately engineered that without careful attention to their quirks and embedded values one cannot develop a good enough picture of knowledge processes in these systems. For example, an academic who rely on Twitter as one source of research news needs to be aware of the way(s) Twitter sorts one&amp;rsquo;s news feed and hopefully develop a counter strategy to offset potential pitfalls a single platform like Twitter may introduce. There was less a need for such awareness when we had few choices and algorithmic decisions were less prevalent in one&amp;rsquo;s educational experience and social life. Given its long tradition of empowering student agency, Knowledge Building has an opportunity to incorporate &lt;em&gt;infrastructural agency&lt;/em&gt; in its design principles so that students are explicitly supported to take control over their knowledge infrastructures while building knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;we need infrastructures for building knowledge about Knowledge Building itself.&lt;/strong&gt; Education systems need to develop knowledge about its operations and especially about the so-called learning outcomes. Various information systems, such as Student Information Systems (SIS) and Learning Management Systems (LMS), are put in place to support day-to-day educational activities. Tests are administered from time to time to evaluate student progress. Knowledge about learning and learners gets generated at different levels to inform decision making and educational practice. Unfortunately, knowledge infrastructures provided by the school system are not meeting the needs of KB. Because of KB&amp;rsquo;s focus on idea improvement, more local, granular knowledge about knowledge building is needed. While KB has a design principle on &amp;ldquo;embedded, concurrent, transformative assessment&amp;rdquo; and we have various assessment tools that operate on process data, there are tensions reflected in various efforts such as assessing students individual growth based on collective discourse, aligning KB discourse with curriculum standards, and advancing socio-emotional dimensions of KB. While there is nothing wrong with advancing in multiple directions, there is a need for a more coordinated plan for advancing our knowledge of knowledge building carried out in real-world settings. An infrastructural approach, and explicit attention to relational properties of knowledge building infrastructures, could help us cope with these various needs for knowledge about Knowledge Building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made these points in relation to Knowledge Building, a pedagogy and learning theory I have been actively working on. But these ideas can be generalized to the learning sciences and education in general. Scholars have incorporated various notions of infrastructure in educational research and practice (Bell, 2019; Bielaczyc, 2013; Guribye, 2015; Hoeppe, 2019; Markauskaite &amp;amp; Goodyear, 2017; Penuel, 2019). &lt;strong&gt;Is it time for us to rally around the idea &amp;ndash; to critique, brainstorm, and design-think?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-readings&#34;&gt;Further readings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;on-infrastructures&#34;&gt;On infrastructures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edwards, P., Jackson, S., Chalmers, M., Bowker, G., Borgman, C., Ribes, D., Calvert, S., &amp;amp; others. (2013). Knowledge infrastructures: Intellectual frameworks and research challenges. Deep Blue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edwards, P. N. (2010). A Vast Machine: Computer Models, Climate Data, and the Politics of Global Warming. The MIT Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knorr Cetina, K. (1999). Epistemic cultures: How the sciences make knowledge. Harvard University Press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read, S. (2019). The Infrastructural Function: A Relational Theory of Infrastructure for Writing Studies. Journal of Business and Technical Communication, 33(3), 233–267. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1050651919834980&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/1050651919834980&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star, S. L., &amp;amp; Ruhleder, K. (1996). Steps Toward an Ecology of Infrastructure: Design and Access for Large Information Spaces. Information Systems Research, 7(1), 111–134. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1287/isre.7.1.111&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1287/isre.7.1.111&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;on-infrastructures-in-education&#34;&gt;On infrastructures in education&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bell, P. (2019). Infrastructuring Teacher Learning about Equitable Science Instruction. Journal of Science Teacher Education. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/1046560X.2019.1668218&#34;&gt;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/1046560X.2019.1668218&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bielaczyc, K. (2013). Informing Design Research: Learning From Teachers’ Designs of Social Infrastructure. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 22(2), 258–311. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/10508406.2012.691925&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/10508406.2012.691925&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guribye, F. (2015). From Artifacts to Infrastructures in Studies of Learning Practices. Mind, Culture, and Activity, 22(2), 184–198. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/10749039.2015.1021358&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/10749039.2015.1021358&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hoeppe, G. (2019). Mediating Environments and Objects as Knowledge Infrastructure. Computer Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW), 28(1), 25–59. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10606-018-9342-0&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10606-018-9342-0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markauskaite, L., &amp;amp; Goodyear, P. (2017). Epistemic Tools, Instruments and Infrastructure in Professional Knowledge Work and Learning. In L. Markauskaite &amp;amp; P. Goodyear (Eds.), Epistemic Fluency and Professional Education: Innovation, Knowledgeable Action and Actionable Knowledge (pp. 341–366). Springer Netherlands. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-007-4369-4_12&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-007-4369-4_12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Penuel, W. R. (2019). Infrastructuring as a Practice of Design-Based Research for Supporting and Studying Equitable Implementation and Sustainability of Innovations. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 28(4–5), 659–677. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/10508406.2018.1552151&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/10508406.2018.1552151&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborative Learning at Scale</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2021collaborative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 10:45:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2021collaborative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CSCL community has traditionally focused on collaborative learning in small groups or communities. Given the rise of mass collaboration and learning at scale, the community is facing unprecedented opportunity to expand its views to advance collaborative learning at scale. In this chapter, we first explicate the history and development of collaborative learning at scale and contend that both learning and collaboration need to be reconceptualized for the nascent context. We propose a framework that considers scale as either a problem to be mitigated or an asset to be harnessed, and then review pedagogical and technological innovations representing these two approaches. We conclude by discussing key tensions and challenges facing collaborative learning at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where is Knowledge Building Analytics Headed?</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/post/2020-11-15-kb-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:28:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/post/2020-11-15-kb-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Knowledge Building Summer Institute (KBSI)&lt;/strong&gt; is going to be special. First, it&amp;rsquo;s held near the end of November, for the first time in summer for folks from the Southern Hemisphere. Second, the conference is going to be virtual, following a hybrid synchronous&amp;ndash;asynchronous model. Much work will be done in Knowledge Forum asynchronously before interactive sessions in Zoom on the conference days. Last but not least, this year&amp;rsquo;s conference will feature a global KB design experiment, &lt;em&gt;Saving the Planet, Saving Lives&lt;/em&gt;, led by colleagues from Ontario and Singpapore. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://ikit.org/summerinstitute2020/index.php/program/&#34;&gt;conference program here&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, it&amp;rsquo;s especially exciting to see a broadening interest in Knowledge Building (KB) Analytics in this intimate community. I still believe KB has a special place in learning analytics because its views on learning and education (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://learning-analytics.info/index.php/JLA/article/view/4552&#34;&gt;Chen &amp;amp; Zhang, 2016&lt;/a&gt;). KB&amp;rsquo;s attempt to refashion education into an effort aligned with knowledge societies can also help learning analytics find more common grounds with CSCW, HCI, knowledge analytics, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This year, there are one theme and two sessions dedicated to Knowledge Building Analytics at KBSI. Here are my quick takeaways, before the conference, from reading papers in these sessions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;graphnetwork-based-approaches&#34;&gt;Graph/network based approaches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of contributions have adopted a graph/network approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xue, Zhang, &amp;amp; Xu (Nanjing Normal Unversity)&lt;/strong&gt; propose to construct &lt;strong&gt;dynamic knowledge graphs (DKG)&lt;/strong&gt; to assess and foster conceptual change. The DKG approach integrates a wide range of techniques from natural language processing (POS tagging, topic modeling, Word2vec), association rule mining, and graph visualization. With the constructed graph, centrality indices can be used to surface key concepts, which collectively provide indicators of a community&amp;rsquo;s current conceptual understanding. The DKG approach is an important technical advancement for KB analytics. It builds on a long-term interest in using network/graph approaches (e.g., KBDeX) in the KB community. It expands our KB analytics work by combining nascent graph database technologies, data mining techniques, and front-end web interfaces to deliver a complete analytics package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grounded in the &amp;ldquo;Good moves in knowledge-creating dialogue&amp;rdquo; framework by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ckbg.org/qwerty/index.php/qwerty/article/view/242&#34;&gt;Bereiter and Scardamalia (2016)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Feng, van Aalst, &amp;amp; Chan (University of Hong Kong)&lt;/strong&gt; propose to use the &lt;strong&gt;Idea-Friend Maps&lt;/strong&gt; to help students consider new ideas, meta-dialogue, high-level ideas, etc. The Idea-Friend Maps use the word networks extracted from KBDeX and enrich them with important information such as knowledge problems. A major contribution made by the Idea-Friend Maps project is it meaningfully connects sophisticated conceptual ideas (i.e. the Good Moves framework) and analytic tools (i.e., KBDeX) to student engagement. The Maps and their accompanying questions are actionable for students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hussein &amp;amp; Chen (Univeresity of Minnesota)&lt;/strong&gt; propose to use network-based text analysis to bridge gaps in knowledge-building discourse, by using network indices and network phenomena such as structural holes. This work is situated in the goal of connecting discourse across spaces but is applicable to meta-discourse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cross-cutting theme among three contributions (Hussein &amp;amp; Chen; Feng, van Aalst, &amp;amp; Chan; Xue, Zhang, &amp;amp; Xu) is the use of network/graph approaches in KB Analytics. Feng et al. use socio-semantic networks created by KBDeX; Hussein &amp;amp; Chen use text networks that rely on network analysis techniques for topic modeling and structural analysis; Xue et al. integrate a range of data science methods in a graph analysis scheme that leads to the identification of dominant terms. We collectively have an interesting mix of ideas about how to use graphs/networks in KB analytics. Graph/network analysis is a promising direction for our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-facing-analytics&#34;&gt;Student-facing analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides Feng, van Aalst, &amp;amp; Chan&amp;rsquo;s Idea-Friend Maps described above, &lt;strong&gt;Ma, Akyea, &amp;amp; Martin (University of Toronto)&lt;/strong&gt; have done some really interesting work engaging 8- to 11-year-olds to review and critique current analytic tools in Knowledge Forum. &amp;ldquo;[Students] demonstrated sophisticated interpretations of their online activities with the Knowledge Forum analytic tools. Not only were they honest and open about receiving feedback through novel forms of data visualization, they were also aware of the potential limitations of these tools and offered thoughtful and insightful feedback for our engineers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Xue et al.&amp;lsquo;s paper, they also mention that pilot studies of the DKG with teachers and students are also underway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not necessarily need more advanced analytical techniques. Work that scaffolds student sense-making and use of analytic information is equally (or even more) important. Trying to put more analytic tools &amp;ndash; good ones &amp;ndash; in the hands of students is a promising idea that&amp;rsquo;s aligned with Knowledge Building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bridge-technical-work-on-analytics-and-kb-conceptsprinciples&#34;&gt;Bridge technical work on analytics and KB concepts/principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tan &amp;amp; Teo (National Institute of Education, Singapore)&lt;/strong&gt; take a much-needed meta perspective. Based on a literature review of KB analytics, they propose two sets of guiding questions that are instrumental for future KB analytics design and development. These questions achieve two important goals: (1) to ground analytics design and use in KB ideals (e.g., students take high-level responsibility), and (2) to suggest areas to consider as we put KB analytics tools into practice. These questions are applicable to the other contributions mentioned above. Tan and Teo remind us that we should not forget what these KB analytics are developed for. They also distinguish augmented intelligence from artificial intelligence (AI) and argue the KB community may want to side with the augmented intelligence camp, which is also called intelligence augmentation (IA) by scholars (Engelbart, 1962).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a promising direction for the community to consolidate a set of such guiding questions for KB analytics and continue to refine them to bring technical work and KB concepts into alignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-on-future-work&#34;&gt;Thoughts on future work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyze KB discourse as a multidimensional phenomenon.&lt;/strong&gt; It is apparent that we as a community has quite impressive expertise in applying data science methods to KB discourse data (there is exciting work not covered here such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://gaoxiazhu.weebly.com/&#34;&gt;Dr. Gaoxia Zhu&amp;rsquo;s dissertation work on emotional dynamics&lt;/a&gt;).  We now need to push for integrated views of KB discourse by bringing various analytical perspectives together &amp;ndash; social, semantic, temporal, emotional, spatial, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Involve students and teachers to co-design analytics tools.&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple papers in these sessions have highlighted the need to look at human factors as we design and deploy KB analytics. This recognition is aligned with &lt;a href=&#34;https://learning-analytics.info/index.php/JLA/article/view/6627&#34;&gt;human-centered design sought by the learning analytics community&lt;/a&gt; in recent years. Feng et al. show us important work that needs to take place to move from analytical results to actionable insights. What&amp;rsquo;s useful is not determined by the researchers or analytical methods; instead, it&amp;rsquo;s determined by the students and teachers who sense-make and problem-solve with the provided information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Articulate conceptual groundings of measures and analytical decisions.&lt;/strong&gt; As mentioned above, the graph/network approach is a promising direction. However, we still need to do a better job at grounding network measures/indices in KB concepts or phenomena. What does betweenness centrality in the word network really mean? Why only nouns are retained in a knowledge graph? Why a certain threshold is chosen when trimming a network? We need to be mindful of these questions and analytical decisions in future work. As a community, we should consider mapping out measures we have, connect them with KB constructs, and examine conceptual congruence and incongruence. Actually, we may need to do a network analysis of our own KB analytics work to identify gaps and future directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for now. I will provide an updated view after the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teachers&#39; networked professional learning with MOOCs</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2020teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 21:06:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2020teachers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;: Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs) are used to support professional learning at scale in many countries. The present study examined a MOOC named Flipped Classrooms that was specially designed for in-service teachers in China. This MOOC was offered for seven consecutive iterations across three years and allowed teachers to re-take this course in connection with their teaching practice. Overall, 16% of all 105,370 learners enrolled in at least two iterations of the MOOC. To understand their learning motivations, their learning engagement within the MOOC, and the connections they forged between the MOOC and their teaching, we conducted a mixed-methods study using multiple data sources including course registration records, course entry surveys, learning performance data, click logs, and semi-structured interviews. Results indicated that teacher-learners re-took the MOOC for various reasons such as refreshing domain understanding, improving grades, and addressing practical problems. Click log analysis found MOOC re-takers with different performance trajectories demonstrated distinct learning patterns across iterations. Qualitative analysis of the interview data revealed additional insights into learning within the MOOC and connections forged by the re-takers between the MOOC and their teaching practice. This study contributes fresh insights into the MOOC literature by investigating MOOC re-takers and sheds light on the promise of using MOOC to support networked professional learning. Implications for future MOOCs and teacher learning opportunities are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and connecting: Using social annotation in online classes</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/zhu2020reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 10:45:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/zhu2020reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purpose: The COVID-19 pandemic has forced many instructors to rapidly shift to online/distance teaching. With a narrow preparation window, many instructors are at a loss of strategies that are both effective in responding to the crisis and compatible with their professional practices. One urgent need in classrooms at all levels is to support social reading of course materials. To fulfill this need, this paper aims to present a systematic literature review on using Web annotation in K-12 and higher education to provide practical and evidence-based recommendations for educators to incorporate social annotation in online teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design/methodology/approach: This paper presents a systematic literature review of the use of Web annotation in formal education. The authors reviewed 39 articles that met the inclusion criteria and extracted the following information from each article: level of education, subject area, learning theory, learning activity design, Web annotation technology, research methods and learning outcomes. Studies were further analyzed and synthesized by the genre of learning activity design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Findings: The authors identified five types of social annotation activity design: processing domain-specific knowledge, supporting argumentation and inquiry, improving literacy skills, supporting instructor and peer assessment and connecting online learning spaces. In addition, the authors developed practical recommendations on setting pedagogical goals, selecting annotation tools, deciding instructor involvement and developing evaluation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originality/value: This study provides a timely response to online/distance teaching under the COVID-19 pandemic. It is a hope that these identified application areas, in combination with four practical recommendations, would provide pragmatic and evidence-based support for educators to engage learners in reading, learning and connecting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting messy with data: Tools and strategies to help students analyze and interpret complex data sources</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/rosenberg2020getting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 10:52:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/rosenberg2020getting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoLAR Webinar: Analyzing Learning and Teaching through the Lens of Networks</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2020-solar-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2020-solar-webinar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Networks is a popular metaphor we use to make sense of the world. Networks provide a powerful way to think about a variety of phenomena from economic and political interdependencies among countries, interactions between humans in local communities, and to protein interactions in drug development. In education, networks give ways to describe human relationships, neural activities in brains, technology-mediated interactions, language development, discourse patterns, etc. The common use of networks to depict these phenomena is unsurprising given the variety of educational theories and approaches that are deeply committed to a networked view of learning. Compatible with this view, network analysis is applied as a method for understanding learning and connections involved in learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This webinar will explore the conceptual, methodological, and practical use of networks in learning analytics by presenting examples from real-world learning and teaching scenarios that cover the following areas. First, in learning analytics networks are a powerful tool to visually represent connections of all sorts in ways that are straightforward for humans to act upon. Second, network analysis offers a set of metrics that are useful for characterising and assessing various dimensions of learning. Third, the modelling of networks can help to develop explanatory theories about complex learning processes. We will present case studies in each area to demonstrate the utility of networks in learning analytics. By doing so, we argue for a wider conception of learning as a networked phenomenon and call for future learning analytics work in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;slideshttpsspeakerdeckcombodongsolar-webinar-analyzing-learning-and-teaching-through-the-lens-of-networks&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/bodong/solar-webinar-analyzing-learning-and-teaching-through-the-lens-of-networks&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;script async class=&#34;speakerdeck-embed&#34; data-id=&#34;7b0377c738ee4455b94d75207fe05b90&#34; data-ratio=&#34;1.77777777777778&#34; src=&#34;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-recordinghttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvged95ilsbjct1s&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gEd95ILsBjc&amp;amp;t=1s&#34;&gt;Video Recording&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gEd95ILsBjc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Socio-Temporal Dynamics in Peer Interaction Events</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2020-lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 12:19:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2020-lak/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Conditions for Knowledge Building for the Public Good</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-icce-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-icce-keynote/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Epistemic Cognition in Knowledge Building: Discourse, Tools, and Analytics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-pel-episteic-cultures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-pel-episteic-cultures/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating Collaborative Learning in a Teacher Professional Development MOOC</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-aera-mooc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-aera-mooc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IdeaMagnets: Towards Knowledge Building on the Open Web</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-ideamagnets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-ideamagnets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teachers as Co-designers of a Knowledge Building Environment</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-kbsi-teacher/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is about timing: Network prestige in asynchronous online discussions</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-mu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 21:08:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-mu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Value-Sensitive Learning Analytics Design</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 21:08:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-lak/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing for Networked Collaborative Discourse: An UnLMSApproach</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-tw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2019-tw/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Value-Sensitive Learning Analytics Design</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-lak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2019-lak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the slides.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Use in K-12 Schools: Cases from North America</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-mingda-institute-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-mingda-institute-lecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the Google Slides.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotation as Infrastructure for Next Generation Digital Learning Environments</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-educause/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/talk/2018-educause/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the Google Slides.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated STEM learning in an idea-centered knowledge-building environment</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/hong2018-ch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/hong2018-ch/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fostering student engagement in online discussion through social learning analytics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-mc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2018-mc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using differentiated feedback to improve performance in introductory statistics</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/cai2018-za/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/cai2018-za/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fostering scientific understanding and epistemic beliefs throughjudgments of promisingness</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-kl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-kl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two tales of time: uncovering the significance of sequentialpatterns among contribution types in knowledge-buildingdiscourse</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-il/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2017-il/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics for knowledge creation: Towards epistemic agency anddesign-mode thinking</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-kn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-kn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schools as knowledge-building organizations: Thirty years ofdesign research</title>
      <link>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-od/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meefen.github.io/publication/chen2016-od/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
