<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academia on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/academia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academia on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/academia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Ongoing Experiment: Public Scholarly Annotation</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-07-public-scholarly-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-07-public-scholarly-annotation/</guid>
      <description>Background stories I value Open Scholarship and have been practicing it for years &amp;ndash; both in terms of doing it and learning to do it. Stian Haklev, an OER and Open Access champion, introduced me to this idea. He built a wiki-based workflow system, named researchr, and convinced a few OISE friends, including Cresencia Fong and Alisa Acosta, to share our annotations publicly, in a well-organized manner. For us, the benefits of using researchr are obvious: the system scaffolds the scholarly process of reading and annotating articles, as well as summarizing and organizing our notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic job search: A reading list</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-03-10-academic-job-search-a-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-03-10-academic-job-search-a-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>When a friend requested me to share some tips on academic job search, I realized it was the time to reflect on this unique journey of myself, or at least to organize a reading list that has inspired my own search. So here we go, a personal, and possibly biased, reading list about academic job search. Enjoy!
General  The Ones We Didn&amp;rsquo;t Hire Academic job hunt advice: Tips for searching for and landing a professorship Volatile and Decentralized: How to get a faculty job, Part 1: The application Volatile and Decentralized: How to get a faculty job, part 1b: How to get an interview Volatile and Decentralized: How to get a faculty job, Part 2: The interview Volatile and Decentralized: How to get a faculty job, Part 3: Negotiating the offer The Six Ways You’re Acting Like a Grad Student  Application materials  Sample CVs | Society for Research in Child Development SRCD | for development Samples for Academic Positions | UCSF Office of Career &amp;amp; Professional Devel Sell your research in writing Writing a Research Plan | Science Careers Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Van Noorden. (2014). Online collaboration: Scientists and the social network</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-06-28-vannoorden2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-06-28-vannoorden2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @VanNoorden2014
Van Noorden, R. (2014). Online collaboration: Scientists and the social network. Nature, 512(7513), 126–129. doi:10.1038/512126a
Notes A brief commentary on the use of social media (esp. ResearchGate) by academics.
Highlights Ijad Madisch, a Berlin-based former physician and virologist, tells this story as just one example of the successes of ResearchGate, which he founded with two friends six years ago. (p. 126)
The list of failed efforts to launch a ‘Facebook for science’ included Scientist Solutions, SciLinks, Epernicus, 2collab and Nature Network (run by the company that publishes Nature).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>