<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>E-learning on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/e-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in E-learning on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/e-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: A review of e-learning in Canada</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-26-abrami2006review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-26-abrami2006review/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @abrami2006review
Abrami, P. C., Bernard, R., Wade, A., Schmid, R. F., Borokhovski, E., Tamin, R., … others. (2006). A review of e-learning in Canada: A rough sketch of the evidence, gaps and promising directions. Canadian Journal of Learning and Technology/La Revue Canadienne de L’apprentissage et de La Technologie, 32(3).
Notes Highlights This review provides a rough sketch of the evidence, gaps and promising directions in e­learning from 2000 onwards, with a particular focus on Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: An extended systematic review of Canadian policy documents on e-Learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-26-borokhovski2011extended/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-26-borokhovski2011extended/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @borokhovski2011extended
Borokhovski, E., Bernard, R., Mills, E., Abrami, P. C., Wade, C. A., Tamim, R., … Surkes, M. A. (2011). An extended systematic review of Canadian policy documents on e-Learning: What we’re doing and not doing. Canadian Journal of Learning and Technology/La Revue Canadienne de L’apprentissage et de La Technologie, 37(3), 1–30.
Notes Highlights In total, 138 policy documents from Canadian provinces and territories and several federal agencies, dated from 2000 to 2010, were identified, retrieved and analyzed using prescriptive and emergent coding approaches with the purpose of uncovering and describing areas of commonality and inconsistency and, hence, determining where discussions about e-learning are lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: E-learning in Canada</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-26-mcgreal2007learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-26-mcgreal2007learning/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @mcgreal2007learning
McGreal, R., &amp;amp; Anderson, T. (2007). E-learning in Canada. International Journal of Distance Education Technologies (IJDET), 5(1), 1–6.
Notes Highlights A principal characteristic of the Canadian experience with e-learning is the uniquely Canadian feature of provincial jurisdiction over education. (p. 1)
Therefore, any investigation of e-learning in Canada must focus more on specific provincial initiatives in technologically enhanced learning rather than a Canadian overview. (p. 1)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sun. (2008). What drives a successful e-Learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-15-sun2008b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-15-sun2008b/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sun2008b
Sun, P.-C., Tsai, R. J., Finger, G., Chen, Y.-Y., &amp;amp; Yeh, D. (2008). What drives a successful e-Learning? An empirical investigation of the critical factors influencing learner satisfaction. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 50(4), 1183–1202. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2006.11.007
Notes Building on earlier research on e-learning, this study aims to build a model of learner satisfaction involving multiple dimensions including course, instructor, learner, tech, design, and environmental dimensions. The presentation of the study is succinct (as one could normally expect from the journal), in some cases too succinct to clarify doubts about the dataset (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>