<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collaborative learning on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/collaborative-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collaborative learning on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/collaborative-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Kennedy (2016) Open Annotation and Close Reading the Victorian Text: Using Hypothes.is with Students</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-03-kennedy2016-qw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-03-kennedy2016-qw/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Kennedy2016-qw
Meegan Kennedy (2016): Open Annotation and Close Readingthe Victorian Text: Using Hypothes.is with Students, Journal of Victorian Culture, DOI:10.1080&amp;frasl;13555502.2016.1233905
Notes Summarize: This commentary introduces an instructor&amp;rsquo;s thoughts and experiences in integrating Hyphthes.is, an open annotation tool, into an undergrad course.
Assess: Thorough intro to all kinds of considerations that would inform another instructor&amp;rsquo;s design efforts.
Reflect: I&amp;rsquo;m planning on using H in my SNA class, so this piece is very helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Su (2010) A Web 2.0-based collaborative annotation system for enhancing knowledge sharing</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-13-su2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-13-su2010/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Su2010
Su, A. Y. S., Yang, S. J. H., Hwang, W.-Y., &amp;amp; Zhang, J. (2010). A Web 2.0-based collaborative annotation system for enhancing knowledge sharing in collaborative learning environments. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 55(2), 752–766. doi:10.1016/j.compedu.2010.03.008
Notes An independent implementation of an interesting web annotation system. This paper focuses on evaluating students&amp;rsquo; acceptance of the system and how the use of web annotations have helped students learn.
The use of annotations in this study, and in many others, has been focused on knowledge sharing, especially in the process of consuming or making sense of shared readings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>