<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Literacies on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/literacies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literacies on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/literacies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ford-Connors2015-dd: Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond: Sources of Word Learning and Productive Contexts for Development</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-18-ford-connors2015-dd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-18-ford-connors2015-dd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ford-Connors2015-dd
Ford-Connors, E., &amp;amp; Paratore, J. R. (2015). Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond: Sources of Word Learning and Productive Contexts for Development. Review of Educational Research, 85(1), 50–91. https://doi.org/10.3102/0034654314540943
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Synthesizing the literature around the general topics of vocabu- lary instruction, classroom discourse, and teacher talk, this review provides a comprehensive and critical examination of instruction that supports vocab- ulary learning in older students with a particular focus on practices that promote productive discussions of content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Buckingham - 2010 - Defining digital literacy</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-27-buckingham2010-mc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-27-buckingham2010-mc/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Buckingham2010-mc
Buckingham, D. (2010). Defining digital literacy. In Medienbildung in neuen Kulturr{ä}umen (pp. 59–71). Springer.
Notes This chapter criticizes traditional emphasis on functional aspects of digital literacy and highlights four broad conceptual aspects that are generally regarded as essential components of media literacy (see Buckingham, 2003): representation, language, production, and audience. The author treats media not simply as tools but cultural forms and invite educators to recognize cultural practices related to new media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Tong - 2014 - A Randomized Study of a Literacy-Integrated Science Intervention</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-29-tong2014-tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-29-tong2014-tx/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Tong2014-tx
Tong, F., Irby, B. J., Lara-Alecio, R., Guerrero, C., Fan, Y., &amp;amp; Huerta, M. (2014). A Randomized Study of a Literacy-Integrated Science Intervention for Low-Socio-economic Status Middle School Students: Findings from first-year implementation. International Journal of Science Education, 36(12), 2083–2109.
Notes Highlights This paper presents the findings from a randomized control trial study of reading/literacy-integrated science inquiry intervention after 1 year of implementation and the treatment effect on 5th-grade low-socio-economic African-American and Hispanic students’ achievement in science and English reading.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>