<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Kucirkova. (2015). A Vygotskian perspective on parent-child talk during iPad story sharing</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-11-kucirkova2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-11-kucirkova2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Kucirkova2015
Kucirkova, N., Sheehy, K., &amp;amp; Messer, D. (2015). A Vygotskian perspective on parent-child talk during iPad story sharing. Journal of Research in Reading, 38(4), 428–441. doi:10.1111&amp;frasl;1467-9817.12030
Notes An interesting study exploring themes of interactions in parent-child talk during iPad story sharing/creation. The analysis was largely informed by Vygotsky’s learning theory focusing on ZPD, dual representation and double stimulation. While results offer insights about parent-child talk in an interesting story-creation iPad app (something less common in traditional storytelling reading research), this study also challenges the Vygotskian frame&amp;rsquo;s explanatory power in this novel context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: O’Hara, K., &amp; Sellen, A. (1997). A comparison of reading paper and on-line documents</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-18-ohara1997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-18-ohara1997/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @OHara1997
O’Hara, K., &amp;amp; Sellen, A. (1997). A comparison of reading paper and on-line documents. In Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on Human factors in computing systems - CHI ’97 (pp. 335–342). New York, New York, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;258549.258787
Notes Highlights The Literature (p. 1)
A fairly substantial body of literature comparing the reading of paper versus on-line documents can be found in the psychological, human factors, and ergonomics literature (see [4, 10] for comprehensive reviews).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>