<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science education on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/science-education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science education on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/science-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Improving conceptual change concerning photosynthesis through text design</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-06-07-mikkila-erdmann2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-06-07-mikkila-erdmann2001/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @mikkila-erdmann2001
Mikkilä-Erdmann, M. (2001). Improving conceptual change concerning photosynthesis through text design. Learning and Instruction, 11(3), 241–257. doi:10.1016/S0959-4752(00)00041-4
Notes Literature review * the simplest form of conceptual change: enrichment&amp;ndash;accumulation on the level of specific theory * revision: reorganization of knowledge on the level of the framework theory&amp;mdash;so more difficult and need specific instruction * problem: students are not aware the contradiction, so tend to enrich rather than revise them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Knowledge Building as a Mediator of Conflict in Conceptual Change</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-09-28-chan1997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-09-28-chan1997/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @chan1997
Chan, C. K. K., Burtis, J., &amp;amp; Bereiter, C. (1997). Knowledge Building as a Mediator of Conflict in Conceptual Change. Cognition and Instruction (Vol. 15, pp. 1–40). doi:10.1207/s1532690xci1501_1
Abstract This study examined how individuals and peers process scientific information that contradicts what they believe and assessed the contribution of this activity to conceptual change. Participants included 54 students in Grade 9 and 54 students in Grade 12, who were randomly assigned to four conditions: (a) individual conflict, (b) peer conflict, &amp;copy; individual assimilation, and (d) peer assimilation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lee2013-sl: Science and language for English language learners in relation to Next Generation Science Standards and with implications for Common Core State Standards for English language arts and mathematics</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2013-sl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2013-sl/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lee2013-sl
Lee, O., Quinn, H., &amp;amp; Valdés, G. (2013). Science and language for English language learners in relation to Next Generation Science Standards and with implications for Common Core State Standards for English language arts and mathematics. Educational Researcher , 42(4), 223–233. Retrieved from http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X13480524
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights By examining intersections between learning of science and learning of language, the article identifies key features of the language of the science classroom as students engage in these language-intensive science and engineering practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lee2017-xm: Common Core State Standards for ELA/Literacy and Next Generation Science Standards</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2017-xm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2017-xm/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lee2017-xm
Lee, O. (2017). Common Core State Standards for ELA/Literacy and Next Generation Science Standards: Convergences and Discrepancies Using Argument as an Example. Educational Researcher , 46(2), 90–102. Retrieved from http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X17699172
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Unlike pre-CCSS standards developed within each subject area, the new standards highlight connections across subject areas (Stage, Asturias, Cheuk, Daro, &amp;amp; Hampton, 2013). (p. 1)
While ELA is traditionally associated with literary texts, the CCSS emphasize informational texts (Pearson, 2013) (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Oshima. (2006). Knowledge-building activity structures in Japanese elementary science pedagogy</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-03-oshima2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-03-oshima2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Oshima2006
Oshima, J., Oshima, R., Murayama, I., Inagaki, S., Takenaka, M., Yamamoto, T., … Nakayama, H. (2006). Knowledge-building activity structures in Japanese elementary science pedagogy. International Journal of Computer-Supported Collaborative Learning, 1(2), 229–246. doi:10.1007/s11412-006-8995-8
Notes Efforts to introduce KB into Japanese elementary classrooms: created two practical design principles&amp;mdash;idea-centered lesson and collective knowledge advancement&amp;mdash;based on 12 KB principles. In two design studies, these two practical principles were integrated with Japanese science activity structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sengupta. (2015). Learning to Deflect: Conceptual Change in Physics During Digital Game Play</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-17-sengupta2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-17-sengupta2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sengupta2015
Sengupta, P., Krinks, K. D., &amp;amp; Clark, D. B. (2015). Learning to Deflect: Conceptual Change in Physics During Digital Game Play. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 24(4), 638–674. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;10508406.2015.1082912
Notes Highlights The current study presents a microgenetic analysis and case study of one student’s processes of knowledge construction as he played a conceptually integrated digital game (SURGE Next) designed to support learning about Newtonian mechanics. (p. 2)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Woodruff, E., &amp; Meyer, K. (1997). Explanations from intra- and inter-group discourse</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-28-woodruff1997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-28-woodruff1997/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Woodruff1997
Woodruff, E., &amp;amp; Meyer, K. (1997). Explanations from intra- and inter-group discourse: Students building knowledge in the science classroom. Research in Science Education, 27(1), 25–39. doi:10.1007/BF02463030
Notes An earlier paper on science education following the &amp;ldquo;progressive discourse&amp;rdquo; approach.
Highlights We have conducted three separate studies in science classrooms that implemented this approach within a science unit. Across the studies we have varied the grade level of the students (grade five, grade seven), varied the topic of inquiry (images and shadows, density), and documented &amp;ldquo;on-line&amp;rdquo; inquiry discourse within a computer software environment called CSILE, standing for Computer Supported Intentional Learning Environment (Scardamalia, Bereiter, McLean, Swallow, &amp;amp; Woodruff, 1989) that networked small groups of students in the grade five class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding students practical epistemologies and their influence on learning through inquiry</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-06-07-sandoval2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-06-07-sandoval2005/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @sandoval2005
Sandoval, W. A. (2005). Understanding students’ practical epistemologies and their influence on learning through inquiry. Science Education, 89(4), 634–656. doi:10.1002/sce.20065
Raw notes Page: 9 Page: 9 What the above studies and others show is that students at all age levels commonly have inarticulate ideas about the nature and role of scientiﬁc experimentation, and the relation between method and theory.
Page: 9 Methods of Science.
Page: 9 Although Deanna Kuhn has argued that most children, and even lay adults, fail to distinguish between theories and evidence (Kuhn, 1993; Kuhn et al.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>