<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data analysis on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/data-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data analysis on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sengupta. (2015). Learning to Deflect: Conceptual Change in Physics During Digital Game Play</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-17-sengupta2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-17-sengupta2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sengupta2015
Sengupta, P., Krinks, K. D., &amp;amp; Clark, D. B. (2015). Learning to Deflect: Conceptual Change in Physics During Digital Game Play. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 24(4), 638–674. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;10508406.2015.1082912
Notes Highlights The current study presents a microgenetic analysis and case study of one student’s processes of knowledge construction as he played a conceptually integrated digital game (SURGE Next) designed to support learning about Newtonian mechanics. (p. 2)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Thompson. (2013). Processing and Visualizing Data in Complex Learning Environments</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-01-thompson2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-01-thompson2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Thompson2013
Thompson, K., Ashe, D., Carvalho, L., Goodyear, P., Kelly, N., &amp;amp; Parisio, M. (2013). Processing and Visualizing Data in Complex Learning Environments. American Behavioral Scientist, 57(10), 1401–1420. doi:10.1177&amp;frasl;0002764213479368
Notes I like the proposed framework and model. But the presence of LA in Case 1 is especially minimal. Case 2 involves much human coding. Appears to be a more traditional CSCL research.
Highlights We discuss, using the cases of two learning environments, how structure affects the behavior of learners and, in turn, how that behavior has the potential to affect learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>