<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/featured/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Featured on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Annotation of Research Articles in Learning Sciences</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-12-08-jls-web-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-12-08-jls-web-annotation/</guid>
      <description>As a member of the Outreach Advisory Board of the Journal of the Learning Sciences (JLS), I was really glad to see the journal putting together a web annotation event during December 11-22, 2017. This activity is yet another move made by the editorial team to engage its readership on various social media venues.
Coming Soon: Web annotation of JLS articles in Hypothes.is.
The first article is a study by Akkerman and Bruining published in 2016 in Volume 25 (2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AERA-NSF Workshop: Data Sharing and Research Transparency (Part II)</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-27-data-sharing-workshop-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-27-data-sharing-workshop-2/</guid>
      <description>(Photo Credit: Zachary Veach)
Story continued, after Part I.
In the 2.5 days of the workshop, the group continued to deepen the discussion on Data Sharing to more concrete and practical items. In Part II of my personal reflection, I summarize key Data Sharing resources/initiatives to be aware of, possible action items, and some personal random thoughts on future directions.
The 3-day workshop on &amp;quot;Data Sharing and Research Transparency at the Article Publishing Stage&amp;quot; comes to a close today in D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Value and Valuation in Education</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-24-value-in-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-24-value-in-education/</guid>
      <description>In his arguments against the Common Core, Prof. Yong Zhao, a known educational thinker, referred to his home village:
 When I was growing up, the most valued talent was the ability to handle water buffalos used to plow the rice field, other than physical strengths to carry things such as newly harvested rice or sweet potatoes. I don’t know for sure how good a water buffalo handler she [Lady Gaga] could be, but I am quite sure she will not be able to run on bumpy muddy paths with 200 pounds of sweet potatoes dangling on each end of a bamboo pole.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>