<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network analysis on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/network-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network analysis on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/network-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Agneessens, F., &amp; Everett, M. G. (2013). Introduction to the special issue on advances in two-mode social networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-15-agneessens2013-wp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-15-agneessens2013-wp/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Agneessens2013-wp
Agneessens, F., &amp;amp; Everett, M. G. (2013). Introduction to the special issue on advances in two-mode social networks. Social Networks, 35(2), 145–147. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2013.03.002
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Two-mode data was collected by Davis et al. (1941) in theirclassic study on theparticipation of Southern women in social events and later by a variety of researchers studying interlocking directorates from the 1970s onwards (e.g., Stokman et al., 1985).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Barab. (2001). Constructing Networks of Action-Relevant Episodes: An In Situ Research Methodology</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-16-barab2001-jt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-16-barab2001-jt/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Barab2001-jt
Barab, S. A., Hay, K. E., &amp;amp; Yamagata-Lynch, L. C. (2001). Constructing Networks of Action-Relevant Episodes: An In Situ Research Methodology. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 10(1-2), 63–112. https://doi.org/10.1207/S15327809JLS10-1-2_5
Notes Summarize: This paper introduces a methodology that&amp;rsquo;s grounded in Activity Theory and situated cognition, and based on ethnographic approaches and network analysis. It offers a very thorough and useful exploration of the need for analysis of knowing &amp;lsquo;in situ&amp;rsquo;, compared with traditional analysis of learning results / knowledge products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Borgatti. (2012). Two-Mode Concepts in Social Network Analysis</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-27-borgatti2012-vh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-27-borgatti2012-vh/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Borgatti2012-vh
Borgatti, S. P. (2012). Social Network Analysis, Two-Mode Concepts in. In R. A. Meyers (Ed.), Computational Complexity (pp. 2912–2924). Springer New York. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4614-1800-9_179
Notes A great intro to two-mode SNA. Requires understanding of SNA basics.
Highlights In social network analysis, 2-mode data refers to data recording ties between two sets of entities. In this con- text, the term “mode” refers to a class of entities – typically called actors, nodes or vertices – whose members have so- cial ties with other members (in the 1-mode case) or with members of another class (in the 2-mode case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Carley. (2003). Dynamic network analysis</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-02-08-carley2003-zk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-02-08-carley2003-zk/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Carley2003-zk
Carley, K. M. (2003). Dynamic network analysis. In R. Breiger, K. Carley, &amp;amp; P. Pattison (Eds.), Dynamic Social Network Modeling and Analysis: Workshop Summary and Papers (pp. 133–145). Washington, DC: National Academies Press. Retrieved from http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.299.8946&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Clearly social network analysis can be applied to the study of covert networks (Sparrow, 1991). Many are stepping forward suggesting that to understand these networks we just need to “connect the dots” and then isolate the “key actors who are often defined in terms of their “centrality” in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Carley. (2012). Data-to-model: a mixed initiative approach for rapid ethnographic assessment</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-30-carley2012-xn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-30-carley2012-xn/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Carley2012-xn
Carley, K. M., Bigrigg, M. W., &amp;amp; Diallo, B. (2012). Data-to-model: a mixed initiative approach for rapid ethnographic assessment. Computational &amp;amp; Mathematical Organization Theory, 18(3), 300–327. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10588-012-9125-y
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Rapid ethnographic assessment is used when there is a need to quickly create a socio-cultural profile of a group or region. While there are many forms such an assessment can take, we view it as providing insight into who are the key actors, what are the key issues, sentiments, resources, activities and locations, how have these changed in recent times, and what roles do the various actors play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Malinick, T. E., Tindall, D. B., &amp; Diani, M. (2013). Network centrality and social movement media coverage</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-15-malinick2013-ub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-15-malinick2013-ub/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Malinick2013-ub
Malinick, T. E., Tindall, D. B., &amp;amp; Diani, M. (2013). Network centrality and social movement media coverage: A two-mode network analytic approach. Social Networks, 35(2), 148–158. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2011.10.005
Notes Summarize:
Reflect:
Highlights abstract This article examines the relationship between structural location (namely, degree centrality) and news media coverage. Our central hypothesis is that the network centrality of social movement actors is positively associated with the prevalence of actors being cited in the print news media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Morris, M. (2003). Local Rules and Global Properties: Modeling the Emergence of Network Structure</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-15-morris2003-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-15-morris2003-pc/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Morris2003-pc
Morris, M. (2003). Local Rules and Global Properties: Modeling the Emergence of Network Structure. In Dynamic Social Network Modeling and Analysis: Workshop Summary and Papers (pp. 174–186). National Academies Press. Retrieved from https://market.android.com/details?id=book-DOo-hq1-oF0C
Notes Summarize: This article argues for use of statistical modeling, esp. ERGM, in network analysis. It offers some useful analysis of the gap (~15 yrs ago) and proposes approaches to mitigating the gaps. Some important points include &amp;lsquo;model closes the gap between theory and data&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;traditional network analysis focuses on descriptives, for no apparent reasons&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Tutzauer, F. (2013). A Family of Affiliation Indices for Two-Mode Networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-15-tutzauer2013-oq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-15-tutzauer2013-oq/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Tutzauer2013-oq
Tutzauer, F. (2013). A Family of Affiliation Indices for Two-Mode Networks. Journal of Social and Biological Structures, 14, 1. Retrieved from https://www.cmu.edu/joss/content/articles/volume14/Tutzauer.pdf
Notes Summarize: This paper introduces affiliation index, a new measure to characterize affiliation in a two-mode network. As the author nicely argues, this index is two-mode in nature, compared to centrality measures which are one-mode in nature and often borrowed to analyze two-mode networks. The author also introduces a family of affiliation indices and significance tests based on its binomial distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Wagner, C. S., &amp; Leydesdorff, L. (2005). Network structure, self-organization, and the growth of international collaboration in science. Research Policy, 34(10), 1608–1618. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respol.2005.08.002 </title>
      <link>/notes/2017-08-31-wagner2005-ib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-08-31-wagner2005-ib/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Wagner2005-ib
Wagner, C. S., &amp;amp; Leydesdorff, L. (2005). Network structure, self-organization, and the growth of international collaboration in science. Research Policy, 34(10), 1608–1618. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respol.2005.08.002
Notes Summarize: Very interesting study of international collaboration using the sociological concept of preferential attachment to make an argument about the self-organizing feature of international collaboration (driven by all sorts of rewards). Two references regarding different types of collaborators highlighted near the end are also quite interesting and could apply to an analysis of an emerging, interdisciplinary area like learning analytics and MOOCs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Wang2016-lu-Modeling customer preferences using multidimensional network analysis in engineering design</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-12-wang2016-lu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-12-wang2016-lu/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Wang2016-lu
Wang, M., Chen, W., Huang, Y., Contractor, N. S., &amp;amp; Fu, Y. (2016). Modeling customer preferences using multidimensional network analysis in engineering design. Design Science, 2. https://doi.org/10.1017/dsj.2016.11
Notes Summarize: This paper presents a case of using multidimensional network analysis &amp;ndash; powered by ERGM &amp;ndash; to model customer preferences in China&amp;rsquo;s car market. Data were from user surveys. The authors patiently set the background, introduce the techniques, compared MNA with unidimensional network analysis, and considerately presented various analytical decisions associated with these approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Zhang2016-ps-Understanding the dynamics of MOOC discussion forums with simulation investigation for empirical network analysis (SIENA)</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-01-zhang2016-ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-01-zhang2016-ps/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Zhang2016-ps
Zhang, J., Skryabin, M., &amp;amp; Song, X. (2016). Understanding the dynamics of MOOC discussion forums with simulation investigation for empirical network analysis (SIENA). Distance Education, 37(3), 270–286. https://doi.org/10.1080/01587919.2016.1226230
Notes Interesting and well-grounded study of MOOC forums using SIENA. It adopts a hypothesis-testing paradigm. The discussion of the literation is extensive and useful. The findings could be further discussed. For example, I would like to see the authors&amp;rsquo; discussion of why reciprocity declined across the time periods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>