<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workflow on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/workflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workflow on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AERA-NSF Workshop: Data Sharing and Research Transparency (Part I)</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-25-data-sharing-workshop-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-25-data-sharing-workshop-1/</guid>
      <description>(Photo Credit: Roche et al. 2014)
It was an honor to be invited to attend the AERA-NSF Workshop on Data Sharing and Research Transparency at the Article Publishing Stage in Washington, D.C. during July 25‐27, 2017. I am attending as an early career scholar from the International Society of the Learning Sciences &amp;mdash; my academic home.
It&amp;rsquo;s only a half-day into the workshop but I&amp;rsquo;m already amazed by so many great thoughts from a full room of journal editors, program officers from funding agencies, and early career peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Workflow Part 2: Portability, Automation, and Openness</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-10-17-paperpile-workflow-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-10-17-paperpile-workflow-part-2/</guid>
      <description>(Photo Credit: Luke Addison)
Portable Annotations and Automation In the previous blog post, I explained key elements of my academic workflow: easy capturing of references, file storage on the cloud, portable annotations produced while reading, automation, and collaborative writing at one place. I made a screencast to share my workflow involving elements of capturing, storing, and collaborative writing in Google Docs.
In preparation for this post, I recorded another video focusing on elements related to portable annotations and the automation of piecing information together for later retrieval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Workflow with Paperpile: Part 1</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-09-22-paperpile-workflow-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-09-22-paperpile-workflow-part-1/</guid>
      <description>It was the beginning of this new school year when I started to &amp;ldquo;revamp&amp;rdquo; my academic workflow, which has been very digital since the dawn of my dissertation research. There are tons of articles you can find online about digital workflow for academics, e.g., this post, this one, this post involving LaTeX, etc. For me, there are a few essential things I want to achieve in my workflow:
 Capture: Easily capture references from the Web, including Google Scholar, journal webpages, and my university library, into my personal reference library.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>