<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Olinghouse2013-yd: The relationship between vocabulary and writing quality in three genres</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-20-olinghouse2013-yd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-20-olinghouse2013-yd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Olinghouse2013-yd
Olinghouse, N. G., &amp;amp; Wilson, J. (2013). The relationship between vocabulary and writing quality in three genres. Reading and Writing, 26(1), 45–65. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11145-012-9392-5
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Abstract The purpose of this study was to examine the role of vocabulary in writing across three genres. Fifth graders (N = 105) wrote three compositions: story, persuasive, and informative. Each composition revolved around the topic of outer space to control for background knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Graesser - 2011 - Coh-Metrix</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-17-graesser2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-17-graesser2011/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Graesser2011
Graesser, A. C., McNamara, D. S., &amp;amp; Kulikowich, J. M. (2011). Coh-Metrix: Providing Multilevel Analyses of Text Characteristics. Educational Researcher, 40(5), 223–234. doi:10.3102/0013189X11413260
Notes An overview of measures provided by Coh-Metrix.
Highlights Two important caveats must be raised before describing the computer analyses of text characteristics. First, computers obviously cannot identify and scale texts on all levels of language, discourse, and meaning. Available computer systems cannot fully comprehend the deep metaphors, literary devices, and historical contexts of Shakespeare’s plays, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Haneda, M., &amp; Wells, G. (2000). Writing in knowledge-building communities</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-26-haneda2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-26-haneda2000/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Haneda2000
Haneda, M., &amp;amp; Wells, G. (2000). Writing in knowledge-building communities. Research in the Teaching of English, 34(3), 430–457. Retrieved from http://www.jstor.org/stable/40171501
Notes This position piece articulates how writing is perceived and supported in knowledge building. It presents a thorough discussion of &amp;ldquo;current&amp;rdquo; understanding in writing, gaps in writing instruction, and the role Knowledge Building plays in writing (and roles writing plays in knowledge building). It also presents three examples of writing in knowledge building communities, in which roles of teachers and technology are explored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: The elements of style</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-09-strunk1918elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-09-strunk1918elements/</guid>
      <description>References Strunk Jr, W. (1918). The elements of style. New York: Penguin.
Citekey: @strunk1918elements
Notes A friend recommended this book to me as a useful guide for English writing. (Some of the advice might be dated though, since it was written a century ago.)
Highlights Chapter II ELEMENTARY RULES OF USAGE (p. 9) (1) Form the possessive singular of nouns with ’s (p. 9)
Charles’s friend (p. 9)
Exceptions are the possessives of ancient proper names in -es and -is, the possessive Jesus’, and such forms as for conscience’ sake, for righteousness’ sake.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>