<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game-based learning on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/game-based-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game-based learning on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/game-based-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: FARMTASIA: an online game-based learning environment based on the VISOLE pedagogy</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-05-25-cheung2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-05-25-cheung2008/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @cheung2008
Cheung, K. K. F., Jong, M. S. Y., Lee, F. L., Lee, J. H. M., Luk, E. T. H., Shang, J., &amp;amp; Wong, M. K. H. (2008). FARMTASIA: an online game-based learning environment based on the VISOLE pedagogy. Virtual Reality, 12(1), 17–25. doi:10.1007/s10055-008-0084-z
Clippings Virtual interactive student-oriented learning environment (VISOLE) is a game-based constructivist pedagogical approach that encompasses the creation of an online interactive world modeled upon a set of interdisciplinary domains, in which students participate as ‘‘citizens’’ to take part cooperatively and competitively in shaping the development of the virtual world as a means to construct their knowledge and skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Game-like learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-05-25-gee2008game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-05-25-gee2008game/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @gee2008game
Gee, J. P. (2008). Game-like learning: An example of situated learning and implications for opportunity to learn. Assessment, equity, and opportunity to learn, 200–221.
Clippings Game-Like Learning (p. 1)
knowledge: as noun and verb (p. 1)
The theory of learning in many schools today is based on what I would call the “content fetish” (Gee 2004). The content fetish is the view that any academic area (whether physics, sociology, or history) is composed of a set of facts or a body of information and that the way learning should work is through teaching and testing such facts and information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Gee Melbourne talk</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-05-26-gee-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-05-26-gee-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @gee-melbourne
Link: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=17JvW0nnr48&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded
Notes the exciting combination of consumption and creation
 all video games are rule systems about shapes, movements, and combinations. but what would happen if I gave each shape, movement, and combination of shapes in Tetris a meaning? story elements: actors, actions; states, events grammar  games as literacy * what&amp;rsquo;s the role of story in games? * Casovilia: story doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. * The primary thing here is the player&amp;rsquo;s production of story elements, not a story per se (like Alucard kills a Sword Lord).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: What video games have to teach us about learning and literacy</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-05-26-gee2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-05-26-gee2003/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @gee2003
Gee, J. P. (2003). What video games have to teach us about learning and literacy. Computers in Entertainment, 1(1), 20. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;950566.950595
Clippings Thus, designers face and largely solve an intriguing educational dilemma, one also faced by schools and workplaces: how to get people, often young people, to learn and master something that is long and challenging—and enjoy it, to boot. (p. 1)
I argue that schools, workplaces, families, and academic researchers have a lot to learn about learning from good computer and video games.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>