<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Temporality on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/temporality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Temporality on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/temporality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining frequent sequences in knowledge building dialogues</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-05-02-mining-frequent-sequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-05-02-mining-frequent-sequences/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I highlighted the significance of studying temporality in collaborative learning and argued it should be studied more widely in learning sciences research because temporality matters for learning in a socio-cultural context. In the specific study I presented at LAK14, an analytic technique named Lag-sequential Analysis (LsA) was applied to investigate sequential patterns among six contribution types in knowledge building dialogues by elementary school students. Such analysis was able to uncover temporal patterns that were otherwise undiscoverable using a traditional &amp;ldquo;coding-and-counting&amp;rdquo; technique, which is widely applied in many learning sciences studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining frequent sequences in knowledge building dialogues</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-05-02-mining-frequent-sequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-05-02-mining-frequent-sequences/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I highlighted the significance of studying temporality in collaborative learning and argued it should be studied more widely in learning sciences research because temporality matters for learning in a socio-cultural context. In the specific study I presented at LAK14, an analytic technique named Lag-sequential Analysis (LsA) was applied to investigate sequential patterns among six contribution types in knowledge building dialogues by elementary school students. Such analysis was able to uncover temporal patterns that were otherwise undiscoverable using a traditional &amp;ldquo;coding-and-counting&amp;rdquo; technique, which is widely applied in many learning sciences studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The taste of time: Temporality in students&#39; explanation building dialogues</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-04-17-temporailty-in-dialogues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-04-17-temporailty-in-dialogues/</guid>
      <description>Things unfold over time. One thing I remember from my high school history lessons is that a particular historical event, e.g., a war, could be triggered by one single incident, but might also be already predetermined by a broader historical context. In the time dimension, various factors come into play, interact with each other, and frame historical events. So interpretation of any event needs to take various factors and players involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Bannert - 2014 - Process mining techniques for analysing patterns and strategies in students’ self-regulated learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-04-01-bannert2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-04-01-bannert2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Bannert2014
Bannert, M., Reimann, P., &amp;amp; Sonnenberg, C. (2014). Process mining techniques for analysing patterns and strategies in students’ self-regulated learning. Metacognition and Learning, 9, 161–185. doi:10.1007/s11409-013-9107-6
Notes A nice article applying Process Mining (PM) on the study of self-regulated learning. Starting from discussing the importance of studying temporal and sequential information in self-regulated learning, this article moves on to introduce the key ideas of PM. Then it illustrates the application of PM, using a software called ProM v5, to study a group of students&amp;rsquo; learning in a hypermedia environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Clustering and sequential pattern mining of online collaborative learning data</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-04-30-perera2009clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-04-30-perera2009clustering/</guid>
      <description>References Perera, D., Kay, J., Koprinska, I., Yacef, K., &amp;amp; Zaïane, O. R. (2009). Clustering and sequential pattern mining of online collaborative learning data. Knowledge and Data Engineering, IEEE Transactions on, 21(6), 759–772.
Citekey: @perera2009clustering
Notes Highlights mirroring (p. 2)
To underpin our work, we have used the Big Five theory of group work [1]. (p. 3)
It has established five key factors: leadership, mutual performance monitoring, backup behaviour, adaptability and team orientation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Identifying Learning Behaviors by Contextualizing Differential Sequence Mining with Action Features and Performance Evolution</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-04-30-kinnebrew2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-04-30-kinnebrew2012/</guid>
      <description>References Kinnebrew, J., &amp;amp; Biswas, G. (2012). Identifying Learning Behaviors by Contextualizing Differential Sequence Mining with Action Features and Performance Evolution. In the 5th International Conference on Educational Data Mining (pp. 57–64). Retrieved from http://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED537192.pdf
Citekey: @Kinnebrew2012
Highlights The core algorithm employs sequence mining techniques to identify differentially frequent patterns between two predefined groups. (p. 1)
In developing a computer-based learning environment (CBLE) called Betty’s Brain, we have adopted a self-regulated learning (SRL) framework to help students develop learning strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>