<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Annotation of Research Articles in Learning Sciences</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-12-08-jls-web-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-12-08-jls-web-annotation/</guid>
      <description>As a member of the Outreach Advisory Board of the Journal of the Learning Sciences (JLS), I was really glad to see the journal putting together a web annotation event during December 11-22, 2017. This activity is yet another move made by the editorial team to engage its readership on various social media venues.
Coming Soon: Web annotation of JLS articles in Hypothes.is.
The first article is a study by Akkerman and Bruining published in 2016 in Volume 25 (2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forest</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-10-13-at-what-price/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-10-13-at-what-price/</guid>
      <description>(Photo Credit: Wikipedia)
The universe is expanding, but at what price.
The Milky Way is a beauty, but at what price.
The Sun is shining, but at what price.
The Earth looks blue, but at what price.
All continents are moving, but at what price.
Civilizations boom, but at what price.
A wall defends &amp;lsquo;us&amp;rsquo;, but at what price.
Pyramids are built tall, but at what price.
Boats cross the ocean, but at what price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AERA-NSF Workshop: Data Sharing and Research Transparency (Part II)</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-27-data-sharing-workshop-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-27-data-sharing-workshop-2/</guid>
      <description>(Photo Credit: Zachary Veach)
Story continued, after Part I.
In the 2.5 days of the workshop, the group continued to deepen the discussion on Data Sharing to more concrete and practical items. In Part II of my personal reflection, I summarize key Data Sharing resources/initiatives to be aware of, possible action items, and some personal random thoughts on future directions.
The 3-day workshop on &amp;quot;Data Sharing and Research Transparency at the Article Publishing Stage&amp;quot; comes to a close today in D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AERA-NSF Workshop: Data Sharing and Research Transparency (Part I)</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-25-data-sharing-workshop-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-25-data-sharing-workshop-1/</guid>
      <description>(Photo Credit: Roche et al. 2014)
It was an honor to be invited to attend the AERA-NSF Workshop on Data Sharing and Research Transparency at the Article Publishing Stage in Washington, D.C. during July 25‐27, 2017. I am attending as an early career scholar from the International Society of the Learning Sciences &amp;mdash; my academic home.
It&amp;rsquo;s only a half-day into the workshop but I&amp;rsquo;m already amazed by so many great thoughts from a full room of journal editors, program officers from funding agencies, and early career peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Value and Valuation in Education</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-24-value-in-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-24-value-in-education/</guid>
      <description>In his arguments against the Common Core, Prof. Yong Zhao, a known educational thinker, referred to his home village:
 When I was growing up, the most valued talent was the ability to handle water buffalos used to plow the rice field, other than physical strengths to carry things such as newly harvested rice or sweet potatoes. I don’t know for sure how good a water buffalo handler she [Lady Gaga] could be, but I am quite sure she will not be able to run on bumpy muddy paths with 200 pounds of sweet potatoes dangling on each end of a bamboo pole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphing the Reddit Place Sensation with Neo4j</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-04-10-graphing-reddit-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-04-10-graphing-reddit-place/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ver never liked the April Fool&amp;rsquo;s Day, until this year when Reddit decided to launch a social experiment called Reddit Place.
The idea is simple. The whole world &amp;ndash; or all Reddit users &amp;ndash; were given a 999 x 999 blank canvas to draw on. Some simple rules apply:
 Each user could choose one pixel from 16 colors to place anywhere on the canvas. They could place as many pixels of as many colors as they wanted, but they had to wait a few minutes between placing each one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A biased introduction to Learning Analytics: Kicking-off #UMNLACoP</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-03-23-umn-lacop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-03-23-umn-lacop/</guid>
      <description>(Photo Credit: Blue Diamond Gallery)
Today, we kicked off our Learning Analytics Community of Practice at UMN (#UMNLACoP)! Launching this CoP has been a joint effort among the Center for Educational Innovation, the College of Liberal Arts, the Libraries, and the College of Education and Human Development.
During today&amp;rsquo;s kick-off event, I spent 15 minutes presenting a quick introduction to the field of Learning Analytics. Below is an audio recording of my presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windchill, and Validity in Learning Analytics</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-11-14-windchill-learning-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-11-14-windchill-learning-analytics/</guid>
      <description>(Photo Credit: Dustin Gaffke)
Windchill I was listening to a science radio program the other (other) night when the host was talking about &amp;lsquo;windchill being inaccurate,&amp;rsquo; even though many of us have never questioned its accuracy at all. Scientific American has published an article on the same topic, saying:
 Wind chill is a mathematically derived number that approximates how cold your skin feels&amp;mdash;not how cold your skin actually is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MOOCs, Open Universities, and Learning Analytics in Asia</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-11-03-trip-to-asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-11-03-trip-to-asia/</guid>
      <description>My October ended with a trip to Asia &amp;ndash; Beijing and Manila this time. Visiting Beijing was like going back to an ever-changing hometown, while visiting Manila (where I&amp;rsquo;ve never been before) was like venturing into a rain forest. Both very exciting!
MOOCs in China: Research and Practice Three days in Beijing was filled by a busy MOOC conference agenda, working meetings at the X-Learning Center on a MOOC project, and casual exchanges with graduate students at the Graduate School of Education at Peking University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Workflow Part 2: Portability, Automation, and Openness</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-10-17-paperpile-workflow-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-10-17-paperpile-workflow-part-2/</guid>
      <description>(Photo Credit: Luke Addison)
Portable Annotations and Automation In the previous blog post, I explained key elements of my academic workflow: easy capturing of references, file storage on the cloud, portable annotations produced while reading, automation, and collaborative writing at one place. I made a screencast to share my workflow involving elements of capturing, storing, and collaborative writing in Google Docs.
In preparation for this post, I recorded another video focusing on elements related to portable annotations and the automation of piecing information together for later retrieval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Workflow with Paperpile: Part 1</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-09-22-paperpile-workflow-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-09-22-paperpile-workflow-part-1/</guid>
      <description>It was the beginning of this new school year when I started to &amp;ldquo;revamp&amp;rdquo; my academic workflow, which has been very digital since the dawn of my dissertation research. There are tons of articles you can find online about digital workflow for academics, e.g., this post, this one, this post involving LaTeX, etc. For me, there are a few essential things I want to achieve in my workflow:
 Capture: Easily capture references from the Web, including Google Scholar, journal webpages, and my university library, into my personal reference library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Tensions in the Field of Learning Analytics</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-05-20-learning-analytics-tensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-05-20-learning-analytics-tensions/</guid>
      <description>As the second iteration of my Learning Analytics course concludes at UMN, I thought it might be a good time to reflect on various issues we&amp;rsquo;ve explored in this course and I&amp;rsquo;ve been personally reflecting on.
Learning analytics is an emerging, highly interdisciplinary field where many disciplines&amp;ndash;such as education, computer science, and engineering&amp;ndash;intersect. Since its first significant scholarly gathering in 2011, learning analytics has been increasingly mentioned in news, technical reports, academic publications, and grant solicitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CanvasNet: Formative feedback for &#39;social learning&#39; on Canvas</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-11-19-canvasnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-11-19-canvasnet/</guid>
      <description>I have been teaching an undergraduate course using Canvas this semester. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how it happened because I&amp;rsquo;m essentially a disbeliever in Learning Management Systems (LMS). I believe one&amp;rsquo;s learning should not be managed. &amp;ldquo;LMS is the minivan of Education,&amp;rdquo; says Phil Hill. Even better, &amp;ldquo;the LMS is more like a bus than a minivan - someone else is driving, it only travels on a pre-arranged route, the bus is often late but you still have to be on time because it won&amp;rsquo;t wait if you miss it&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; says Stephen Downes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching in My First Semester</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-08-17-teaching-first-semester/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-08-17-teaching-first-semester/</guid>
      <description>Teaching was a thing that I was least sure about when taking on my position at The U. People talk about how little training on grant writing one gets as a PhD student. For me, teaching was probably more neglected while doing my PhD.
Fortunately I was not short of ideas for teaching because I had encountered so many great teachers in my life and I happen to also research teaching and learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A &#39;Round&#39; Trip</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-06-21-a-round-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-06-21-a-round-trip/</guid>
      <description>It has been a while since my last post, thanks to the &amp;ldquo;madness&amp;rdquo; of travel and other affairs near the end of my first semester at The U. From March, I attended LAK in Poughkeepsie NY, AERA in Chicago, an educational discourse workshop in Ann Arbor, and CSCL in Gothenburg, Sweden. Before CSCL, I visited several cities in China, including Beijing where I talked with a group of talented grad students at Peking University and chatted in length with a colleague at Beijing Normal University; after CSCL, I visited a colleague &amp;amp; friend in Oslo and enjoyed a wonderful &amp;ldquo;Norway in a Nutshell&amp;rdquo; fjord trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining frequent sequences in knowledge building dialogues</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-05-02-mining-frequent-sequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-05-02-mining-frequent-sequences/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I highlighted the significance of studying temporality in collaborative learning and argued it should be studied more widely in learning sciences research because temporality matters for learning in a socio-cultural context. In the specific study I presented at LAK14, an analytic technique named Lag-sequential Analysis (LsA) was applied to investigate sequential patterns among six contribution types in knowledge building dialogues by elementary school students. Such analysis was able to uncover temporal patterns that were otherwise undiscoverable using a traditional &amp;ldquo;coding-and-counting&amp;rdquo; technique, which is widely applied in many learning sciences studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards A Longitudinal Understanding of the Growth of Productive Vocabulary in Knowledge Building</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-02-04-longitudinal-productive-vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-02-04-longitudinal-productive-vocabulary/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;My theory is that it&amp;rsquo;s all about gravity. The groundwater stays down by gravity!&amp;rdquo; (Grade one, Water unit)
&amp;ldquo;Because the plane is so big and heavy it is hard to reduce gravity because gravity can be taken away better if there are lighter, stronger materials.&amp;rdquo; (Grade two, Flight unit)
&amp;ldquo;How does gravity work? Is it a force in the ground that pulls you down or something in the air that pushes you down?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Course: Learning Analytics in the Knowledge Age</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-01-27-learning-analytics-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-01-27-learning-analytics-course/</guid>
      <description>There has been tons of learning going on for me after moving to Minnesota two months ago: getting used to the imperial unit system; finding out it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to purchase alcohol on Sundays; realizing we need to &amp;ldquo;import&amp;rdquo; our car; people actually can fly kites on lakes; and, of course, people don&amp;rsquo;t have the accent as in the movie Fargo :)&amp;hellip; It has been an amazing experience so far to get accustomed to MPLS (I am not saying &amp;ldquo;Twin Cities&amp;rdquo; because local Minnesotans prefer MPLS &amp;ndash; another lesson learned).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Archeology of the Learning Analytics Community</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-10-14-twitter-archeology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-10-14-twitter-archeology/</guid>
      <description>Learning analytics as a nascent field of scholarship is evolving rapidly and garnering broad interest in both educational research and practice. Since the inaugural Learning Analytics and Knowledge (LAK) conference in 2011, exciting moves have been made during the past four years. The Society of Learning Analytics Research (SoLAR) was launched in 2012; the Learning Analytics Summer Institute (LASI) was first held in 2013; the first issue of the Journal of Learning Analytics was published in 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Forum API: A demo</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-06-06-knowledge-forum-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-06-06-knowledge-forum-api/</guid>
      <description>Knowledge Forum (KF) has been recognized as the founding software in the computer-supported collaborative learning (CSCL) community. And it was also one of the earliest to offer embedded analytic tools for formative assessment. Thanks to contributions from a broad international community, a number of analytic tools have been developed for KF, including a suite of embedded applets (e.g., Contributions, Social Networks, Semantic Overlap, Vocabulary Growth, and Lexical Analysis; see Teplovs et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining frequent sequences in knowledge building dialogues</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-05-02-mining-frequent-sequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-05-02-mining-frequent-sequences/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I highlighted the significance of studying temporality in collaborative learning and argued it should be studied more widely in learning sciences research because temporality matters for learning in a socio-cultural context. In the specific study I presented at LAK14, an analytic technique named Lag-sequential Analysis (LsA) was applied to investigate sequential patterns among six contribution types in knowledge building dialogues by elementary school students. Such analysis was able to uncover temporal patterns that were otherwise undiscoverable using a traditional &amp;ldquo;coding-and-counting&amp;rdquo; technique, which is widely applied in many learning sciences studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the quality of Finland&#39;s education system can exceed the quality of its teachers?</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-04-20-finland-education-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-04-20-finland-education-system/</guid>
      <description>Assessing one single student is not easy, not to mention an education system. Yet, OECD has been running a Programme for International Student Assessment (PISA) since 2000 to evaluate education systems by testing the skills and knowledge of 15-year-olds around the world.
Because of its superb performance in PISA since 2000, Finland&amp;rsquo;s education system has been celebrated worldwide. It had been holding the top spot in PISA&amp;rsquo;s overall ranking for years, attracting other countries to study and imitate its model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The taste of time: Temporality in students&#39; explanation building dialogues</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-04-17-temporailty-in-dialogues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-04-17-temporailty-in-dialogues/</guid>
      <description>Things unfold over time. One thing I remember from my high school history lessons is that a particular historical event, e.g., a war, could be triggered by one single incident, but might also be already predetermined by a broader historical context. In the time dimension, various factors come into play, interact with each other, and frame historical events. So interpretation of any event needs to take various factors and players involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital learning in Ontario schools: A &#39;new normal&#39;</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-03-31-digital-learning-in-ontario-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-03-31-digital-learning-in-ontario-schools/</guid>
      <description>Supported by a Mitacs fellowship, I have been working with a Toronto-based non-profit organization, People for Education (P4E), to investigate digital learning in Ontario public schools since October 2013. 
Today, a report about digital learning in Ontario schools has been officially released. Although there have been studies of digital learning in the Canadian context, this topic has not been system-wise inspected. This report draws on a rich set of data coming from P4E&amp;rsquo;s annual principal questionnaire participated by 28% of Ontario public schools, as well as student demographics and questionnaire data from Ontario&amp;rsquo;s Education Quality and Accountability Office (EQAO).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic job search: A reading list</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-03-10-academic-job-search-a-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-03-10-academic-job-search-a-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>When a friend requested me to share some tips on academic job search, I realized it was the time to reflect on this unique journey of myself, or at least to organize a reading list that has inspired my own search. So here we go, a personal, and possibly biased, reading list about academic job search. Enjoy!
General  The Ones We Didn&amp;rsquo;t Hire Academic job hunt advice: Tips for searching for and landing a professorship Volatile and Decentralized: How to get a faculty job, Part 1: The application Volatile and Decentralized: How to get a faculty job, part 1b: How to get an interview Volatile and Decentralized: How to get a faculty job, Part 2: The interview Volatile and Decentralized: How to get a faculty job, Part 3: Negotiating the offer The Six Ways You’re Acting Like a Grad Student  Application materials  Sample CVs | Society for Research in Child Development SRCD | for development Samples for Academic Positions | UCSF Office of Career &amp;amp; Professional Devel Sell your research in writing Writing a Research Plan | Science Careers Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB &#43; Java &#43; R = A handy toolbox for archiving and analyzing Twitter data</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-12-09-mongodb-java-r-a-handy-toolbox-for-archiving-and-analyzing-twitter-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-12-09-mongodb-java-r-a-handy-toolbox-for-archiving-and-analyzing-twitter-data/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Martin Hawksey&amp;rsquo;s brilliant Google Spreadsheet TAGS for archiving Twitter data for y-e-a-r-s. It works very well, and allowed me to develop little R toys like twitterytics-shiny to interactively explore Twitter archives.
However, I have a few complains. First, Twitter API authentication needs to be set up for each archive. The task which require a few steps in Google Spreadsheet is not trivial. Second, I often ended up getting hundreds or even thousands of duplicates that may cause the file size to exceed Google Spreadsheet&amp;rsquo;s size limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Links from the MOOC Research Conference Twitter Backchannel (#MRI13)</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-12-09-top-links-from-the-mooc-research-conference-twitter-backchannel-mri13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-12-09-top-links-from-the-mooc-research-conference-twitter-backchannel-mri13/</guid>
      <description>The MOOC Research Conference has just taken place at University of Texas, Arlington, December 5-6, 2013. I was fortunate to be on board of one research project &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Hatch, Match, and Dispatch: Examining the relationship between student intent, expectations, behaviours and outcomes in six Coursera MOOCs at the University of Toronto&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; which was among the 20+ MRI projects participating in this MOOC Research Conference. Chris Teplovs, Stian Håklev and Laurie Harrison from our team attended the conference in person, and they were surprised by an Icepocalyse in that area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make CORDTRA Diagrams with R</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-07-01-make-cordtra-diagrams-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-07-01-make-cordtra-diagrams-with-r/</guid>
      <description>CORDTRA (Chronologically-Ordered Representation of Discourse and Tool-Related Activity) is a visualization technique proposed by Cindy Hmelo-Silver (2003) for interpreting collaborative learning processes, based on Luckin et al.&amp;rsquo;s CORDFU (Chronologically-Ordered Representation of Discourse and Features Used). This technique could provide a holistic view of learning processes by making temporal relationship among various types of learning activities visible. By presenting a few interesting case studies, Hmelo-Silver and colleagues (2003, 2008) demonstrate that CORDTRA could provide useful insights about student interactions in computer-supported collaborative learning (CSCL).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Modeling and Visualization of Knowledge Forum Discussion</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-07-01-topic-modeling-and-visualization-of-knowledge-forum-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-07-01-topic-modeling-and-visualization-of-knowledge-forum-discussion/</guid>
      <description>In an earlier blog post I played with the idea of visualizing Knowledge Forum discourse in a 2D space, to support one specific perspective of community knowledge focusing on semantic similarity/distance among contributions. I used Latent Semantic Analysis (LSA) for similarity computation and Multidimensional scaling (MDS) for dimensionality reduction. The results was interesting, with notes around a same topic generally clustered together. However, as one colleague pointed out in a comment, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to interpret topics around different clusters and it would be nice if it&amp;rsquo;s possible to inspect clusters and somehow label them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#CSCL2013 pre-conference workshop: Measuring Collaborative Thinking Using Epistemic Network Analysis</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-06-15-cscl2013-pre-conference-workshop-measuring-collaborative-thinking-using-epistemic-network-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-06-15-cscl2013-pre-conference-workshop-measuring-collaborative-thinking-using-epistemic-network-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;ve participated in a wonderful full-day workshop about Epistemic Network Analysis (ENA), which I had been wishing to learn for a long time. David and Gol did a great job explaining its theoretical background, walking through a bunch of mathematical computation behind it, and doing some interesting demos with some real data from their research project. I had a great time playing with the sample data with my &amp;ldquo;teammate&amp;rdquo; Alisa, and will definitely apply it on some Knowledge Forum data in the near future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KNAER Data Visualization Workshop</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-04-03-knaer-data-visualization-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-04-03-knaer-data-visualization-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Today I was attending a data visualization workshop organized by the KNAER Data Visualization project in collaboration with AERO. I was one of the presenters, including Paul Anisef, Rob Brown, Chris Conley and Cosmin Marmureanu. It was the first time I met with them in person although we have been working together for a few months already on data visualization.
The workshop went quite well, with around 60 participants mostly from school boards and the ministry of education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyze Text Similarity with R: Latent Semantic Analysis and Multidimentional Scaling</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-03-11-analyze-text-similarity-in-r-latent-semantic-analysis-and-multidimentional-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-03-11-analyze-text-similarity-in-r-latent-semantic-analysis-and-multidimentional-scaling/</guid>
      <description>Background One of the most pressing questions I have been pondering upon when redesigning Knowledge Forum is how to represent the knowledge space of a community to better support idea improvement. Many people think Knowledge Forum as another discussion forum (or learning management system) with a 2-D interface (see below). This notion lead people to treat a Knowledge Forum view merely as a container of notes. The reason why this happens is because users usually fail to recognize one important principle behind the design of Knowledge Forum view: to support multiple perspectives of community knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo of Using twitter-hashtag-analytics to Analyze Tweets from #LAK13</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-02-26-demo-of-using-twitter-hashtag-analytics-package-to-analyze-tweets-from-lak13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-02-26-demo-of-using-twitter-hashtag-analytics-package-to-analyze-tweets-from-lak13/</guid>
      <description>Building on Ben Marwick, Martin Hawksey and Tony Hirst&amp;rsquo;s work on analyzing tweets with R, I started an R project for tweet analysis, namely twitter-hashtag-analytics. This project is hosted on Github and welcomes anyone who&amp;rsquo;s interested to contribute. It is my very first attempt to write a package in R, so I admit the capabilities of it is still limited and its structure may be not properly planned. Any advice will be highly appreciated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Overview&#34; of #AERA2012 Tweets</title>
      <link>/blog/2012-04-16-overview-of-aera2012-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012-04-16-overview-of-aera2012-tweets/</guid>
      <description>The AERA Annual Meeting is probably the largest getting-together of educational researchers and practitioners around the world. This year it has around 13,000 participants. Several hundreds of them are taking advantage of Twitter as a &#34;backchannel&#34; for communication at this conference. On Twitter, hashtags are usually used to easily aggregate tweets of a same topic together. This year, three hashtags, i.e. #AERA2012, #AERA, and #AERA12, are used, and #AERA2012 is the most popular one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promisingness Judgments by Grade 3s</title>
      <link>/blog/2011-09-16-promisingness-judgments-by-grade-3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011-09-16-promisingness-judgments-by-grade-3s/</guid>
      <description>I started working on a tool called &#34;Promising Ideas tool,&#34; firstly named as &#34;Big Ideas tool,&#34; one and a half years ago. It is an add-on to Knowledge Forum (KF), a knowledge-building environment used in many kinds of settings but mostly in primary schools. The Promising Ideas tool is really simple in terms of functionality. It looks like a lite and KF-confined version of Diigo or SparTag.us, which are both used for people to tag important information on the Web and leave traces for later-comers for better browsing heuristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The meaning of promisingness</title>
      <link>/blog/2011-05-25-meaning-of-promisingness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011-05-25-meaning-of-promisingness/</guid>
      <description>Although I have been using the word “promisingness” in my writing and conversations since last year, I am still not 100% percent sure about the meaning of it. When we discuss this concept with primary school teachers, they also found it not easy to grasp, let alone young kids (however, we are teaching this concept to grade 3s). This situation is not surprising because promisingness is not even recognized as a word in many popular dictionaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Knowledge Building with Open Educational Resources</title>
      <link>/blog/2010-12-24-integrate-knowledge-building-with-learning-in-open-educational-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2010-12-24-integrate-knowledge-building-with-learning-in-open-educational-resources/</guid>
      <description>Open Educational Resources Inspired by the MIT OpenCourseWare (OCW) which was launched in 2002, the open educational resources (OER) movement, which strives to “champion the sharing of knowledge worldwide to increase human intellectual capacity,” has rapidly expanded throughout the world and is becoming increasingly powerful in the era of knowledge creation and lifelong learning. Most OER projects to date have been concentrated on making quality educational content openly and freely accessible on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking on the altered side</title>
      <link>/blog/2010-03-09-walking-on-the-altered-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2010-03-09-walking-on-the-altered-side/</guid>
      <description>About forty years ago, Dr. James Finn gave a speech entitled &amp;ldquo;A Walk on the Altered Side&amp;rdquo; talking about an undergoing revolution in education powered by cutting edge technologies at that time, technologies that were best represented by computers. He opened up his discussion by quoting J. Robert Oppenheimer&amp;rsquo;s words,
 &amp;ldquo;One thing that is new is the prevalence of newness, the changing scale and scope of change itself, so that the world alters as we walk in it, so that the years of man’s life measure not some small growth or rearrangement or moderation of what he learned in childhood, but a great upheaval.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>