<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advanced SNA on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/advanced-sna/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advanced SNA on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/advanced-sna/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Contractor et al. (2011). Multidimensional networks and the dynamics of sociomateriality</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-12-contractor2011-vc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-12-contractor2011-vc/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Contractor2011-vc
Contractor, N., Monge, P., &amp;amp; Leonardi, P. M. (2011). Multidimensional networks and the dynamics of sociomateriality: bringing technology inside the network. International Journal of Communication Systems, 5, 39. Retrieved from http://ijoc.org/index.php/ijoc/article/view/1131
Notes Summarize: Fascinating work on multidimensional networks&amp;mdash;multi-mode, multi-plex, dynamic networks (akin to Carley&amp;rsquo;s dynamic network analysis). This paper starts by talking about sociomateriality&amp;mdash;arguing that tech and human are inseparable, so they should be kept in a same network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Contractor, N. (2009). The Emergence of Multidimensional Networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-12-contractor2009-sv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-12-contractor2009-sv/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Contractor2009-sv
Contractor, N. (2009). The Emergence of Multidimensional Networks. Journal of Computer-Mediated Communication: JCMC, 14(3), 743–747. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1083-6101.2009.01465.x
Notes Summarize: This short essay makes some really great points about the emergence of multidimentinoal networks (multimode, multiplex) in the context of Internet evolution.
Highlights Yet there are some success stories that suggest the need to understand the social factors that shape the use of technologies to create and sustain organizational, interorganizational, and community knowledge networks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>