<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sna on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/sna/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sna on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sna/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lungeanu &amp; Contractor. (2015). The effects of diversity and network ties on innovations</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-14-lungeanu2015-mb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-14-lungeanu2015-mb/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lungeanu2015-mb
Lungeanu, A., &amp;amp; Contractor, N. S. (2015). The effects of diversity and network ties on innovations: The emergence of a new scientific field. The American Behavioral Scientist, 59(5), 548–564. https://doi.org/10.1177/0002764214556804
Notes Summarize: Very interesting study investigating factors impacting (reflected in) coauthorship relations in a new field. SIENA was used for the modeling of network dynamics. Key finding:
 Taken together with net findings about cognitive dissimilarity, this study suggests that innovation in networked research is most likely when teams draw on individuals with diverse knowledge resources, but who also have prior collaborations with each other or with common others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Contractor, N. (2009). The Emergence of Multidimensional Networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-12-contractor2009-sv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-12-contractor2009-sv/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Contractor2009-sv
Contractor, N. (2009). The Emergence of Multidimensional Networks. Journal of Computer-Mediated Communication: JCMC, 14(3), 743–747. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1083-6101.2009.01465.x
Notes Summarize: This short essay makes some really great points about the emergence of multidimentinoal networks (multimode, multiplex) in the context of Internet evolution.
Highlights Yet there are some success stories that suggest the need to understand the social factors that shape the use of technologies to create and sustain organizational, interorganizational, and community knowledge networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Vaquero, L. M., &amp; Cebrian, M. (2013). The rich club phenomenon in the classroom</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-27-vaquero2013-ld/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-27-vaquero2013-ld/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Vaquero2013-ld
Vaquero, L. M., &amp;amp; Cebrian, M. (2013). The rich club phenomenon in the classroom. Scientific Reports, 3, 1174. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep01174
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights social interactions generally imply better score for students engaging in them. We find that thesestudents, which is created during the first weeks of the course. Low performing students try to engage in theclub after it has been initially formed, and fail to produce reciprocity in their interactions, displaying more (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Borgatti. (2012). Two-Mode Concepts in Social Network Analysis</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-27-borgatti2012-vh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-27-borgatti2012-vh/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Borgatti2012-vh
Borgatti, S. P. (2012). Social Network Analysis, Two-Mode Concepts in. In R. A. Meyers (Ed.), Computational Complexity (pp. 2912–2924). Springer New York. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4614-1800-9_179
Notes A great intro to two-mode SNA. Requires understanding of SNA basics.
Highlights In social network analysis, 2-mode data refers to data recording ties between two sets of entities. In this con- text, the term “mode” refers to a class of entities – typically called actors, nodes or vertices – whose members have so- cial ties with other members (in the 1-mode case) or with members of another class (in the 2-mode case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Gruzd - 2013 - Enabling community through social media</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-03-30-gruzd2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-03-30-gruzd2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Gruzd2013
Gruzd, A., &amp;amp; Haythornthwaite, C. (2013). Enabling community through social media. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 15(10). doi:10.2196/jmir.2796
Notes Highlights Pescosolido [19] has suggested that a network-centered view of health, based on social network principles, can act as a bridge between medical sciences and individual health experience. Her ideas respond to an increasing recognition of the impact of connectivity and experience: “The individual is seen as embedded in an ongoing relational dynamic with sequences of events seen as patterned, contingent and emergent” (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Studying Online Social Networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-11-05-garton2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-11-05-garton2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @garton2006
Garton, L., Haythornthwaite, C., &amp;amp; Wellman, B. (2006). Studying Online Social Networks. Journal of Computer-Mediated Communication, 3(1). doi:10.1111/j.1083-6101.1997.tb00062.x
Summary This paper gives a great introduction to SNA, covering basic concepts, units of analysis, data collection, and data analysis. Although everything is not in great detail, but it&amp;rsquo;s a great place to start unless you wish to start with a huge textbook.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>