<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data literacy on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/data-literacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data literacy on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-literacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Mandinach. (2016). Teachers learning how to use data: A synthesis of the issues and what is known</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-12-mandinach2016a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-12-mandinach2016a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Mandinach2016a
Mandinach, E. B., &amp;amp; Jimerson, J. B. (2016). Teachers learning how to use data: A synthesis of the issues and what is known. Teaching and Teacher Education, 1–6. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.tate.2016.07.009
Notes This is an editorial of a very timely issue on data literacy of teachers, to be published in Teaching and Teacher Education. This editorial highlights several crosscutting concepts in this area: (a) the need for continuous learning around data e the where and when; (b) the need to integrate data skills with content knowledge and pedagogical content knowledge and link the data skills to other aspects of effective teaching; &amp;copy; the sustainability of impact; (d) models of effective professional learning and the impact of collaborative inquiry and data teaming; and (e) the logic model on impact of data use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Mandinach. (2016). What does it mean for teachers to be data literate</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-12-mandinach2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-12-mandinach2016/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Mandinach2016
Mandinach, E. B. (2016). What does it mean for teachers to be data literate: Laying out the skills, knowledge, and dispositions. Teaching and Teacher Education, 1–27. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.tate.2016.07.011
Notes A foundational piece in the special issue laying out an evolving framework of Data Literacy for Teachers (DLFT). This paper introduces the history of the framework, presents its components, and discusses next steps different parties should take to foster data literacy among teachers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>