<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Constructivism on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/constructivism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Constructivism on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/constructivism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Beyond the Individual-Social Antinomy in Discussions of Piaget and Vygotsky</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-06-cole1996/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-06-cole1996/</guid>
      <description>References Cole, M., &amp;amp; Wertsch, J. V. (1996). Beyond the Individual-Social Antinomy in Discussions of Piaget and Vygotsky. Human Development, 39(5), 250–256. doi:10.1159&amp;frasl;000278475
Citekey: @Cole1996
Notes  This article affords a &amp;lsquo;fresh&amp;rsquo; look at the contrast between Piaget and Vygotsky&amp;rsquo;s constructivist theories. The authors highlight that Piaget has not denied the role of social interactions in knowledge construction, so hasn&amp;rsquo;t Vygotsgy excluded the role of individual thinking. While conventional contrast focuses on the individual vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Genetic epistemology</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-06-piaget1970genetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-06-piaget1970genetic/</guid>
      <description>References Piaget, J. (1970). Genetic epistemology. New York, NY, US: Columbia University Press.
Citekey: @piaget1970genetic
Notes  Piaget&amp;rsquo;s presents a &amp;ldquo;genetic epistemology&amp;rdquo; in that he elaborates how our understanding of knowledge (epistemology) develops in actual people (children) instead of simply as an abstract philosophy based on our adult intuitions about knowledge (the traditional epistemological approach).
According to Jean Piaget, genetic epistemology &amp;ldquo;attempts to explain knowledge, and in particular scientific knowledge, on the basis of its history, its sociogenesis, and especially the psychological origins of the notions and operations upon which it is based&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Vygotsky, Piaget, and Education</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-06-devries2000vygotsky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-06-devries2000vygotsky/</guid>
      <description>References DeVries, R. (2000). Vygotsky, Piaget, and Education: a reciprocal assimilation of theories and educational practices. New Ideas in Psychology, 18(2-3), 187–213. doi:10.1016/S0732-118X(00)00008-8
Citekey: @devries2000vygotsky
Notes Highlights 1. Introduction (p. 1) The current state of my search is one of some confusion. It has been di$cult to resolve a paradox in Vygotsky&amp;rsquo;s work. On the one hand, Vygotsky often sounded like a behaviorist. On the other hand, Vygotsky often sounded like a constructivist.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>