<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experimental design on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/experimental-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experimental design on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/experimental-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Clark - 2014 - Quantitative research designs: recognizing the overall plan for a study</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-28-clark2014-nn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-28-clark2014-nn/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Clark2014-nn
Clark, V. L. P., &amp;amp; Creswell, J. W. (2014). Understanding research: A consumer’s guide. Pearson Higher Ed. (Chapter 6)
Notes Highlights This chapter first introduces you to two major types of quantitative research. It then focuses on the characteristics of five quantitative research designs that you will likely encounter as you read research. Knowing about different quantitative research designs will help you read the Method sections of quantitative reports and understand and evaluate the research designs used in quantitative studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hwang. (2007). A study of multimedia annotation of Web-based materials</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-15-hwang2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-15-hwang2007/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hwang2007
Hwang, W.-Y., Wang, C.-Y., &amp;amp; Sharples, M. (2007). A study of multimedia annotation of Web-based materials. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 48(4), 680–699. doi:10.1016/j.compedu.2005.04.020
Notes Highlights We describe a Web-based tool for creating and sharing annotations and investigate the eVect on learning of its use with college students. First, an annotation tool was designed and implemented for the research. Second, learning support mechanisms, including full and group annotation sharing, were developed to promote students’ motivation for annotation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>