<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine learning on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine learning on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes:  neuralnet: Training of neural network</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-06-gunther2010neuralnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-06-gunther2010neuralnet/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @gunther2010neuralnet
Gu ̈nther, F. and Fritsch, S. (2010). neuralnet: Training of neural networks. The R journal, 2(1):30–38.
Notes This article introduces neuralnet &amp;ndash; an R package that trains supervised neural networks.
Highlights There are two other packages that deal with artificial neural networks at the moment: nnet (Venables and Ripley, 2002) and AMORE (Limas et al., 2007). nnet provides the opportunity to train feed-forward neural networks with traditional backpropagation and in AMORE, the TAO robust neural network algorithm is implemented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: What Sociolinguistics and Machine Learning Have to Say to One Another about Interaction Analysis</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-05-rose2014what/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-05-rose2014what/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @rose2014what
Rosé, C. P., &amp;amp; Tovares A. (in press). What Sociolinguistics and Machine Learning Have to Say to One Another about Interaction Analysis. In L. Resnick, Asterhan C., &amp;amp; Clarke S. (Eds.), Socializing Intelligence Through Academic Talk and Dialogue. Washington, D.C.: American Educational Research Association.
Notes  This chapter grapples with two seemingly contradictory views towards discourse analysis: a sociolinguist approach that embraces complexity (such as Gee&amp;rsquo;s intertextuality approach), and a quantitative approach that strives to best discretize discourse behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>