<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edtech on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/edtech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edtech on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/edtech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital learning in Ontario schools: A &#39;new normal&#39;</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-03-31-digital-learning-in-ontario-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-03-31-digital-learning-in-ontario-schools/</guid>
      <description>Supported by a Mitacs fellowship, I have been working with a Toronto-based non-profit organization, People for Education (P4E), to investigate digital learning in Ontario public schools since October 2013. 
Today, a report about digital learning in Ontario schools has been officially released. Although there have been studies of digital learning in the Canadian context, this topic has not been system-wise inspected. This report draws on a rich set of data coming from P4E&amp;rsquo;s annual principal questionnaire participated by 28% of Ontario public schools, as well as student demographics and questionnaire data from Ontario&amp;rsquo;s Education Quality and Accountability Office (EQAO).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Why the Learning Sciences and Instructional Systems Need Each Other</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-01-hoadley2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-01-hoadley2004/</guid>
      <description>References Hoadley, C. M. (2004). Learning and Design: Why the Learning Sciences and Instructional Systems Need Each Other. Educational Technology, 3, 6–12.
Citekey: @Hoadley2004
Notes Highlights &amp;ldquo;While both analyses varied in their coverage and techniques, they came to similar conclusions, that the literatures identified with these two communities had surprisingly little overlap, and that a small number of individuals represented a large portion of what overlap did exist.&amp;rdquo; (p. 3)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>