<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Scholarship on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Scholarship on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Farris2016-fz: Democratizing Children’s Computation: Learning Computational Science as Aesthetic Experience</title>
      <link>/notes/2018-05-31-farris2016-fz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2018-05-31-farris2016-fz/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Farris2016-fz
Farris, A. V., &amp;amp; Sengupta, P. (2016). Democratizing Children’s Computation: Learning Computational Science as Aesthetic Experience: Democratizing Children&amp;rsquo;s Computation. Educational Theory, 66(1-2), 279–296. https://doi.org/10.1111/edth.12168
Notes Summarize: Drawing on Dewey&amp;rsquo;s classic works (Democracy and Education and Art and Experience), the authors make an intriguing argument that learning computation should be seen as an &amp;lsquo;aesthetic experience&amp;rsquo;. This argument is based on a detailed discussion of ideas from Dewey, ideas from the philosophy of science, and challenges with introducing computation to K-12 classrooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Greenhow2016-vu: Social media and education: reconceptualizing the boundaries of formal and informal learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2018-05-10-greenhow2016-vu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2018-05-10-greenhow2016-vu/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Greenhow2016-vu
Greenhow, C., &amp;amp; Lewin, C. (2016). Social media and education: reconceptualizing the boundaries of formal and informal learning. Learning, Media and Technology, 41(1), 6–30. https://doi.org/10.1080/17439884.2015.1064954
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights We propose a model theorising social media as a space for learning with varying attributes of formality and informality. Through two contrasting case studies we apply our model together with social constructivism and connectivism as theoretical lenses through which to tease out the complexities of learning in various settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Gravel2017-yf: Integrating Computational Artifacts into the Multi-representational Toolkit of Physics Education</title>
      <link>/notes/2018-04-23-gravel2017-yf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2018-04-23-gravel2017-yf/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Gravel2017-yf
Gravel, B. E., &amp;amp; Wilkerson, M. H. (2017). Integrating Computational Artifacts into the Multi-representational Toolkit of Physics Education. In D. F. Treagust, R. Duit, &amp;amp; H. E. Fischer (Eds.), Multiple Representations in Physics Education (pp. 47–70). Cham: Springer International Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-58914-5_3
Notes Summarize:
A piece presenting two case studies about computational artifacts in two communities &amp;ndash; one group of scientists, and one community of grade 5 students &amp;ndash; and their use of computational representation in their own work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Barnett2004-vo</title>
      <link>/notes/2018-04-17-barnett2004-vo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2018-04-17-barnett2004-vo/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Barnett2004-vo
Lodge, J. M., Alhadad, S. S. J., Lewis, M. J., &amp;amp; Gašević, D. (2017). Inferring Learning from Big Data: The Importance of a Transdisciplinary and Multidimensional Approach. Technology, Knowledge and Learning, 22(3), 385–400. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10758-017-9330-3
Notes Summarize: Nice paper discussion the importance of engaging in transdisciplinary dialogues in learning analytics to expose philosophical assumptions we make. Many great points are made by making analogies with other transdisciplinary areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Suthers2015-vf: From contingencies to network-level phenomena</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-12-22-suthers2015-vf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-12-22-suthers2015-vf/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Suthers2015-vf
Suthers, D. (2015). From contingencies to network-level phenomena: multilevel analysis of activity and actors in heterogeneous networked learning environments. In Proceedings of the Fifth International Conference on Learning Analytics And Knowledge (pp. 368–377). ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/2723576.2723626
Notes Summarize: Introduces the Traces framework coming out of Suthers&amp;rsquo; years of work in CSCL and learning analytics.
Reflect: This paper and the Traces framework are super relevant to my current thinking on multidimensional network analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes:  neuralnet: Training of neural network</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-06-gunther2010neuralnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-06-gunther2010neuralnet/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @gunther2010neuralnet
Gu ̈nther, F. and Fritsch, S. (2010). neuralnet: Training of neural networks. The R journal, 2(1):30–38.
Notes This article introduces neuralnet &amp;ndash; an R package that trains supervised neural networks.
Highlights There are two other packages that deal with artificial neural networks at the moment: nnet (Venables and Ripley, 2002) and AMORE (Limas et al., 2007). nnet provides the opportunity to train feed-forward neural networks with traditional backpropagation and in AMORE, the TAO robust neural network algorithm is implemented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: A review of e-learning in Canada</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-26-abrami2006review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-26-abrami2006review/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @abrami2006review
Abrami, P. C., Bernard, R., Wade, A., Schmid, R. F., Borokhovski, E., Tamin, R., … others. (2006). A review of e-learning in Canada: A rough sketch of the evidence, gaps and promising directions. Canadian Journal of Learning and Technology/La Revue Canadienne de L’apprentissage et de La Technologie, 32(3).
Notes Highlights This review provides a rough sketch of the evidence, gaps and promising directions in e­learning from 2000 onwards, with a particular focus on Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Agneessens, F., &amp; Everett, M. G. (2013). Introduction to the special issue on advances in two-mode social networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-15-agneessens2013-wp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-15-agneessens2013-wp/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Agneessens2013-wp
Agneessens, F., &amp;amp; Everett, M. G. (2013). Introduction to the special issue on advances in two-mode social networks. Social Networks, 35(2), 145–147. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2013.03.002
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Two-mode data was collected by Davis et al. (1941) in theirclassic study on theparticipation of Southern women in social events and later by a variety of researchers studying interlocking directorates from the 1970s onwards (e.g., Stokman et al., 1985).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Agudo-Peregrina. (2014). Can we predict success from log data in VLEs</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-11-29-agudo2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-11-29-agudo2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Agudo2014
Agudo-Peregrina, Á. F., Iglesias-Pradas, S., Conde-González, M. Á., &amp;amp; Hernández-García, Á. (2014). Can we predict success from log data in VLEs? Classification of interactions for learning analytics and their relation with performance in VLE-supported F2F and online learning. Computers in Human Behavior, 31, 542–550. doi:10.1016/j.chb.2013.05.031
Notes Highlights The emergence of distance learning fostered a shift towards the decentralization of the learning process, with higher effort put on course structure and content creation (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ali. (2012). A qualitative evaluation of evolution of a learning analytics tool</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-11-29-ali2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-11-29-ali2012/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ali2012
Ali, L., Hatala, M., Gašević, D., &amp;amp; Jovanović, J. (2012). A qualitative evaluation of evolution of a learning analytics tool. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 58(1), 470–489. doi:10.1016/j.compedu.2011.08.030
Notes Highlights In our research, we have been specifically interested in investigating the use of semantic technologies for learning analytics. Semantic technologies can enable meaningful linking of students’ learning activities and their interactions with the learning contents as well as with the other participants of their learning processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ali. (2013). Factors influencing beliefs for adoption of a learning analytics tool</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-01-ali2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-01-ali2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ali2013
Ali, L., Asadi, M., Gašević, D., Jovanović, J., &amp;amp; Hatala, M. (2013). Factors influencing beliefs for adoption of a learning analytics tool: An empirical study. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 62, 130–148.
Notes Highlights In this paper, we propose and empirically validate a Learning Analytics Acceptance Model (LAAM) of factors influencing the beliefs of educators concerning the adoption a learning analytics tool. In particular, our model explains how the usage beliefs (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Allen - 2015 - Modeling Students’ Reading Comprehension Skills with Natural Language Processing Techniques</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-04-02-allen2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-04-02-allen2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Allen2015
Allen, L. K., Snow, E. L., &amp;amp; McNamara, D. S. (2015). Are you reading my mind? Modeling Students’ Reading Comprehension Skills with Natural Language Processing Techniques. In Proceedings of the Fifth International Conference on Learning Analytics And Knowledge - LAK ’15 (pp. 246–254). doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;2723576.2723617
Notes Applying Coh-Metrix and LSA to assess students&amp;rsquo; reading comprehension. Could also be applied in collaborative online discourse.
Highlights The current study leverages natural language processing tools to build models of students’ comprehension ability from the linguistic properties of their self-explanations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: An Exploration of Epistemological Understanding and Participation in Online Knowledge Building Communities</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-29-forrester2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-29-forrester2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @forrester2006
Notes Highlights References Forrester, B. (2006). An Exploration of Epistemological Understanding and Participation in Online Knowledge Building Communities. University of Toronto.
Notes Marlene recommended it to me, to inform me of my thinking on epistemological issues in KB and promisingness.
The idea of belief-mode vs. design-mode epistemology is interesting. (This thesis integrates Marlene&amp;rsquo;s analysis of Kuhn and Perry research, clarifying that it represents a belief-mode epistemology.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: An extended systematic review of Canadian policy documents on e-Learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-26-borokhovski2011extended/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-26-borokhovski2011extended/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @borokhovski2011extended
Borokhovski, E., Bernard, R., Mills, E., Abrami, P. C., Wade, C. A., Tamim, R., … Surkes, M. A. (2011). An extended systematic review of Canadian policy documents on e-Learning: What we’re doing and not doing. Canadian Journal of Learning and Technology/La Revue Canadienne de L’apprentissage et de La Technologie, 37(3), 1–30.
Notes Highlights In total, 138 policy documents from Canadian provinces and territories and several federal agencies, dated from 2000 to 2010, were identified, retrieved and analyzed using prescriptive and emergent coding approaches with the purpose of uncovering and describing areas of commonality and inconsistency and, hence, determining where discussions about e-learning are lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Analyzing collaborative knowledge construction</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-05-21-hmelo-silver2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-05-21-hmelo-silver2003/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @hmelo-silver2003
Notes Highlights References Hmelo-Silver, C. E. (2003). Analyzing collaborative knowledge construction. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 41(4), 397–420. doi:10.1016/j.compedu.2003.07.001
Summary I got interested in this paper because of the CORDTRA diagram mentioned at an AERA session. The main message from this article is discourse data need to be analyzed with multiple methods in order to get a clear understanding about what&amp;rsquo;s going on with collaborative learning or knowledge construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Analyzing the flow of ideas and profiles of contributors in an open learning community</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-04-11-halatchliyski2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-04-11-halatchliyski2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @halatchliyski2013
References Halatchliyski, I., Hecking, T., G\&amp;ldquo;ohnertTilman, &amp;amp; Hoppe, H. U. (2013). Analyzing the flow of ideas and profiles of contributors in an open learning community. In Proceedings of the Third International Conference on Learning Analytics and Knowledge LAK &amp;lsquo;13 (66). New York, New York, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;2460296.2460311
Rough summary The title of this article grasped my eyes. It appeared to be very relevant to what we&amp;rsquo;re discussing about designing assessment of/for knowledge creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Andrade, A. (2015). Using Situated-Action Networks to visualize complex learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-14-andrade2015using/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-14-andrade2015using/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @andrade2015using
Andrade, A. (2015). Using Situated-Action Networks to visualize complex learning. In O. Lindwall, P. Häkkinen, T. Koschmann, P. Tchounikine, &amp;amp; S. Ludvigsen (Eds.), Exploring the Material Conditions of Learning: The Computer Supported Collaborative Learning (CSCL) Conference 2015, Volume 1 (pp. 372–379). Gothenburg, Sweden: International Society of the Learning Sciences.
Notes This paper introduces a quite interesting analytical technique, named Situated-Action Network, which is theoretically informed by sociocultural learning theories and methodologically grounded in SNA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Assessment of adult attitudes towards continuing education</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-18-darkenwald1988assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-18-darkenwald1988assessment/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @darkenwald1988assessment
Darkenwald GG and Hayes ER (1988). “Assessment of adult attitudes towards continuing education.” International journal of lifelong education, 7(3), pp. 197-204.
Notes Highlights Most definitions of attitude are similar to that proposed by Gagne and Briggs (1974: 62):&amp;lsquo;An internal state which affects an individual&amp;rsquo;s choice of action toward some object, person, or event&amp;rsquo;. Little wonder, then, that the construct of &amp;lsquo;attitude&amp;rsquo; occupies a central place in current theory on participation in continuing (or adult) education (Cross 1981;Darkenwald and Merriam 1982; Houle1984; Rubenson 1977).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Aturban (2015) Quantifying orphaned annotations in Hypothes.is</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-14-aturban2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-14-aturban2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Aturban2015
Aturban, M., Nelson, M. L., &amp;amp; Weigle, M. C. (2015). Quantifying orphaned annotations in Hypothes.is (pp. 15–27). doi:10.1007&amp;frasl;978-3-319-24592-8_2
Notes An empirical investigation of orphaned annotations in Hypothes.is. The results are clearly stated in the paper. This paper highlights the significant challenge faced by web annotations &amp;ndash; the persistence of the first-order content that maintains the context of annotations.
(This paper has a light, useful intro to Hypothes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Bannert - 2014 - Process mining techniques for analysing patterns and strategies in students’ self-regulated learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-04-01-bannert2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-04-01-bannert2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Bannert2014
Bannert, M., Reimann, P., &amp;amp; Sonnenberg, C. (2014). Process mining techniques for analysing patterns and strategies in students’ self-regulated learning. Metacognition and Learning, 9, 161–185. doi:10.1007/s11409-013-9107-6
Notes A nice article applying Process Mining (PM) on the study of self-regulated learning. Starting from discussing the importance of studying temporal and sequential information in self-regulated learning, this article moves on to introduce the key ideas of PM. Then it illustrates the application of PM, using a software called ProM v5, to study a group of students&amp;rsquo; learning in a hypermedia environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Barab. (2001). Constructing Networks of Action-Relevant Episodes: An In Situ Research Methodology</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-16-barab2001-jt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-16-barab2001-jt/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Barab2001-jt
Barab, S. A., Hay, K. E., &amp;amp; Yamagata-Lynch, L. C. (2001). Constructing Networks of Action-Relevant Episodes: An In Situ Research Methodology. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 10(1-2), 63–112. https://doi.org/10.1207/S15327809JLS10-1-2_5
Notes Summarize: This paper introduces a methodology that&amp;rsquo;s grounded in Activity Theory and situated cognition, and based on ethnographic approaches and network analysis. It offers a very thorough and useful exploration of the need for analysis of knowing &amp;lsquo;in situ&amp;rsquo;, compared with traditional analysis of learning results / knowledge products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Bereiter - 2014 - Knowledge building and knowledge creation: One concept, two hills to climb</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-12-10-bereiter2014knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-12-10-bereiter2014knowledge/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @bereiter2014knowledge
Bereiter C and Scardamalia M (2014). “Knowledge building and knowledge creation: One concept, two hills to climb.” In Knowledge Creation in Education, pp. 35-52. Springer.
Notes Highlights Early in the 1990s, the term “knowledge creation” entered the organizational sciences literature, conveying the idea that companies can not only accumulate and use but literally create knowledge that enables them to progress (Nonaka 1991; Nonaka and Takeuchi 1995). At about the same time, the term “knowledge building” appeared in the learning sciences literature, representing the same idea (Scardamalia and Bereiter 1991; Scardamalia et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Berliner2002-jo- Comment: Educational research: The hardest science of all</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-07-berliner2002-jo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-07-berliner2002-jo/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Berliner2002-jo
Berliner, D. C. (2002). Comment: Educational research: The hardest science of all. Educational Researcher, 31(8), 18–20. https://doi.org/10.3102/0013189X031008018
Notes Summarize: An argument against the sole promotion / endorsement of randomized control trials / experiments in the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001. Nicely argued.
Highlights The “evidence-based practices” and “scientific research” men- tioned over 100 times in the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001 are code words for randomized experiments, a method of re- search with which I too am much enamored (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Berners-Lee. (2006). Creating a science of the Web</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-19-berners-lee2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-19-berners-lee2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Berners-Lee2006
Berners-Lee, T. (2006). Creating a science of the Web. Science, 313(5788), 769–771. doi:10.1126/science.1126902
Notes Highlights Understanding and fostering the growth of the World Wide Web, both in engineering and societal terms, will require the development of a new interdisciplinary field. (p. 1)
lyzes the natural world, and tries to find microscopic laws that, extrapolated to the macroscopic realm, would generate the behavior observed. Computer science, by contrast, though partly analytic, is principally synthetic: It is concerned with the construction of new languages and algorithms in order to produce novel desired computer behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Berners-Lee. (2010). Long live the Web</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-19-berners-lee2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-19-berners-lee2010/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Berners-Lee2010
Berners-Lee, T. (2010). Long live the Web. Scientific American, 303(6), 80–85. doi:10.1038/scientificamerican1210-80
Notes Highlights Once you enter your data into one of these services, you cannot easily use them on another site. Each site is a silo, walled o from the others. (p. 3)
Universality is the FoUndation (p. 3)
The primary design principle underlying the Web’s usefulness and growth is universality. When you make a link, you can link to anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Beyond the Individual-Social Antinomy in Discussions of Piaget and Vygotsky</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-06-cole1996/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-06-cole1996/</guid>
      <description>References Cole, M., &amp;amp; Wertsch, J. V. (1996). Beyond the Individual-Social Antinomy in Discussions of Piaget and Vygotsky. Human Development, 39(5), 250–256. doi:10.1159&amp;frasl;000278475
Citekey: @Cole1996
Notes  This article affords a &amp;lsquo;fresh&amp;rsquo; look at the contrast between Piaget and Vygotsky&amp;rsquo;s constructivist theories. The authors highlight that Piaget has not denied the role of social interactions in knowledge construction, so hasn&amp;rsquo;t Vygotsgy excluded the role of individual thinking. While conventional contrast focuses on the individual vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Black &amp; Wiliam - 1998 - Assessment and classroom learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-09-23-black1998a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-09-23-black1998a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Black1998a
Black, P., &amp;amp; Wiliam, D. (1998). Assessment and classroom learning. Assessment in Education: Principles, Policy &amp;amp; Practice, 5(1), 7–74. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;0969595980050102
Notes A comprehensive review of the effectiveness of feedback in classrooms.
Highlights ABSTRACT This article is a review of the literature on classroom formative assessment. Several studies show firm evidence that innovations designed to strengthen the frequent feedback that students receive about their learning yield substantial learning gains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Blikstein - 2013 - Multimodal learning analytics</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-13-blikstein2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-13-blikstein2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Blikstein2013
Blikstein, P. (2013). Multimodal learning analytics. In Proceedings of the Third International Conference on Learning Analytics and Knowledge - LAK ’13 (p. 102). New York, New York, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;2460296.2460316
Notes Paulo Blikstein&amp;rsquo;s intro to a series of his preliminary work on multimodal learning analytics. I think he is credited as the creator of this line of work.
 I presented a series of proof-of-concept studies for what I termed “multimodal learning analytics:” a set of techniques that can be used to collect multiple sources of data in highfrequency (video, logs, audio, gestures, biosensors), synchronize and code the data, and examine learning in realistic, ecologically valid, social, mixed-media learning environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Boote - 2005 - Scholars Before Researchers</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-10-04-boote2005-kt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-10-04-boote2005-kt/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Boote2005-kt
Boote, D. N., &amp;amp; Beile, P. (2005). Scholars Before Researchers: On the Centrality of the Dissertation Literature Review in Research Preparation. Educational Researcher , 34(6), 3–15.
Notes Highlights This article suggests criteria to evaluate the quality of dissertation literature reviews and reports a study that examined dis- sertations at three universities. Acquiring the skills and knowledge required to be education scholars, able to analyze and synthesize the research in a field of specialization, should be the focal, integrative activity of predissertation doctoral education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Borgatti. (2012). Two-Mode Concepts in Social Network Analysis</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-27-borgatti2012-vh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-27-borgatti2012-vh/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Borgatti2012-vh
Borgatti, S. P. (2012). Social Network Analysis, Two-Mode Concepts in. In R. A. Meyers (Ed.), Computational Complexity (pp. 2912–2924). Springer New York. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4614-1800-9_179
Notes A great intro to two-mode SNA. Requires understanding of SNA basics.
Highlights In social network analysis, 2-mode data refers to data recording ties between two sets of entities. In this con- text, the term “mode” refers to a class of entities – typically called actors, nodes or vertices – whose members have so- cial ties with other members (in the 1-mode case) or with members of another class (in the 2-mode case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Buckingham - 2010 - Defining digital literacy</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-27-buckingham2010-mc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-27-buckingham2010-mc/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Buckingham2010-mc
Buckingham, D. (2010). Defining digital literacy. In Medienbildung in neuen Kulturr{ä}umen (pp. 59–71). Springer.
Notes This chapter criticizes traditional emphasis on functional aspects of digital literacy and highlights four broad conceptual aspects that are generally regarded as essential components of media literacy (see Buckingham, 2003): representation, language, production, and audience. The author treats media not simply as tools but cultural forms and invite educators to recognize cultural practices related to new media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: CSILE/Knowledge Forum</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia2004/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia2004
Scardamalia, M. (2004). CSILE/Knowledge Forum. In A. Kovalchick &amp;amp; K. Dawson (Eds.), Education and technology: An encyclopedia (pp. 183–192). Santa Barbara, CA: ABC-CLIO.
Notes ::The origins of CSILE (Computer Supported Intentional Learning Environments) are in research on knowledge building, on the nature of expertise, and on the socio-cultural dynamics of innovation. CSILE was designed to (a) make advanced knowledge processes accessible to all participants, including children, (b) foster the creation and continual improvement of public artifacts or community knowledge (Scardamalia, 2002), and ( c ) provide a community space for carrying out this knowledge building work collaboratives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Carley. (2003). Dynamic network analysis</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-02-08-carley2003-zk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-02-08-carley2003-zk/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Carley2003-zk
Carley, K. M. (2003). Dynamic network analysis. In R. Breiger, K. Carley, &amp;amp; P. Pattison (Eds.), Dynamic Social Network Modeling and Analysis: Workshop Summary and Papers (pp. 133–145). Washington, DC: National Academies Press. Retrieved from http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.299.8946&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Clearly social network analysis can be applied to the study of covert networks (Sparrow, 1991). Many are stepping forward suggesting that to understand these networks we just need to “connect the dots” and then isolate the “key actors who are often defined in terms of their “centrality” in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Carley. (2012). Data-to-model: a mixed initiative approach for rapid ethnographic assessment</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-30-carley2012-xn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-30-carley2012-xn/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Carley2012-xn
Carley, K. M., Bigrigg, M. W., &amp;amp; Diallo, B. (2012). Data-to-model: a mixed initiative approach for rapid ethnographic assessment. Computational &amp;amp; Mathematical Organization Theory, 18(3), 300–327. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10588-012-9125-y
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Rapid ethnographic assessment is used when there is a need to quickly create a socio-cultural profile of a group or region. While there are many forms such an assessment can take, we view it as providing insight into who are the key actors, what are the key issues, sentiments, resources, activities and locations, how have these changed in recent times, and what roles do the various actors play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Chai, S. C., &amp; Khine, M. S. (2006). An Analysis of Interaction and Participation Patterns in Online Community</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-01-chai2006a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-01-chai2006a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Chai2006a
Chai, S. C., &amp;amp; Khine, M. S. (2006). An Analysis of Interaction and Participation Patterns in Online Community. Journal of Educational Technology &amp;amp; Society, 9(1), 250–261.
Notes Highlights Although the KBC model draws on the constructivist-oriented theories, researchers directly involved in developing KBC argued that the KBC has moved social-cultural framework beyond the acquisition of knowledge and appropriation of practices to that of creation of knowledge. (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Chan, C. K. K., &amp; van Aalst, J. (2006). Teacher Development through Computer‐supported Knowledge Building</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-03-chan2006b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-03-chan2006b/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Chan2006b
Chan, C. K. K., &amp;amp; van Aalst, J. (2006). Teacher Development through Computer‐supported Knowledge Building: Experience from Hong Kong and Canadian teachers. Teaching Education, 17(1), 7–26. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;10476210500527907
Notes Highlights We propose a framework for designing teacher education courses premised on the knowledge-building perspective developed by Scardamalia and Bereiter (2003) to illustrate how teacher education may encourage teachers to become inquirers and knowledge creators in a knowledge-building community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Chen. (2010). What do students do in a F2F CSCL classroom? The optimization of multiple communications modes</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-08-18-chen2010-ao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-08-18-chen2010-ao/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Chen2010-ao
Chen, W., Looi, C.-K., &amp;amp; Tan, S. (2010). What do students do in a F2F CSCL classroom? The optimization of multiple communications modes. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 55(3), 1159–1170. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2010.05.013
Notes Summarize: An interesting descriptive (or exploratory) case study investigating student online &amp;amp; F2F communication in a CSCL environment.
Highlights Small groups of students interacted face- to-face over a computer-mediated communication (CMC) technology called Group Scribbles (GS) to jointly complete a learning task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Chen. (2012). Development and evaluation of a Web 2.0 annotation system</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-15-chen2012c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-15-chen2012c/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Chen2012c
Chen, Y.-C., Hwang, R.-H., &amp;amp; Wang, C.-Y. (2012). Development and evaluation of a Web 2.0 annotation system as a learning tool in an e-learning environment. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 58(4), 1094–1105. doi:10.1016/j.compedu.2011.12.017
Notes This study implements MyNote, the web annotation system primarily tied to an LMS, and evaluate usability of this system with students. This system does not adhere to any web annotation standards.
Highlights The purpose of this study was to develop a Web 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Choudhury - 2004 - Characterizing social interactions using the sociometer</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-27-choudhury2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-27-choudhury2004/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Choudhury2004
Choudhury, T., &amp;amp; Pentland, A. (2004). Characterizing social interactions using the sociometer. Proceedings of NAACOS, 1–4. Retrieved from http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.153.7399&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf
Notes A much earlier version of sociometers when they only measure voices for conversation and turn-taking.
Highlights SENSING &amp;amp; MODELING HUMAN NETWORKS (p. 1)
This paper describes our work in developing a computational framework to model face-to-face interactions within a community. We have integrated methods from speech processing and machine learning to demonstrate that it is possible to extract information about people’s patterns of communication, without imposing any restriction on the user’s interactions or environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Choudhury - 2008 - The Mobile Sensing Platform: An Embedded Activity Recognition System</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-29-choudhury2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-29-choudhury2008/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Choudhury2008
Choudhury, T., Borriello, G., Consolvo, S., Haehnel, D., Harrison, B., Hemingway, B., … Wyatt, D. (2008). The Mobile Sensing Platform: An Embedded Activity Recognition System. IEEE Pervasive Computing, 7(2), 32–41. doi:10.1109/MPRV.2008.39
Notes A seemingly early work of mobile sensing leading to fitness products like Fitbit. The article introduces an iterative process of designing and testing generations of mobile sensing devices. It highlights the importance synergy between hardware and software (machine learning algorithms) in order to accurately detect and classify physical activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ciccarese (2013) Web annotation as a first-class object</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-14-ciccarese2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-14-ciccarese2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ciccarese2013
Ciccarese, P., Soiland-Reyes, S., &amp;amp; Clark, T. (2013). Web annotation as a first-class object. IEEE Internet Computing, 17(6), 71–75. doi:10.1109/MIC.2013.123
Notes A thorough explanation of the history of web annotation.
Highlights The W3C Open Annotation Data Model provides facilities for annotating content directly on the Web without changing the original content.Third-party semantic annotations of content are now emerging as rst-class objects on the Web. (p. 71)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Clark - 2014 - Quantitative research designs: recognizing the overall plan for a study</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-28-clark2014-nn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-28-clark2014-nn/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Clark2014-nn
Clark, V. L. P., &amp;amp; Creswell, J. W. (2014). Understanding research: A consumer’s guide. Pearson Higher Ed. (Chapter 6)
Notes Highlights This chapter first introduces you to two major types of quantitative research. It then focuses on the characteristics of five quantitative research designs that you will likely encounter as you read research. Knowing about different quantitative research designs will help you read the Method sections of quantitative reports and understand and evaluate the research designs used in quantitative studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Clow, D. (2013). An overview of learning analytics</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-01-clow2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-01-clow2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Clow2013
Clow, D. (2013). An overview of learning analytics. Teaching in Higher Education, 18(6), 683–695. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;13562517.2013.827653
Notes Highlights It is rooted in the dramatic increase in the quantity of data about learners and linked to management approaches that focus on quantitative metrics, which are sometimes antithetical to an educational sense of teaching. (p. 1)
It argues that teachers can and should engage with learning analytics as a way of influencing the metrics agenda towards richer conceptions of learning and to improve their teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Clustering and sequential pattern mining of online collaborative learning data</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-04-30-perera2009clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-04-30-perera2009clustering/</guid>
      <description>References Perera, D., Kay, J., Koprinska, I., Yacef, K., &amp;amp; Zaïane, O. R. (2009). Clustering and sequential pattern mining of online collaborative learning data. Knowledge and Data Engineering, IEEE Transactions on, 21(6), 759–772.
Citekey: @perera2009clustering
Notes Highlights mirroring (p. 2)
To underpin our work, we have used the Big Five theory of group work [1]. (p. 3)
It has established five key factors: leadership, mutual performance monitoring, backup behaviour, adaptability and team orientation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Cole &amp; Engeström - 1993 - A cultural-historical approach to distributed cognition</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-03-24-cole1993-zt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-03-24-cole1993-zt/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Cole1993-zt
Cole, M., &amp;amp; Engeström, Y. (1993). A cultural-historical approach to distributed cognition. In G. Salomon (Ed.), Distributed cognitions: Psychological and educational considerations (pp. 1–46). New York: Cambridge University Press.
Notes Summarize: This is a seminal piece about the activity (system) theory as a cultural-historical view of learning. It touches on several important connections between AT and expansive learning, distributed cognition, etc.
Assess: I especially like the second example presented in this paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Colvin - 2014 - Learning in an introductory physics MOOC: All cohorts learn equally, including an on-campus class</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-26-colvin14learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-26-colvin14learning/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @colvin14learning
Colvin K, Champaign J, Liu A, Zhou Q, Fredericks C and Pritchard D (2014). “Learning in an introductory physics MOOC: All cohorts learn equally, including an on-campus class.” The International Review of Research in Open and Distance Learning, 15(4). ISSN 1492-3831, .
Notes Highlights Abstract
We studied student learning in the MOOC 8.MReV Mechanics ReView, run on the edX.org open source platform. We studied learning in two ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Community knowledge assessment in a knowledge building environment</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-07-18-hong2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-07-18-hong2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hong2014
Hong, H.-Y. and Scardamalia, M. (2014). Community knowledge assessment in a knowledge building environment. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 71:279–288.
Notes Highlights According to Stahl (2006) group cognition requires a theory of collaboration that takes the group as the unit of analysis rather than the individual. ‘Learning by groups’ is not the same as ‘learning in groups’ or individual learning through social processes. (p. 1)
1.1. Community knowledge (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Computer Support for Knowledge-Building Communities</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia1994/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia1994/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia1994
Scardamalia, M., &amp;amp; Bereiter, C. (1994). Computer Support for Knowledge-Building Communities. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 3(3), 265–283. doi:10.1207/s15327809jls0303_3
Notes It has seemed to us that a promising approach to school restructuring would start by examining how schools (including the high-achieving ones) limit knowledge-building potential. By addressing fundamental shortcom- ings, we may find it possible to do more than struggle to catch up.
 informal knowledge that has been found to characterize expert competence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Computer-supported intentional learning environments</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-16-scardamalia1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-16-scardamalia1989/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia1989
Scardamalia, M., Bereiter, C., Mclean, R. S., Swallow, J., &amp;amp; Woodruff, E. (1989). Computer-supported intentional learning environments. Journal of Educational Computing Research, 5(1), 51–68.
Notes This article explains design principles of CSILE. These principles are very much based on literature about successful learning. Comparing to knowledge building principles, they are very different in that they emphasize on learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Contractor et al. (2011). Multidimensional networks and the dynamics of sociomateriality</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-12-contractor2011-vc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-12-contractor2011-vc/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Contractor2011-vc
Contractor, N., Monge, P., &amp;amp; Leonardi, P. M. (2011). Multidimensional networks and the dynamics of sociomateriality: bringing technology inside the network. International Journal of Communication Systems, 5, 39. Retrieved from http://ijoc.org/index.php/ijoc/article/view/1131
Notes Summarize: Fascinating work on multidimensional networks&amp;mdash;multi-mode, multi-plex, dynamic networks (akin to Carley&amp;rsquo;s dynamic network analysis). This paper starts by talking about sociomateriality&amp;mdash;arguing that tech and human are inseparable, so they should be kept in a same network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Contractor, N. (2009). The Emergence of Multidimensional Networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-12-contractor2009-sv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-12-contractor2009-sv/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Contractor2009-sv
Contractor, N. (2009). The Emergence of Multidimensional Networks. Journal of Computer-Mediated Communication: JCMC, 14(3), 743–747. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1083-6101.2009.01465.x
Notes Summarize: This short essay makes some really great points about the emergence of multidimentinoal networks (multimode, multiplex) in the context of Internet evolution.
Highlights Yet there are some success stories that suggest the need to understand the social factors that shape the use of technologies to create and sustain organizational, interorganizational, and community knowledge networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Cowan, P., &amp; Butler, R. (2013). Using Activity Theory to Problematize the Role of the Teacher During Mobile Learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-10-cowan2013-ke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-10-cowan2013-ke/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Cowan2013-ke
Cowan, P., &amp;amp; Butler, R. (2013). Using Activity Theory to Problematize the Role of the Teacher During Mobile Learning. SAGE Open, 3(4), 2158244013516155. https://doi.org/10.1177/2158244013516155
Notes Summarize: Interesting use of activity theory. There is an attempt to advance AT in this piece as well. The focus on &amp;lsquo;4 faces&amp;rsquo; of activity systems is interesting and may be combined with automated, network measures.
Highlights m-learning is a new peda- gogical option for teachers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Dawson, S. (2010). “Seeing” the learning community</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-13-dawson2010a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-13-dawson2010a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Dawson2010a
Dawson, S. (2010). “Seeing” the learning community: An exploration of the development of a resource for monitoring online student networking. British Journal of Educational Technology, 41(5), 736–752. doi:10.1111/j.1467-8535.2009.00970.x
Notes Another great article by Shane Dawson, which sports a very well-written intro and discussion. The SNA analysis conducted in this study is different from those in SNAPP studies, emphasizing ego-centric networks of high- vs. low-performing students in a large lecture (N &amp;gt; 1000).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Dawson. (2010). SNAPP</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-13-dawson2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-13-dawson2010/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Dawson2010
Dawson, S., Bakharia, A., &amp;amp; Heathcote, E. (2010). SNAPP: Realising the affordances of real-time SNA within networked learning environments. In Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Networked Learning (pp. 125–133).
Notes This paper introduces SNAPP, a real-time SNA tool integrated with multiple widely used LMS. The paper explains motivation of designing this tool, multiple design principles of this tool, and its main usefulness (uncovering facilitator centric patterns and identifying isolators).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Design Research for Sustained Innovation</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-03-31-bereiter2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-03-31-bereiter2002/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @bereiter2002
Bereiter, C. (2002). Design Research for Sustained Innovation. Cognitive Studies, 9(3), 321&amp;ndash;327.
Clippings Although there is innovation in education it tends to be sporadic and discontinuous, with the result that innovative practices seldom win out against those with a long evolutionary history. (p. 1)
add a note here (p. 2)
The automobile engine is especially interesting, because the inherent drawbacks of the reciprocating piston engine were recognized early and there were periodic attempts at radical innovation, none of which has yet succeeded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Designing for Productive Failure</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-03-26-kapur2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-03-26-kapur2012/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @kapur2012
Kapur, M., &amp;amp; Bielaczyc, K. (2012). Designing for Productive Failure. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 21(1), 45&amp;ndash;83. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;10508406.2011.591717
Clippings the design principles undergirding productive failure (PF; M. Kapur, 2008). (p. 3)
(a) PF, in which students collaboratively solved complex problems on average speed without any instructional support or scaffolds up until a teacher-led consolidation; or (b) direct instruction (DI), in which the teacher provided strong instructional support, scaffolding, and feedback (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Developmental aspects of expertise: Rationality and generalization</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-06-24-bickhard1996/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-06-24-bickhard1996/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @bickhard1996
Notes Highlights References Bickhard, M. H., &amp;amp; Campbell, R. L. (1996). Developmental aspects of expertise: Rationality and generalization. Journal of Experimental &amp;amp; Theoretical Artificial Intelligence, 8(3-4), 399–417. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;095281396147393
Notes Cited by Carl and Marlene when talking about promisingness in QWERTY paper.
&amp;ldquo;negative knowledge&amp;rdquo;
An expert is someone who knows some of the worst mistakes that can be made in his subject, and how to avoid them. Werner Heisenberg</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Dijksterhuis. (2006). On Making the Right Choice</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-09-30-dijksterhuis2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-09-30-dijksterhuis2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Dijksterhuis2006
Dijksterhuis, A. (2006). On Making the Right Choice: The Deliberation-Without-Attention Effect. Science, 311(5763), 1005–1007. doi:10.1126/science.1121629
Notes A nice article reporting on four studies on the &amp;ldquo;Deliberation-Without-Attention&amp;rdquo; hypothesis; that is, simple choices (such as between different towels or different sets of oven mitts) indeed produce better results after conscious thought, but that choices in complex matters (such as between different houses or different cars) should be left to unconscious thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: E-learning in Canada</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-26-mcgreal2007learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-26-mcgreal2007learning/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @mcgreal2007learning
McGreal, R., &amp;amp; Anderson, T. (2007). E-learning in Canada. International Journal of Distance Education Technologies (IJDET), 5(1), 1–6.
Notes Highlights A principal characteristic of the Canadian experience with e-learning is the uniquely Canadian feature of provincial jurisdiction over education. (p. 1)
Therefore, any investigation of e-learning in Canada must focus more on specific provincial initiatives in technologically enhanced learning rather than a Canadian overview. (p. 1)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ebben-2014-Unpacking MOOC scholarly discourse</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-10-13-ebben2014-gz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-10-13-ebben2014-gz/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ebben2014-gz
Ebben, M., &amp;amp; Murphy, J. S. (2014). Unpacking MOOC scholarly discourse: a review of nascent MOOC scholarship. Learning, Media and Technology, 39(3), 328–345.
Notes Summarize: This paper unpacks the MOOC scholarly discourse, with critical lenses that are terribly needed. It focuses on publications from 2009 – 2013, which features the transitional moment from cMOOCs to xMOOCs. The search results &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; include 15 papers published during that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Edelson. (2002). Design research</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-07-edelson2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-07-edelson2002/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Edelson2002
Edelson, D. C. (2002). Design research: What we learn when we engage in design. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 11(1), 105–121. doi:10.1207/S15327809JLS1101_4
Notes An important piece on design research articulating different types of theories in DR, as well as &amp;lsquo;twin intentions/goals&amp;rsquo; of advancing both design theories and domain theories in DR.
Highlights The emerging design research paradigm treats design as a strategy for developing and refining theories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Educating intuition</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-09-26-hogarth2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-09-26-hogarth2001/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @hogarth2001
Hogarth, R. M. (2001). Educating intuition. Chicago, Ill.: University of Chicago Press.
Notes Hogarth defines intuition as responses ‘reached with little apparent effort, and typically without conscious effort. They involve little or no conscious deliberation’ (p. 14).
Hogarth pursues the question of whether we can rely upon our intuition. That is, should we let our intuition guide our decision making? The answer that emerges from the book is not a simple ‘yes’ or ‘no’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Engestrom. (2009). The future of activity theory</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-04-04-engestrom2009-fq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-04-04-engestrom2009-fq/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Engestrom2009-fq
Engeström, Y. (2009). The future of activity theory: A rough draft. Learning and Expanding with Activity Theory, 303–328. Retrieved from https://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;id=pyY5EusnjBcC&amp;amp;oi=fnd&amp;amp;pg=PA303&amp;amp;dq=the+future+of+activity+theory&amp;amp;ots=KRW_JyuHpy&amp;amp;sig=mvpfOxH73y4RFSPYguo4CrM0LDY
Notes Summarize: A thoughtful piece that explains AT deeply and also explores its neighboring concepts.
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Recently Aaro Toomela has published two papers in which he critically assesses the contents and potential of activity theory. The first one is titled ’Activity theory is a dead end for cultural-historical psychology’ (Toomela, 2000), the second one ’Activity theory is a dead end for methodological thinking in cultural psychology too’ (Toomela, 2008).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Engeström, Y., &amp; Sannino, A. (2011). Discursive manifestations of contradictions in organizational change efforts</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-04-engestrom2011-yr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-04-engestrom2011-yr/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Engestrom2011-yr
Engeström, Y., &amp;amp; Sannino, A. (2011). Discursive manifestations of contradictions in organizational change efforts: A methodological framework. Journal of Organizational Change Management, 24(3), 368–387. https://doi.org/10.1108/09534811111132758
Notes Summarize: This paper clarifies the concept of contradiction in activity theory and introduces a methodology for identifying contradictions reflected in discourse of an organization. &amp;ldquo;Four types of discursive manifestations, namely dilemmas, conflicts, critical conflicts, and double binds, could be effectively identified in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Engeström. (2000). Activity theory as a framework for analyzing and redesigning work</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-03-24-engestrom2000-yq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-03-24-engestrom2000-yq/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Engestrom2000-yq
Engeström, Y. (2000). Activity theory as a framework for analyzing and redesigning work. Ergonomics, 43(7), 960–974. https://doi.org/10.1080/001401300409143
Notes Summarize: Engeström expands on the notion of knotworking in this article, in comparison with the 1993 article. This is especially relevant to critical moments of knowledge creation. A bit surprising there has been not much uptake of this concept in KB research.
The notion of constant co-configuration is also interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: FARMTASIA: an online game-based learning environment based on the VISOLE pedagogy</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-05-25-cheung2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-05-25-cheung2008/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @cheung2008
Cheung, K. K. F., Jong, M. S. Y., Lee, F. L., Lee, J. H. M., Luk, E. T. H., Shang, J., &amp;amp; Wong, M. K. H. (2008). FARMTASIA: an online game-based learning environment based on the VISOLE pedagogy. Virtual Reality, 12(1), 17–25. doi:10.1007/s10055-008-0084-z
Clippings Virtual interactive student-oriented learning environment (VISOLE) is a game-based constructivist pedagogical approach that encompasses the creation of an online interactive world modeled upon a set of interdisciplinary domains, in which students participate as ‘‘citizens’’ to take part cooperatively and competitively in shaping the development of the virtual world as a means to construct their knowledge and skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Factor Structure of the Adult Attitudes Toward Adult and Continuing Education Scale and its Capacity to Predict Participation Behavior: Evidence for Adoption of a Revised Scale</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-18-blunt02factor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-18-blunt02factor/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @blunt02factor
Blunt A and Yang B (2002). “Factor Structure of the Adult Attitudes Toward Adult and Continuing Education Scale and its Capacityt O Predict Participation Behavior: Evidence for Adoption of a Revised Scale.” Adult Education Quarterly, 52(4), pp. 299-314. , http://aeq.sagepub.com/content/52/4/299.full.pdf+html, .
Notes Briefly, this paper trim the widely used AACES from 22 items to 9 items and further checked the revised instrument&amp;rsquo;s validity and reliability and predictive strength.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ferguson - 2012 - Social learning analytics</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-19-ferguson2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-19-ferguson2012/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ferguson2012
Ferguson, R., &amp;amp; Shum, S. B. (2012). Social learning analytics. In Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Learning Analytics and Knowledge - LAK ’12 (p. 23). New York, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;2330601.2330616
Notes People commonly misinterpret social learning analytics as social network analysis. This article addresses this misinterpretation.
Highlights the perspective from that of the institution gathering data about learners in order to inform organisational objectives, to that of providing new tools for the learner and teacher, drawing on experience from the learning sciences with the intention of understanding and optimizing not only learning but also the environments in which it takes place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Flyvbjerg, B. (2006). Five Misunderstandings About Case-Study Research</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-18-flyvbjerg2006-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-18-flyvbjerg2006-eu/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Flyvbjerg2006-eu
Flyvbjerg, B. (2006). Five Misunderstandings About Case-Study Research. Qualitative Inquiry: QI, 12(2), 219–245. https://doi.org/10.1177/1077800405284363
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights This article examines five common misunderstandings about case-study research: (a) theoretical knowledge is more valuable than practical knowledge; (b) one cannot generalize from a single case, therefore, the single-case study cannot contribute to scientific development; &amp;copy; the case study is most useful for generating hypotheses, whereas other methods are more suitable for hypotheses testing and theory building; (d) the case study contains a bias toward verification; and (e) it is often difficult to summarize specific case stud- ies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ford-Connors - 2015 - Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-11-ford-connors2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-11-ford-connors2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ford-Connors2015
Ford-Connors, E., &amp;amp; Paratore, J. R. (2015). Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond: Sources of Word Learning and Productive Contexts for Development. Review of Educational Research, 85(1), 50–91. doi:10.3102&amp;frasl;0034654314540943
Notes This article provides a comprehensive and balanced review of vocabulary instruction focusing on two aspects: (1) sources of word learning, and (2) productive contexts for vocabulary learning. This review is based upon the notion that word learning is complex, multidimensional, and incremental.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ford-Connors2015-dd: Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond: Sources of Word Learning and Productive Contexts for Development</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-18-ford-connors2015-dd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-18-ford-connors2015-dd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ford-Connors2015-dd
Ford-Connors, E., &amp;amp; Paratore, J. R. (2015). Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond: Sources of Word Learning and Productive Contexts for Development. Review of Educational Research, 85(1), 50–91. https://doi.org/10.3102/0034654314540943
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Synthesizing the literature around the general topics of vocabu- lary instruction, classroom discourse, and teacher talk, this review provides a comprehensive and critical examination of instruction that supports vocab- ulary learning in older students with a particular focus on practices that promote productive discussions of content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Fostering epistemological beliefs and conceptual change in chemistry using knowledge building</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-10-04-lam2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-10-04-lam2008/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @lam2008
Lam, I., &amp;amp; Chan, C. K. K. (2008). Fostering epistemological beliefs and conceptual change in chemistry using knowledge building. In Proceedings of the 8th international conference on International conference for the learning sciences Volume 1 (Vol. 1, pp. 461–468). Utrecht, The Netherlands: International Society of the Learning Sciences. Retrieved from http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1599812.1599868
Clippings Abstract:
Various measures were collected at pre and posttests including epistemological beliefs, conceptual-change questions and online discourse and reflection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Game-like learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-05-25-gee2008game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-05-25-gee2008game/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @gee2008game
Gee, J. P. (2008). Game-like learning: An example of situated learning and implications for opportunity to learn. Assessment, equity, and opportunity to learn, 200–221.
Clippings Game-Like Learning (p. 1)
knowledge: as noun and verb (p. 1)
The theory of learning in many schools today is based on what I would call the “content fetish” (Gee 2004). The content fetish is the view that any academic area (whether physics, sociology, or history) is composed of a set of facts or a body of information and that the way learning should work is through teaching and testing such facts and information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Gasevic - 2014 - Where is research on massive open online courses headed</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-10-12-gasevic2014-ki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-10-12-gasevic2014-ki/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Gasevic2014-ki
Gasevic, D., Kovanovic, V., Joksimovic, S., &amp;amp; Siemens, G. (2014). Where is research on massive open online courses headed? A data analysis of the MOOC Research Initiative. The International Review Of Research In Open And Distributed Learning, 15(5), 134–176.
Notes Summarize: This review is unique compared to typical literature analysis as it focuses on grant proposals submitted to the MRI initiative. Applying a wide range of analytical techniques, this paper uncovers key themes, leading authors (being cited in proposals), representation of disciplines, status of interdisciplinarity, and the impact of the breadth of coverage (defined by SNA measures of resulting citation networks within clusters of disciplines) on likelihood of being funded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Gee Melbourne talk</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-05-26-gee-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-05-26-gee-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @gee-melbourne
Link: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=17JvW0nnr48&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded
Notes the exciting combination of consumption and creation
 all video games are rule systems about shapes, movements, and combinations. but what would happen if I gave each shape, movement, and combination of shapes in Tetris a meaning? story elements: actors, actions; states, events grammar  games as literacy * what&amp;rsquo;s the role of story in games? * Casovilia: story doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. * The primary thing here is the player&amp;rsquo;s production of story elements, not a story per se (like Alucard kills a Sword Lord).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Genetic epistemology</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-06-piaget1970genetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-06-piaget1970genetic/</guid>
      <description>References Piaget, J. (1970). Genetic epistemology. New York, NY, US: Columbia University Press.
Citekey: @piaget1970genetic
Notes  Piaget&amp;rsquo;s presents a &amp;ldquo;genetic epistemology&amp;rdquo; in that he elaborates how our understanding of knowledge (epistemology) develops in actual people (children) instead of simply as an abstract philosophy based on our adult intuitions about knowledge (the traditional epistemological approach).
According to Jean Piaget, genetic epistemology &amp;ldquo;attempts to explain knowledge, and in particular scientific knowledge, on the basis of its history, its sociogenesis, and especially the psychological origins of the notions and operations upon which it is based&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Goel. (2014). Predicting Individual Behavior with Social Networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-09-30-goel2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-09-30-goel2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Goel2014
Goel, S., &amp;amp; Goldstein, D. G. (2014). Predicting Individual Behavior with Social Networks. Marketing Science, 33(1), 82–93. doi:10.1287/mksc.2013.0817
Notes Highlights For over a decade, online marketers have predicted behavior at the individual level using variables such as age and sex (demographic targeting), location (geographic targeting), and website usage patterns (behavioral targeting). Today, ad servers can respond to the text of the page being viewed, be it a news story or personal email, and deliver ads on the fly that match page content (contextual targeting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Graesser - 2011 - Coh-Metrix</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-17-graesser2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-17-graesser2011/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Graesser2011
Graesser, A. C., McNamara, D. S., &amp;amp; Kulikowich, J. M. (2011). Coh-Metrix: Providing Multilevel Analyses of Text Characteristics. Educational Researcher, 40(5), 223–234. doi:10.3102/0013189X11413260
Notes An overview of measures provided by Coh-Metrix.
Highlights Two important caveats must be raised before describing the computer analyses of text characteristics. First, computers obviously cannot identify and scale texts on all levels of language, discourse, and meaning. Available computer systems cannot fully comprehend the deep metaphors, literary devices, and historical contexts of Shakespeare’s plays, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Gruzd - 2013 - Enabling community through social media</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-03-30-gruzd2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-03-30-gruzd2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Gruzd2013
Gruzd, A., &amp;amp; Haythornthwaite, C. (2013). Enabling community through social media. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 15(10). doi:10.2196/jmir.2796
Notes Highlights Pescosolido [19] has suggested that a network-centered view of health, based on social network principles, can act as a bridge between medical sciences and individual health experience. Her ideas respond to an increasing recognition of the impact of connectivity and experience: “The individual is seen as embedded in an ongoing relational dynamic with sequences of events seen as patterned, contingent and emergent” (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Guo. (2014). Demographic Differences in How Students Navigate Through MOOCs</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-26-guo2014-ve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-26-guo2014-ve/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Guo2014-ve
Guo, P. J., &amp;amp; Reinecke, K. (2014). Demographic Differences in How Students Navigate Through MOOCs. In Proceedings of the First ACM Conference on Learning @ Scale Conference (pp. 21–30). New York, NY, USA: ACM.
Notes A nice study exploring demographic differences (age, gender, country origin) among MOOC learners. Interesting findings that many learners skipped a significant portion of course content, navigated in a non-linear manner, etc., pointing to opportunities for future research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Gutiérrez &amp; Penuel (2014). Relevance to Practice as a Criterion for Rigor</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-23-gutierrez2014-qm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-23-gutierrez2014-qm/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Gutierrez2014-qm
Gutiérrez, K. D., &amp;amp; Penuel, W. R. (2014). Relevance to Practice as a Criterion for Rigor. Educational Researcher , 43(1), 19–23.
Notes Highlights The authors argue for a reconceptualization of rigor that requires sustained, direct, and systematic documentation of what takes place inside programs to document how students and teachers change and adapt interventions in interactions with each other in relation to their dynamic local contexts. (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hakkarainen, K. (2003). Emergence of progressive-inquiry culture in computer-supported collaborative learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-01-hakkarainen2003a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-01-hakkarainen2003a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hakkarainen2003a
Hakkarainen, K. (2003). Emergence of progressive-inquiry culture in computer-supported collaborative learning. Learning Environments Research, 6(2), 199–220. doi:10.1023/a:1024995120180
Notes Highlights ABSTRACT. The study focused on analysing the emergence of a progressive-inquiry culture in two CSILE (Computer-Supported Intentional Learning Environment) classrooms across a three-year period. A principal feature of this kind of culture is the processing of explanatory knowledge instead of merely factual knowledge. The results of the study indicate that the classroom culture changed over the three years following the introduction of CSILE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Haneda, M., &amp; Wells, G. (2000). Writing in knowledge-building communities</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-26-haneda2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-26-haneda2000/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Haneda2000
Haneda, M., &amp;amp; Wells, G. (2000). Writing in knowledge-building communities. Research in the Teaching of English, 34(3), 430–457. Retrieved from http://www.jstor.org/stable/40171501
Notes This position piece articulates how writing is perceived and supported in knowledge building. It presents a thorough discussion of &amp;ldquo;current&amp;rdquo; understanding in writing, gaps in writing instruction, and the role Knowledge Building plays in writing (and roles writing plays in knowledge building). It also presents three examples of writing in knowledge building communities, in which roles of teachers and technology are explored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hewitt, J., &amp; Scardamalia, M. (1998). Design principles for distributed knowledge building processes</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-22-hewitt1998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-22-hewitt1998/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hewitt1998
Hewitt, J., &amp;amp; Scardamalia, M. (1998). Design principles for distributed knowledge building processes. Educational Psychology Review, 10(1), 75–96. doi:10.1023/A:1022810231840
Notes A great review article (sort of) that summarizes design principles of knowledge-building communities in the late 90s. Interesting insights into the historical development of KB as an ed approach.
Highlights In this paper we explore various interpretations of the term &amp;ldquo;distributed cognition,&amp;rdquo; then turn our attention to communities grounded in the practice of collaborative knowledge building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hickey. (2010). Participatory assessment of 21st century proficiencies</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-06-24-shute2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-06-24-shute2010/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hickey2010
Hickey, D. T., Honeyford, M. A., Clinton, K. A., &amp;amp; McWilliams, J. (2010). Participatory assessment of 21st century proficiencies. In V. J. Shute &amp;amp; B. J. Becker (Eds.), Innovative assessment for the 21st century (pp. 107–138). Springer. doi:10.1007&amp;frasl;978-1-4419-6530-1
Notes Highlights 8.1 New Media the Technology Proficiencies and Schools (p. 109)
Recent studies reveal the tremendous levels of “hanging out, messing around, and geeking out” in friendship-driven and interest-driven social networks (Ito, 2008).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hickey. (2011). Reading Moby-Dick in a Participatory Culture</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-06-24-hickey2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-06-24-hickey2011/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hickey2011
Hickey, D. T., McWilliams, J., &amp;amp; Honeyford, M. A. (2011). Reading Moby-Dick in a Participatory Culture: Organizing Assessment for Engagement in a New Media Era. Journal of Educational Computing Research, 45(2), 247–263. doi:10.2190/EC.45.2.g
Notes Highlights This article identifies discrepancies between traditional instructional practices that emphasize individual mastery of abstract concepts and skills and new media literacy practices that rely upon collaborative, social, and context-specific activity. (p. 1)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Higher Levels of Agency for Children in Knowledge Building</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-28-scardamalia1991/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-28-scardamalia1991/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia1991
Scardamalia, M., &amp;amp; Bereiter, C. (1991). Higher Levels of Agency for Children in Knowledge Building: A Challenge for the Design of New Knowledge Media. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 1(1), 37–68. doi:10.1207/s15327809jls0101_3
Notes This paper is particularly useful: * It connects agency with ZPD, and makes it clear KB turns more agency to students and lets students decide ZPD. * It reports a set of interesting studies on student questioning, especially the one examining whether students can pick promising questions from those generated by themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hoff - 2002 - How children use input to acquire a lexicon</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-11-04-hoff2002children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-11-04-hoff2002children/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @hoff2002children
Hoff E and Naigles L (2002). “How children use input to acquire a lexicon.” Child development, 73(2), pp. 418-433.
Notes Highlights The process of acquiring a lexicon is clearly a process of learning from experience, and the relevant experience must be conversational interaction, because that is the context in which exposure to language occurs. (p. 1)
The Social–Pragmatic View of the Role of Input (p. 1)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: How scientists really reason</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-06-05-dunbar1995/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-06-05-dunbar1995/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @dunbar1995
Dunbar, K. N. (1995). How scientists really reason: Scientific reasoning in real-world laboratories. In R. J. Sternberg &amp;amp; J. Davidson (Eds.), The Nature of Insight (pp. 365–395). MIT Press.
Notes http://cognet.mit.edu/library/books/mitpress/0262691876/cache/chpt11.pdf
Two approaches: in vitro and in vivo.
This chapter focuses on in vivo study.
Mechanisms underlying conceptual change: 1. (how scientists treat) inconsistent results 2. analogy, esp. local and reginal analogies 3.fruitful analogies call for different sources of knowledge of lab members 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hwang. (2007). A study of multimedia annotation of Web-based materials</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-15-hwang2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-15-hwang2007/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hwang2007
Hwang, W.-Y., Wang, C.-Y., &amp;amp; Sharples, M. (2007). A study of multimedia annotation of Web-based materials. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 48(4), 680–699. doi:10.1016/j.compedu.2005.04.020
Notes Highlights We describe a Web-based tool for creating and sharing annotations and investigate the eVect on learning of its use with college students. First, an annotation tool was designed and implemented for the research. Second, learning support mechanisms, including full and group annotation sharing, were developed to promote students’ motivation for annotation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Identifying Learning Behaviors by Contextualizing Differential Sequence Mining with Action Features and Performance Evolution</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-04-30-kinnebrew2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-04-30-kinnebrew2012/</guid>
      <description>References Kinnebrew, J., &amp;amp; Biswas, G. (2012). Identifying Learning Behaviors by Contextualizing Differential Sequence Mining with Action Features and Performance Evolution. In the 5th International Conference on Educational Data Mining (pp. 57–64). Retrieved from http://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED537192.pdf
Citekey: @Kinnebrew2012
Highlights The core algorithm employs sequence mining techniques to identify differentially frequent patterns between two predefined groups. (p. 1)
In developing a computer-based learning environment (CBLE) called Betty’s Brain, we have adopted a self-regulated learning (SRL) framework to help students develop learning strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Improving conceptual change concerning photosynthesis through text design</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-06-07-mikkila-erdmann2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-06-07-mikkila-erdmann2001/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @mikkila-erdmann2001
Mikkilä-Erdmann, M. (2001). Improving conceptual change concerning photosynthesis through text design. Learning and Instruction, 11(3), 241–257. doi:10.1016/S0959-4752(00)00041-4
Notes Literature review * the simplest form of conceptual change: enrichment&amp;ndash;accumulation on the level of specific theory * revision: reorganization of knowledge on the level of the framework theory&amp;mdash;so more difficult and need specific instruction * problem: students are not aware the contradiction, so tend to enrich rather than revise them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Introduction to the Special Issue on Learning Analytics</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-11-05-haythornthwaite2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-11-05-haythornthwaite2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @haythornthwaite2013
Haythornthwaite, C., de Laat, M., &amp;amp; Dawson, S. (2013). Introduction to the Special Issue on Learning Analytics. American Behavioral Scientist, 57(10), 1371–1379. doi:10.1177&amp;frasl;0002764213498850
Summary An intro to [[http://abs.sagepub.com/content/57/10.toc|a special issue of LA]] on the //Social Sciences, Interdisciplinary// journal. Also a nice brief intro to the field of LA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Jiang. (2013). Mining the Temporal Evolution of the Android Bug Reporting Community via Sliding Windows</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-10-02-jiang2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-10-02-jiang2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Jiang2013
Jiang, F., Wang, J., Hindle, A., &amp;amp; Nascimento, M. A. (2013). Mining the Temporal Evolution of the Android Bug Reporting Community via Sliding Windows. CoRR, abs/1310.7. Retrieved from http://arxiv.org/abs/1310.7469
Notes This paper reports a study of applying an interesting sliding-windows social network analysis on Android bug reporting community. This technique shows clear advantage in comparison with global analysis of social networks in that it takes temporal information into consideration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Johnson - 2014 - The ethics of big data in higher education</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-12-09-johnson2014ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-12-09-johnson2014ethics/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @johnson2014ethics
Johnson, J. A. (2014). The ethics of big data in higher education. International Review of Information Ethics, 7:3–10.
Notes Highlights The immediate challenge considers the extent to which data mining’s outcomes are themselves ethical with respect to both individuals and institutions. A deep challenge, not readily apparent to institutional researchers or administrators, considers the implications of uncritical understanding of the scientific basis of data mining. (p. 1)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Johnson2004-cv</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-10-19-johnson2004-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-10-19-johnson2004-cv/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Johnson2004-cv
NA
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights The purposes of this article are to position mixed methods research (mixed research is a synonym) as the natural complement to tradi- tional qualitative and quantitative research, to present pragmatism as offering an attractive philosophical partner for mixed methods re- search, and to provide a framework for designing and conducting mixed methods research. (p. 1)
Qualitative purists (also called constructivists and interpretivists) reject what they call positivism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Jonassen-1999-Activity theory as a framework for designing constructivist learning environments</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-03-10-jonassen1999-dz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-03-10-jonassen1999-dz/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Jonassen1999-dz
Jonassen, D. H., &amp;amp; Rohrer-Murphy, L. (1999). Activity theory as a framework for designing constructivist learning environments. Educational Technology Research and Development, 47(1), 61–79. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF02299477
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Activ- ity theory is a socio-cultural, socio-historical lens through which designers can analyze human activity systems. It focuses on the inter- action of human activity and consciousness within its relevant environmental context. (p. 1)
Activity the- ory posits that conscious learning emerges from activity (performance), not as a precursor to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ke, F. (2008). A case study of computer gaming for math: Engaged learning from gameplay?</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-08-18-ke2008-hw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-08-18-ke2008-hw/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ke2008-hw
Ke, F. (2008). A case study of computer gaming for math: Engaged learning from gameplay? Computers &amp;amp; Education, 51(4), 1609–1620. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2008.03.003
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Therefore, the key question remains misty: Do computer games really foster an engaging, effective learning experience in classrooms? (p. 2)
Quite a few current researchers shy away from drill and practice games and have claimed them as not equally effective in improving learning and skills in comparison to other game genres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Kennedy (2016) Open Annotation and Close Reading the Victorian Text: Using Hypothes.is with Students</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-03-kennedy2016-qw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-03-kennedy2016-qw/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Kennedy2016-qw
Meegan Kennedy (2016): Open Annotation and Close Readingthe Victorian Text: Using Hypothes.is with Students, Journal of Victorian Culture, DOI:10.1080&amp;frasl;13555502.2016.1233905
Notes Summarize: This commentary introduces an instructor&amp;rsquo;s thoughts and experiences in integrating Hyphthes.is, an open annotation tool, into an undergrad course.
Assess: Thorough intro to all kinds of considerations that would inform another instructor&amp;rsquo;s design efforts.
Reflect: I&amp;rsquo;m planning on using H in my SNA class, so this piece is very helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Kerres Malecki. (2003). Carrying a weapon to school and perceptions of social support in an urban middle school</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-15-kerresmalecki2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-15-kerresmalecki2003/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @KerresMalecki2003
Kerres Malecki, C., &amp;amp; Kilpatrick Demaray, M. (2003). Carrying a weapon to school and perceptions of social support in an urban middle school. Journal of Emotional and Behavioral Disorders, 11(3), 169–178. http://doi.org/10.1177/10634266030110030401
Notes Notes to me as an instructor:
 Stats involved in this paper  descriptive analysis ANOVA MANOVA logistic regression internal consistency as measured by alpha coefficient  Discussion points  roles of quantitative analyses limitations of this study next steps of research you can think of?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Kinnebrew2013-A Contextualized, Differential Sequence Mining Method to Derive Students’ Learning Behavior Patterns</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-26-kinnebrew2013-de/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-26-kinnebrew2013-de/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Kinnebrew2013-de
Kinnebrew, J. S., Loretz, K. M., &amp;amp; Biswas, G. (2013). A Contextualized, Differential Sequence Mining Method to Derive Students’ Learning Behavior Patterns. JEDM - Journal of Educational Data Mining, 5(1), 190–219.
Notes Highlights The core algorithm employs a novel combination of sequence mining techniques to identify di erentially frequent patterns between groups of students (e.g., experimental versus control conditions or high versus low performers). We extend this technique by contextualizing the sequence mining with information about the stu- dent&amp;rsquo;s performance over the course of the learning interactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Knowledge Building Discourse Explorer</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-04-10-oshima2012a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-04-10-oshima2012a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @oshima2012a
Oshima, J., Oshima, R., &amp;amp; Matsuzawa, Y. (2012). Knowledge Building Discourse Explorer: a social network analysis application for knowledge building discourse. Educational Technology Research and Development. doi:10.1007/s11423-012-9265-2
Notes Rough summary I got to know KBDeX two years ago. This paper is very helpful for understanding the power of this tool to support assessment for knowledge creation. Before reading it, I was thinking of KBDeX as just another analytic tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Knowledge Building as a Mediator of Conflict in Conceptual Change</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-09-28-chan1997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-09-28-chan1997/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @chan1997
Chan, C. K. K., Burtis, J., &amp;amp; Bereiter, C. (1997). Knowledge Building as a Mediator of Conflict in Conceptual Change. Cognition and Instruction (Vol. 15, pp. 1–40). doi:10.1207/s1532690xci1501_1
Abstract This study examined how individuals and peers process scientific information that contradicts what they believe and assessed the contribution of this activity to conceptual change. Participants included 54 students in Grade 9 and 54 students in Grade 12, who were randomly assigned to four conditions: (a) individual conflict, (b) peer conflict, &amp;copy; individual assimilation, and (d) peer assimilation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Knowledge Forum: altering the relationship between students and scientific knowledge</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-10-07-caswell2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-10-07-caswell2002/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @caswell2002
Caswell, B., &amp;amp; Bielaczyc, K. (2002). Knowledge Forum: altering the relationship between students and scientific knowledge. Education, Communication &amp;amp; Information, 1(3), 281–305. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;146363102753535240
Clips ABSTRACT This paper explores the use of Knowledge Forum, a networked computer program designed to support knowledge building communication and to foster thinking and learning skills. The paper focuses on a Grade 5&amp;frasl;6 classroom and looks at how students view scientic knowledge and what it means to learn science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Knowledge building: Theory, pedagogy, and technology</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia2006
Scardamalia, M., &amp;amp; Bereiter, C. (2006). Knowledge building: Theory, pedagogy, and technology. In R. K. Sawyer (Ed.), The Cambridge handbook of the learning sciences (pp. 97–115). Cambridge University Press.
Notes From Computer Supported Intentional Learning to Knowledge Building Environments  an elementary school (Scardamalia, Bereiter, McLean, Swallow, and Woodruff, 1989).   an elementary school (Scardamalia, Bereiter, McLean, Swallow, and Woodruff, 1989).   an elementary school (Scardamalia, Bereiter, McLean, Swallow, and Woodruff, 1989).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Kress - 2009 - Multimodality: A social semiotic approach to contemporary communication</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-26-kress2009multimodality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-26-kress2009multimodality/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @kress2009multimodality
Kress, G. (2009). Multimodality: A social semiotic approach to contemporary communication. New York, NY: Routledge.
Notes Disclaimer: The highlights are from a book review rather than the book itself. Sounds like a worthwhile read. Getting the book soon&amp;hellip;
Highlights Writing about multimodality requires defining “mode,” but this is notoriously difficult (cf. Forceville 2006, Elleström 2010). Kress advocates a dynamic view: “socially, what counts as mode is a matter for a community and its social representational needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Kress - 2009 - Multimodality: A social semiotic approach to contemporary communication</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-26-r-graphics-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-26-r-graphics-talk/</guid>
      <description>Interactive graphics Hadley Wickham
 linked brushes  Abuse the browser based on htmlwidgets for R: http://www.htmlwidgets.org/ - http://bwlewis.github.io/rthreejs/ - leeflet - dygraphs
ggvis - ggplot2 + interactivity
Winston Chang Shiny</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Kucirkova. (2015). A Vygotskian perspective on parent-child talk during iPad story sharing</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-11-kucirkova2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-11-kucirkova2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Kucirkova2015
Kucirkova, N., Sheehy, K., &amp;amp; Messer, D. (2015). A Vygotskian perspective on parent-child talk during iPad story sharing. Journal of Research in Reading, 38(4), 428–441. doi:10.1111&amp;frasl;1467-9817.12030
Notes An interesting study exploring themes of interactions in parent-child talk during iPad story sharing/creation. The analysis was largely informed by Vygotsky’s learning theory focusing on ZPD, dual representation and double stimulation. While results offer insights about parent-child talk in an interesting story-creation iPad app (something less common in traditional storytelling reading research), this study also challenges the Vygotskian frame&amp;rsquo;s explanatory power in this novel context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Kuhn2012-qo The structure of scientific revolutions</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-13-kuhn2012-qo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-13-kuhn2012-qo/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Kuhn2012-qo
Kuhn, T. S. (2012). The structure of scientific revolutions (4th ed.). Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press. Retrieved from https://books.google.com/books?id=3eP5Y_OOuzwC
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights A footnote encountered by chance led me to the experiments by which Jean Piaget has illuminated both the various worlds of the 2growing child and the process of transition from one to the next.2 One of my colleagues set me to reading pape rs in the psychology of perception, my colleagues set me to reading pape rs in the psychology of perception, particularly the Gestalt psychologists ; another introduced me to B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: LAe-R</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-08-29-petropoulou2014lae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-08-29-petropoulou2014lae/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @petropoulou2014lae
Petropoulou, O., Kasimatis, K., Dimopoulos, I., and Retalis, S. (2014). Lae-r: A new learning analytics tool in moodle for assessing students’ performance. Bulletin of the IEEE Technical Committee on Learning Technology, 16(1):1.
Notes The short paper introduces Learning Analytics Enriched Rubric (LAe-R), an assessment plugin in Moodle. One unique thing about this tool is it allows the teacher to create rubrics by themselves and map aspects of learning with specific activities in Moodle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ladson-Billings, G. (2006). From the achievement gap to the education debt</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-01-ladson-billings2006-um/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-01-ladson-billings2006-um/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ladson-Billings2006-um
Ladson-Billings, G. (2006). From the achievement gap to the education debt: Understanding achievement in U.S. schools. Educational Researcher, 35(7), 3–12.
Notes This is a powerful piece illuminating the issue with the achievement gap &amp;ndash; or, for a better phrase, education debt &amp;ndash; in the US. By tracing down the roots of the education debt, it paints a wholer picture of the problem, esp. for a foreigner like myself who does not share the collective memories mentioned in the paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Latent class analysis of early reading skills</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-09-26-sainsbury2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-09-26-sainsbury2011/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @sainsbury2011
Sainsbury, M., &amp;amp; Benton, T. (2011). Designing a formative e-assessment: Latent class analysis of early reading skills. British Journal Of Educational Technology, 42(3), 500–514. doi:10.1111/j.1467-8535.2009.01044.x
Notes This article is interesting in that it explores computer-based formative assessment based on traditionally designed item-based test. It applies an interesting technique, Latent Class Analysis/model, to classfy students into different groups. Based on charactersitics of those groups, the system could produce profiles that could inform instruction of teachers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Laufer - 1994 - The Lexical Profile of Second Language Writing: Does It Change Over Time?</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-10-30-laufer01121994/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-10-30-laufer01121994/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Laufer01121994
Laufer B (1994). “The Lexical Profile of Second Language Writing: Does It Change Over Time?” RELC Journal, 25(2), pp. 21-33. , http://rel.sagepub.com/content/25/2/21.full.pdf+html, .
Notes One of the classic studies by Laufer around Lexical Frequency Profile.
Highlights lexical richness, (p. 2)
lexical variation. (p. 2)
lexical acquisition research would have to account for the gradual increase in the learner’s vocabulary size, as the most striking difference between the vocabulary of native speakers and that of language learners is in the number of words they can control, particularly in free production: speech or writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Laufer - 2013 - Lexical Frequency Profiles</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-11-04-laufer2013lexical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-11-04-laufer2013lexical/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @laufer2013lexical
Laufer B (2013). “Lexical Frequency Profiles.” In Chapelle CA (ed.), The Encyclopedia of Applied Linguistics. Blackwell Publishing Ltd.
Notes A encyclopedia entry about Lexical Frequency Profiles. Laufer explains the assumption, concepts, and tools nicely.
 Assumption: A large number of infrequent words would make a text more difficult to understand. More advanced learners could use a higher percentage of infrequent vocabulary than learners of lower proficiencies. Concepts: Knowledge is taken to be the information about a word which is stored and interconnected in the mental lexicon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lee. (2011). Computational thinking for youth in practice</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-10-01-denner2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-10-01-denner2011/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Denner2011
Lee, I., Martin, F., Denner, J., Coulter, B., Allan, W., Erickson, J., … Werner, L. (2011). Computational thinking for youth in practice. ACM Inroads, 2(1), 32. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;1929887.1929902
Notes Highlights Key questions include: ■ What does computational thinking for youth look like in practice? ■ How can we support growth in computational thinking, both in and out of school? (p. 1)
INTRODUCTION Computational thinking (CT) is a term coined by Jeannette Wing [11] to describe a set of thinking skills, habits and approaches that are integral to solving complex problems using a computer and widely applicable in the information society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lee. (2016). Social network analysis of peer relationships and online interactions in a blended class using blogs</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-24-lee2016-ys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-24-lee2016-ys/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lee2016-ys
Lee, J., &amp;amp; Bonk, C. J. (2016). Social network analysis of peer relationships and online interactions in a blended class using blogs. The Internet and Higher Education, 28, 35–44.
Notes An interesting study exploring the relationships between perceived closeness between students and their actual interactions on blogs. Some explanations of SNA are questionable, so are the interpretation of several SNA results. For instance, comparisons of network measures over time should come after an explicit explanation of network construction (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lee2013-sl: Science and language for English language learners in relation to Next Generation Science Standards and with implications for Common Core State Standards for English language arts and mathematics</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2013-sl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2013-sl/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lee2013-sl
Lee, O., Quinn, H., &amp;amp; Valdés, G. (2013). Science and language for English language learners in relation to Next Generation Science Standards and with implications for Common Core State Standards for English language arts and mathematics. Educational Researcher , 42(4), 223–233. Retrieved from http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X13480524
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights By examining intersections between learning of science and learning of language, the article identifies key features of the language of the science classroom as students engage in these language-intensive science and engineering practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lee2017-xm: Common Core State Standards for ELA/Literacy and Next Generation Science Standards</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2017-xm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2017-xm/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lee2017-xm
Lee, O. (2017). Common Core State Standards for ELA/Literacy and Next Generation Science Standards: Convergences and Discrepancies Using Argument as an Example. Educational Researcher , 46(2), 90–102. Retrieved from http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X17699172
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Unlike pre-CCSS standards developed within each subject area, the new standards highlight connections across subject areas (Stage, Asturias, Cheuk, Daro, &amp;amp; Hampton, 2013). (p. 1)
While ELA is traditionally associated with literary texts, the CCSS emphasize informational texts (Pearson, 2013) (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lin. (2013). Online formative assessments with social network awareness</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-14-lin2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-14-lin2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lin2013
Lin, J.-W., &amp;amp; Lai, Y.-C. (2013). Online formative assessments with social network awareness. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 66, 40–53. doi:10.1016/j.compedu.2013.02.008
Notes This paper reports an interesting SNA-based system that recommend peer helpers based on friendship statuses (&amp;lsquo;social context&amp;rsquo; as called by the authors) and results of &amp;lsquo;formative assessment&amp;rsquo; (i.e., results of a formative test; &amp;lsquo;knowledge context&amp;rsquo; as called by the authors). The tool, SNAFA, engages students in 1) self-report information including friendship statuses, 2) take a test, and 3) review recommended peer helpers to seek help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Linguistic Reflections of Student Engagement in Massive Open Online Courses</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-01-wen2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-01-wen2014/</guid>
      <description>References Wen, M., Yang, D., &amp;amp; Rose, C. P. (2014). Linguistic Reflections of Student Engagement in Massive Open Online Courses. In ICWSM’14.
Citekey: @Wen2014
Notes  This paper introduces a novel approach to use linguistic features to measure student motivation and cognitive engagement (two important aspects for learning) in MOOC discussion forum.
 Highlights &amp;ldquo;Based on the learning sciences literature, we quantify a student’s level of engagement in a MOOC from two different angles: (1) displayed level of motivation to continue with the course and (2) the level of cognitive engagement with the learning material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Littlejohn - 2016 - Learning in MOOCs: Motivations and self-regulated learning in MOOCs</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-26-littlejohn2016-um/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-26-littlejohn2016-um/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Littlejohn2016-um
Littlejohn, A., Hood, N., Milligan, C., &amp;amp; Mustain, P. (2016&amp;frasl;4). Learning in MOOCs: Motivations and self-regulated learning in MOOCs. The Internet and Higher Education, 29, 40–48.
Notes Nice research investigating SRL in MOOCs. Survey used for measuring SRL of learners; interviews were used to understand learners in greater details.
No use of clicklog data to triangulate these findings could be a future direction.
Highlights Massive open online courses (MOOCs) require individual learners to be able to self-regulate their learning, determining when and how they engage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Liyanagunawardena-2013-A Systematic Study of the Published Literature 2008-2012</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-10-13-liyanagunawardena2013-ku/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-10-13-liyanagunawardena2013-ku/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Liyanagunawardena2013-ku
Liyanagunawardena, T. R., Adams, A. A., &amp;amp; Williams, S. A. (2013). MOOCs: A Systematic Study of the Published Literature 2008-2012. The International Review of Research in Open and Distributed Learning, 14(3), 202–227.
Notes Summarize: An early review of the MOOC literature. Forty-five peer reviewed papers are identified, using several different search strategies. Several glitches/hurdles were noted, such as other research using the same acronym. Quantitative analysis deals with pub year, counts in journals, leading authors, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lockyer. (2013). Informing Pedagogical Action</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-01-lockyer2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-01-lockyer2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lockyer2013
Lockyer, L., Heathcote, E., &amp;amp; Dawson, S. (2013). Informing Pedagogical Action: Aligning Learning Analytics With Learning Design. American Behavioral Scientist, 57(10), 1439–1459. doi:10.1177&amp;frasl;0002764213479367
Notes Learning design is a new area for me. But one critical point made in this article is that interpretation of learning analytics should be made in the context of pedagogical designs. This is a point that should not be neglected so often in learning analytics research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lopez-Meneses-2015-Analysis and Implications of the Impact of MOOC Movement in the Scientific Community: JCR and Scopus</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-10-13-lopez-meneses2015-ct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-10-13-lopez-meneses2015-ct/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lopez-Meneses2015-ct
López-Meneses, E., Vázquez-Cano, E., &amp;amp; Román-Graván, P. (2015). Analysis and Implications of the Impact of MOOC Movement in the Scientific Community: JCR and Scopus (2010-13). Comunicar, 22(44), 73–80.
Notes Summarize: One interesting approach used in this paper is key word network based on co-occurrence.
Assess: However, the extraction of dominant keywords did not offer significant insights in the discourse. The discussion mentioned that influential pieces in MOOCs exist in non-academic spaces like blogs, highlighting a tension among different spaces for scholarly communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lungeanu &amp; Contractor. (2015). The effects of diversity and network ties on innovations</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-14-lungeanu2015-mb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-14-lungeanu2015-mb/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lungeanu2015-mb
Lungeanu, A., &amp;amp; Contractor, N. S. (2015). The effects of diversity and network ties on innovations: The emergence of a new scientific field. The American Behavioral Scientist, 59(5), 548–564. https://doi.org/10.1177/0002764214556804
Notes Summarize: Very interesting study investigating factors impacting (reflected in) coauthorship relations in a new field. SIENA was used for the modeling of network dynamics. Key finding:
 Taken together with net findings about cognitive dissimilarity, this study suggests that innovation in networked research is most likely when teams draw on individuals with diverse knowledge resources, but who also have prior collaborations with each other or with common others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lv - 2011 - Towards Large-Scale Mobile Sensing and Analytics</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-28-lv2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-28-lv2011/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lv2011
Lv, Q. (2011). Towards Large-Scale Mobile Sensing and Analytics. Mobile Sensing: Challenges, Opportunities and Future Directions. UbiComp. Retrieved from http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/beijing/events/ms_ubicomp11/papers/lv.pdf
Notes Highlights The rapid adoption of smartphones and their increased sensing capabilities make it possible to collect a large amount of multi-modality mobile sensing data, which tend to be diverse, dynamic, and may vary significantly across users and applications. (p. 1)
In this paper, we identify the key characteristics and design challenges for large-scale mobile sensing and analytics, which are then demonstrated through three case studies in environmental monitoring, transportation electrification, and mobile video chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Macfadyen. (2012). Numbers are not enough</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-06-macfadyen2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-06-macfadyen2012/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Macfadyen2012
Macfadyen, L., &amp;amp; Dawson, S. (2012). Numbers are not enough. Why e-learning analytics failed to inform an institutional strategic plan. Journal of Educational Technology &amp;amp; Society, 15(3), 149–163.
Notes Highlights institutional level; academic analytics: Instead, the best institutional predictors of educational gain are “measures of educational process: what institutions do with their resources to make the most of whatever students they have” (Gibbs, 2010, p. 2). To investigate the impact, a longitudinal participant observation process (Douglas, 1976).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Malinick, T. E., Tindall, D. B., &amp; Diani, M. (2013). Network centrality and social movement media coverage</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-15-malinick2013-ub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-15-malinick2013-ub/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Malinick2013-ub
Malinick, T. E., Tindall, D. B., &amp;amp; Diani, M. (2013). Network centrality and social movement media coverage: A two-mode network analytic approach. Social Networks, 35(2), 148–158. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2011.10.005
Notes Summarize:
Reflect:
Highlights abstract This article examines the relationship between structural location (namely, degree centrality) and news media coverage. Our central hypothesis is that the network centrality of social movement actors is positively associated with the prevalence of actors being cited in the print news media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Mandinach. (2016). Teachers learning how to use data: A synthesis of the issues and what is known</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-12-mandinach2016a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-12-mandinach2016a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Mandinach2016a
Mandinach, E. B., &amp;amp; Jimerson, J. B. (2016). Teachers learning how to use data: A synthesis of the issues and what is known. Teaching and Teacher Education, 1–6. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.tate.2016.07.009
Notes This is an editorial of a very timely issue on data literacy of teachers, to be published in Teaching and Teacher Education. This editorial highlights several crosscutting concepts in this area: (a) the need for continuous learning around data e the where and when; (b) the need to integrate data skills with content knowledge and pedagogical content knowledge and link the data skills to other aspects of effective teaching; &amp;copy; the sustainability of impact; (d) models of effective professional learning and the impact of collaborative inquiry and data teaming; and (e) the logic model on impact of data use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Mandinach. (2016). What does it mean for teachers to be data literate</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-12-mandinach2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-12-mandinach2016/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Mandinach2016
Mandinach, E. B. (2016). What does it mean for teachers to be data literate: Laying out the skills, knowledge, and dispositions. Teaching and Teacher Education, 1–27. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.tate.2016.07.011
Notes A foundational piece in the special issue laying out an evolving framework of Data Literacy for Teachers (DLFT). This paper introduces the history of the framework, presents its components, and discusses next steps different parties should take to foster data literacy among teachers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Martínez. (2016). Promoting student metacognition through the analysis of their own debates</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-11-16-martinez2016-sz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-11-16-martinez2016-sz/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Martinez2016-sz
Martínez, M. L., &amp;amp; Valdivia, I. M. Á. (2016). Promoting student metacognition through the analysis of their own debates. Is it better with text or with graphics? Educational Technology &amp;amp; Society, 19(4), 167–177. Retrieved from http://www.jstor.org/stable/jeductechsoci.19.4.167
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights ABSTRACT This paper presents a higher education experience aimed at explicitly promoting metacognitive processes in a social and collaborative context. Students carried out a debate on an e-forum, and were later asked to collaboratively analyse their own debates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Mazza, R., &amp; Botturi, L. (2007). Monitoring an Online Course with the GISMO Tool</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-12-mazza2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-12-mazza2007/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Mazza2007
Mazza, R., &amp;amp; Botturi, L. (2007). Monitoring an Online Course with the GISMO Tool: A Case Study. Journal of Interactive Learning Research, 18(2), 251–265. Retrieved from http://www.editlib.org/?fuseaction=Reader.ViewFullText&amp;amp;paper_id=30472#page=100
Notes This paper introduces GISMO, an interesting visual analytics tool integrated into Moodle to support monitoring of learning activities. Activities tracked by GISMO are mostly behavioral (e.g., accessing course materials and posting/reading forum posts). By turning data into a range of (simple) visualizations GISMO could help the instructor (it&amp;rsquo;s only accessible to instructors) monitor students and find areas of the course to be redesigned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Mazza, R., &amp; Dimitrova, V. (2007). CourseVis</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-12-mazza2007a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-12-mazza2007a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Mazza2007a
Mazza, R., &amp;amp; Dimitrova, V. (2007). CourseVis: A graphical student monitoring tool for supporting instructors in web-based distance courses. International Journal of Human-Computer Studies, 65(2), 125–139. doi:10.1016/j.ijhcs.2006.08.008
Notes This paper introduces CoruseVis, a visual learning analytics system designed for WebCT. The design of CourseVis draws heavily from Information Visualization principles and (loosely) map with three identified aspects of learning, namely cognitive, social, and behavioral. A large portion of this paper reports on an evaluation study about the effectiveness, efficiency, and usefulness of CourseVis among instructors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Meara - 2000 - Lex30: an improved method of assessing productive vocabulary in an L2</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-11-09-meara2000lex30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-11-09-meara2000lex30/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @meara2000lex30
Meara P and Fitzpatrick T (2000). “Lex30: an improved method of assessing productive vocabulary in an L2.” System, 28(1), pp. 19-30.
Notes Highlights Unfortunately, it is much more dicult to assess productive vocabulary knowledge than it is to assess receptive vocabulary knowledge. The main reason for this is that the vocabulary produced by a learner, whether in written or spoken form, tends to be so context-speci®c that it is dicult to calculate from any small sample the true size or range of the learner&amp;rsquo;s productive vocabulary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Meara - 2001 - P-Lex: A Simple and Effective Way of Describing the lexical Characteristics of Short L2 Tests.</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-11-10-meara2001p/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-11-10-meara2001p/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @meara2001p
Meara P and Bell H (2001). “P-Lex: A Simple and Effective Way of Describing the lexical Characteristics of Short L2 Tests.” Prospect, 16(3), pp. 5-19.
Notes This article introduces a novel way to assess productive vocabulary &amp;ndash; P-LeX &amp;ndash; which is better at handling shorter text (in comparison with LFP) and easier to interpret.
Highlights ABSTRACT This paper describes an alternative approach to assessing the lexical complexity of short texts produced by second language learners of English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Michalak, R. (2016). Diigo</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-14-michalak2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-14-michalak2016/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Michalak2016
Michalak, R. (2016). Diigo. Technical Services Quarterly, 33(1), 96–97. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;07317131.2015.1093854
Notes As an experienced Diigo user (before), I found this intro not informative enough to illustrate the core philosophy of Diigo, that is to create another layer on top of web content. This intro focuses too much on the Library, which is important indeed, but does not talk enough about the social engagement piece that (co-)defines Diigo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Mor2015-kw</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-03-02-mor2015-kw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-03-02-mor2015-kw/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Mor2015-kw
NA
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights In most design disciplines there is usually a clear division of labour between designers, developers and evaluators. An architect designs a building, which a contractor builds. An inspector verifies that it meets all the required standards. (p. 1)
In Schön’s view, this is the antidote for what he calls the dilemma of abandonment: practitioners may feel, in relation to the academy, a sense of having been seduced and abandoned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Morris, M. (2003). Local Rules and Global Properties: Modeling the Emergence of Network Structure</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-15-morris2003-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-15-morris2003-pc/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Morris2003-pc
Morris, M. (2003). Local Rules and Global Properties: Modeling the Emergence of Network Structure. In Dynamic Social Network Modeling and Analysis: Workshop Summary and Papers (pp. 174–186). National Academies Press. Retrieved from https://market.android.com/details?id=book-DOo-hq1-oF0C
Notes Summarize: This article argues for use of statistical modeling, esp. ERGM, in network analysis. It offers some useful analysis of the gap (~15 yrs ago) and proposes approaches to mitigating the gaps. Some important points include &amp;lsquo;model closes the gap between theory and data&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;traditional network analysis focuses on descriptives, for no apparent reasons&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: NA</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-04-kollar2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-04-kollar2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Kollar2013
NA
Notes Highlights We argue that, just like musical pieces, TEL environments need to be created (i.e., orchestrated), adapted (i.e., arranged) and reified (i.e., conducted), and educational research that attempts to make a practical impact needs to consider all three processes. (p. 507)
We argue that it is the narrow perspective that Dillenbourg advocates concerning what orchestration is (namely the real-time management of events and activities in a classroom) that ignites such criticism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: National Academy of Engineering. (2015). Educate to Innovate</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-04-28-nae2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-04-28-nae2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @nae2015
National Academy of Engineering. (2015). Educate to Innovate: Factors That Influence Innovation: Based on Input from Innovators and Stakeholders. Washington, D.C.: The National Academies Press.
Notes This book on &amp;lsquo;education for innovation&amp;rsquo; is a fun read. Ideas presented in the book are mostly based on interviews and workshops with &amp;lsquo;innovators&amp;rsquo; and resonated with me. Chapter 4, which presents a framework that explains how skills experiences and environments relate to innovation, is of particular interest to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Nistor. (2014). Participation in virtual academic communities of practice</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-01-nistor2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-01-nistor2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Nistor2014
Nistor, N., Baltes, B., Dascălu, M., Mihăilă, D., Smeaton, G., &amp;amp; Trăuşan-Matu, Ş. (2014). Participation in virtual academic communities of practice under the influence of technology acceptance and community factors. A learning analytics application. Computers in Human Behavior, 34, 339–344. doi:10.1016/j.chb.2013.10.051
Notes Not a typical learning analytics research even though &amp;lsquo;learning analytics&amp;rsquo; is featured in the title.
Highlights 2.2. Educational technology acceptance (p. 340)
A prominent acceptance theory is Venkatesh’s Unified Theory of Acceptance and Use of Technology (UTAUT; Venkatesh et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Olinghouse2013-yd: The relationship between vocabulary and writing quality in three genres</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-20-olinghouse2013-yd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-20-olinghouse2013-yd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Olinghouse2013-yd
Olinghouse, N. G., &amp;amp; Wilson, J. (2013). The relationship between vocabulary and writing quality in three genres. Reading and Writing, 26(1), 45–65. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11145-012-9392-5
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Abstract The purpose of this study was to examine the role of vocabulary in writing across three genres. Fifth graders (N = 105) wrote three compositions: story, persuasive, and informative. Each composition revolved around the topic of outer space to control for background knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Oliveira. (2014). Dynamic communities in evolving customer networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-10-02-oliveira2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-10-02-oliveira2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Oliveira2014
Oliveira, M., Guerreiro, A., &amp;amp; Gama, J. (2014). Dynamic communities in evolving customer networks: an analysis using landmark and sliding windows. Social Network Analysis and Mining, 4(1), 208. doi:10.1007/s13278-014-0208-2
Notes This article contrasts two kinds of dynamic network analysis&amp;mdash;landmark window and sliding window&amp;mdash;by applying both approaches to analysis of a customer network. Besides comparisons of well-known network metrics (e.g., centrality, density), it also tracks development of sub-communities in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Onnela - 2014 - Using sociometers to quantify social interaction patterns</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-27-onnela2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-27-onnela2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Onnela2014
Onnela, J.-P., Waber, B. N., Pentland, A., Schnorf, S., &amp;amp; Lazer, D. (2014). Using sociometers to quantify social interaction patterns. Scientific Reports, 4, 1–8. doi:10.1038/srep05604
Notes One of the most clear description of how sociometers work. Study focuses on gender difference in terms of proximity and talkativeness. &amp;ldquo;The strongest effect discovered in our study is the difference in gender participation as a function of tie strength and group size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Oshima, J. (1998). Differences in Knowledge-Building Between Two Types of Networked Learning Environments</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-28-oshima1998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-28-oshima1998/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Oshima1998
Oshima, J. (1998). Differences in Knowledge-Building Between Two Types of Networked Learning Environments: An Information-Flow Analysis. Journal of Educational Computing Research, 19(3), 329–351. doi:10.2190/YLLX-M9CW-15X9-BJJ9
Notes Interesting work comparing S-CSILE with D-CSILE. A probable indication of pedagogical transition from intentional learning to KB and also tech transition from CSILE to KF.
Coding schemes are also interesting &amp;ndash; revealing an earlier differentiation of referent vs. problem-based knowledge which gets less discussed in later literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Oshima. (2006). Knowledge-building activity structures in Japanese elementary science pedagogy</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-03-oshima2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-03-oshima2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Oshima2006
Oshima, J., Oshima, R., Murayama, I., Inagaki, S., Takenaka, M., Yamamoto, T., … Nakayama, H. (2006). Knowledge-building activity structures in Japanese elementary science pedagogy. International Journal of Computer-Supported Collaborative Learning, 1(2), 229–246. doi:10.1007/s11412-006-8995-8
Notes Efforts to introduce KB into Japanese elementary classrooms: created two practical design principles&amp;mdash;idea-centered lesson and collective knowledge advancement&amp;mdash;based on 12 KB principles. In two design studies, these two practical principles were integrated with Japanese science activity structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: O’Hara, K., &amp; Sellen, A. (1997). A comparison of reading paper and on-line documents</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-18-ohara1997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-18-ohara1997/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @OHara1997
O’Hara, K., &amp;amp; Sellen, A. (1997). A comparison of reading paper and on-line documents. In Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on Human factors in computing systems - CHI ’97 (pp. 335–342). New York, New York, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;258549.258787
Notes Highlights The Literature (p. 1)
A fairly substantial body of literature comparing the reading of paper versus on-line documents can be found in the psychological, human factors, and ergonomics literature (see [4, 10] for comprehensive reviews).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Pelletier, J., Reeve, R., &amp; Halewood, C. (2006). Young children’s knowledge building and literacy development through Knowledge Forum</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-03-pelletier2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-03-pelletier2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Pelletier2006
Pelletier, J., Reeve, R., &amp;amp; Halewood, C. (2006). Young children’s knowledge building and literacy development through Knowledge Forum{\textregistered}. Early Education and Development, 17(3), 323–346.
Notes Highlights the literacy development of 4-year-old children in a laboratory school (p. 2)
Over the course of the year, children participated in a longitudinal photo journal project. With adult support, children posted their photo journals and ideas to KF® in the form of electronic “notes,” which allowed children to view each other’s work and to build on ideas by posting their responses and comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ph .D. Thesis Research: Where do I Start</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-09-26-davis2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-09-26-davis2001/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @davis2001
Davis, D. (2001). Ph .D. Thesis Research: Where do I Start? Retrieved from http://www.columbia.edu/~drd28/Thesis Research.pdf
Notes This article is very important&amp;ndash;maybe the most helpful one in terms of articulating promisingness in looking for thesis topic. It centers around some points such as being interesting, important, and new.
1. How Do I Find “The Right Topic”?  First, there is no “Right Topic.” &amp;ndash;Much more important is to find something that is important and genuinely interests you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Phillips. (2014). Research in the hard sciences, and in very hard “softer” domains</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-23-phillips2014-jd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-23-phillips2014-jd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Phillips2014-jd
Phillips, D. C. (2014). Research in the hard sciences, and in very hard “softer” domains. Educational Researcher . Retrieved from http://edr.sagepub.com/content/43/1/9.short
Notes Highlights Drawing on the work of Popper and Dewey, this commentary highlights the relative similarities between hard sciences and education research in their rhetorical nature, while acknowledging the divergent paths of these two fields of inquiry with regard to prediction and generalizability. (p. 1)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Porcaro. (2014). Educational change in Oman</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-23-porcaro2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-23-porcaro2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Porcaro2014
Porcaro, D. S. (2014). Educational change in Oman: a design research study of personal, institutional, and societal reactions to collaborative knowledge building. Technology, Pedagogy and Education, 23(2), 199–223. doi:10.1080/1475939X.2013.802993
Notes I am reading this article when reviewing literature on knowledge building. However, knowledge building is not a central concept in this article as its general sense is applied here. Maybe constructivist collaborative learning is the general approach here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Predicting mooc dropout over weeks using machine learning methods</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-11-kloft14predicting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-11-kloft14predicting/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @kloftpredicting
Kloft, M., Stiehler, F., Zheng, Z., and Pinkwart, N. (2014). Predicting mooc dropout over weeks using machine learning methods. In Modeling Large Scale Social Interaction in Massively Open Online Courses Workshop (EMNLP 2014).
Notes A potentially useful paper. The element of using historical features to predict dropouts is useful. It also built and tested a number of features for predicting dropouts. But the value of predicting dropouts in later weeks of a MOOC is limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Psychometric Properties of the Alternative Form of the Education Participation Scale</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-18-boshier91psychometric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-18-boshier91psychometric/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @boshier91psychometric
Boshier R (1991). “Psychometric Properties of the Alternative Form of the Education Participation Scale.” Adult Education Quarterly, 41(3), pp. 150-167. , http://aeq.sagepub.com/content/41/3/150.full.pdf+html, .
Notes This article reports a reconstruction of the widely used Education Participation Scale (EPS) created by Boshier in 1970s. The &amp;lsquo;newly&amp;rsquo; created EPS, i.e., EPS (A form) in contrast with EPS (F form), is composed of a total of 42 items in 7 dimensions below (with each dimension having 6 items):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Pursuit of explanation within a computer-supported classroom</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-10-04-hakkarainen2004a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-10-04-hakkarainen2004a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @hakkarainen2004a
Hakkarainen, K. (2004). Pursuit of explanation within a computer-supported classroom. International Journal of Science Education, 26(8), 979–996. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;1468181032000354
Notes The purpose of the study is to analyse whether elementary school children, collaborating within a computer-supported classroom, may profitably participate in research-like processes of inquiry that characterize practices of scientific research. The problem addressed in the study is whether 10-year-old and 11-year-old children, in appropriate circumstances, engage in working with knowledge at a deep level of explanation instead of processing only factual and descriptive knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Quantified measures of online discourse as knowledge building indicators</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-02-zhang2011c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-02-zhang2011c/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Zhang2011c
Zhang, J. and Sun, Y. (2011). Quantified measures of online discourse as knowledge building indicators. In Spada, H., G., S., Miyake, N., and Law, N., editors, Connecting computer-supported collaborative learning to policy and practice: CSCL2011 conference proceedings, volume 1, pages 72–79. ISLS, Hong Kong SAR, China.
Notes Highlights This secondary data analysis examined a set of social interaction (e.g., social network patterns), content (e.g., questions, ideas), and lexical measures (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Reasons nurses participate in continuing education</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-18-oconnor1979reasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-18-oconnor1979reasons/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @oconnor1979reasons
O&amp;rsquo;Connor AB (1979). “Reasons nurses participate in continuing education.” Nursing Research, 28(6), pp. 354-359.
And this piece as well:
O’Connor, A. B. (1982). Reasons nurses participate in self-study continuing education programs. Nursing research, 31(6):371–374.
Notes Basically, these two studies used a revised version of the EPS (Education Participation Scale) to measure motivation of continuing education among nurses. Two studies were different in terms of sample size &amp;ndash; the 1982 study surveyed around 1800 nurses (twice as big as in the 1979 study).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Rentzou, K. (2013). Greek preschool children’s playful behaviour</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-15-rentzou2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-15-rentzou2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Rentzou2013
Rentzou, K. (2013). Greek preschool children’s playful behaviour: assessment and correlation with personal and family characteristics. Early Child Development and Care, 183(11), 1733–1745. http://doi.org/10.1080/03004430.2012.752736
Notes Notes to me as an instructor:
 This study reports on correlation analyses Discussion points  correlation vs. causation what constitutes strong correlation? how to go from correlations? how to write a discussion section?   Highlights The present study had a twofold aim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Roll - 2015 - Understanding, evaluating, and supporting self-regulated learning using learning analytics</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-26-roll_undated-pn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-26-roll_undated-pn/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Roll_undated-pn
Roll, I., &amp;amp; Winne, P. H. (2015). Understanding, evaluating, and supporting self-regulated learning using learning analytics. Journal of Learning Analytics, 2(1), 7–12.
Notes Highlights In terms of one widely cited model of self‐regulated learning proposed by Winne and Hadwin (1998; Winne, 2011; Greene &amp;amp; Azevedo, 2007), learners exercise agency across four loosely sequenced phases: (1) They scan their environment to identify internal factors (cognitive, motivational, affective) and external features that may influence a task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Rose-2016-Technology Support for Discussion Based Learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-10-14-rose2016-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-10-14-rose2016-rs/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Rose2016-rs
Rosé, C. P., &amp;amp; Ferschke, O. (2016). Technology Support for Discussion Based Learning: From Computer Supported Collaborative Learning to the Future of Massive Open Online Courses. International Journal of Artificial Intelligence in Education, 26(2), 660–678.
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Thisarticleoffersavisionfortechnologysupportedcollaborativeanddiscussionbased learning at scale. (p. 660)
In particular, this support has been enabled by an integration of text mining and conversational agents to form a novel type of micro-script support for productive discussion processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Rudolph, J. L. (2014). Why Understanding Science Matters: The IES Research Guidelines as a Case in Point</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-23-rudolph2014-fd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-23-rudolph2014-fd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Rudolph2014-fd
Rudolph, J. L. (2014). Why Understanding Science Matters: The IES Research Guidelines as a Case in Point. Educational Researcher , 43(1), 15–18.
Notes Highlights “appropriate empirical evaluation” that can identify those things that “are in fact improvements,” that will in turn “contribute to the bigger pic- ture of scientific knowledge” (p. 11). (p. 1)
s far back as the 1950s (as many education researchers well know), federal efforts to reshape education drew on research practices and organiza- tional approaches from the natural sciences, where instrumental success and cumulative progress are the norms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Rummel-2016-Different Futures of Adaptive Collaborative Learning Support</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-10-14-rummel2016-wa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-10-14-rummel2016-wa/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Rummel2016-wa
Rummel, N., Walker, E., &amp;amp; Aleven, V. (2016). Different Futures of Adaptive Collaborative Learning Support. International Journal of Artificial Intelligence in Education, 26(2), 784–795.
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights In this position paper we contrast a Dystopian view of the future of adaptive collaborative learning support (ACLS) with a Utopian scenario that – due to betterdesigned technology, grounded in research – avoids the pitfalls of the Dystopian version and paints a positive picture of the practice of computer-supported collaborative learning 25 years from now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sadler - 1998 - Formative assessment</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-09-23-sadler1998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-09-23-sadler1998/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sadler1998
Sadler, D. R. (1998). Formative assessment: Revisiting the territory. Assessment in Education: Principles, Policy &amp;amp; Practice, 5(1), 77–84. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;0969595980050104
Notes This is a commentary on Black &amp;amp; Williams (1998) &amp;ndash; a review article on the effective of formative feedback on learning.
Highlights A key argument is that students are already assessing their own work and generating their own feedback, and that higher education should build on this ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sannino et al. (2009). Activity theory between historical engagement and future-making practice</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-04-sannino2009-cg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-04-sannino2009-cg/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sannino2009-cg
Sannino, A., Daniels, H., &amp;amp; Gutiérrez, K. D. (2009). Activity theory between historical engagement and future-making practice. In A. Sannino, H. Daniels, &amp;amp; K. D. Gutiérrez (Eds.), Learning and expanding with activity theory (pp. 1–15). Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. Retrieved from https://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;id=pyY5EusnjBcC&amp;amp;oi=fnd&amp;amp;pg=PA1&amp;amp;dq=Activity+theory+between+historical+engagement+and+future-making+practice.+&amp;amp;ots=KRX_JACIwx&amp;amp;sig=Evh74CCwE-Yq92ecqQU_3XMgFJg
Notes Summarize: This chapter provides an interesting and thorough overview of the historical context of activity theory. Understanding the historical circumstance of this theory is important for any use of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sannino et al. (2016). Formative Interventions for Expansive Learning and Transformative Agency</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-10-sannino2016-lr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-10-sannino2016-lr/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sannino2016-lr
Sannino, A., Engeström, Y., &amp;amp; Lemos, M. (2016). Formative Interventions for Expansive Learning and Transformative Agency. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 25(4), 599–633. https://doi.org/10.1080/10508406.2016.1204547
Notes Summarize: A very nicely (and also densely written) paper presenting three cases of expansive learning. It highlights six theoretical lens to be used in analysis of expansive learning. The cases are from two schools and a university library. Formative interventions are also compared with design-based research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Schneider-2016-Making Reading Visible: Social Annotation with Lacuna in the Humanities Classroom</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-04-24-schneider2016-du/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-04-24-schneider2016-du/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Schneider2016-du
Schneider, E., Hartman, S., Eshel, A., &amp;amp; Johnsrud, B. (2016). Making Reading Visible: Social Annotation with Lacuna in the Humanities Classroom. Journal of Interactive Technology and Pedagogy, (9). Retrieved from http://jitp.commons.gc.cuny.edu/making-reading-visible-social-annotation-with-lacuna-in-the-humanities-classroom/
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights we find that student annotations and writing on Lacuna give instructors more insight into students’ perspectives on texts and course materials. (p. 1)
The visibility of shared annotations encourages students to take on a more active role as peer instructors and peer learners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Schwartz - 2013 - Measuring What Matters Most: Choice-Based Assessments for the Digital Age</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-05-07-schwartz13measuring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-05-07-schwartz13measuring/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @schwartz13measuring
Schwartz, D. L., &amp;amp; Arena, D. (2013). Measuring What Matters Most: Choice-Based Assessments for the Digital Age. Cambridge, Massachusetts; London, England: The MIT Press.
Notes Highlights Erna Yackel and Paul Cobb (1996, 473) nicely summarize the perspective of many: “The development of intellectual and social autonomy is a major goal in the current educational reform movement, more generally, and in the reform movement in mathematics education, in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Segedy - 2015 - Using Coherence Analysis to Characterize Self-Regulated Learning Behaviours in Open-Ended Learning Environments</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-26-segedy2015-sy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-26-segedy2015-sy/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Segedy2015-sy
Segedy, J. R., Kinnebrew, J. S., &amp;amp; Biswas, G. (2015). Using Coherence Analysis to Characterize Self-Regulated Learning Behaviours in Open-Ended Learning Environments. Journal of Learning Analytics, 2(1), 13–48.
Notes Nice work! So this work follows this &amp;lsquo;logic&amp;rsquo;: SRL is important and we have good theoretical models based on decades of research. We have Betty&amp;rsquo;s Brain as an &amp;lsquo;open-ended learning environment&amp;rsquo; (note that&amp;rsquo;s different from open learning environments), where SRL is key for learner success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sengupta. (2015). Learning to Deflect: Conceptual Change in Physics During Digital Game Play</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-17-sengupta2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-17-sengupta2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sengupta2015
Sengupta, P., Krinks, K. D., &amp;amp; Clark, D. B. (2015). Learning to Deflect: Conceptual Change in Physics During Digital Game Play. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 24(4), 638–674. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;10508406.2015.1082912
Notes Highlights The current study presents a microgenetic analysis and case study of one student’s processes of knowledge construction as he played a conceptually integrated digital game (SURGE Next) designed to support learning about Newtonian mechanics. (p. 2)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sentiment Analysis in MOOC Discussion Forums</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-01-wen2014a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-01-wen2014a/</guid>
      <description>##References
Wen, M., Yang, D., &amp;amp; Rosé, C. P. (2014). Sentiment Analysis in MOOC Discussion Forums: What does it tell us? In EDM2014.
Citekey: @Wen2014a
##Notes
General comments
 What will be a more interesting variable to correlate to than drop out rates? The link between sentiment and dropout behaviors is slippery, because we have no evidence that negative sentiments will cause dropouts. So the main logic in this paper is undermined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Shum - 2012 - UNESCO Policy Brief: Learning Analytics</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-01-14-shum2012a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-01-14-shum2012a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Shum2012a
Shum SB (2012). “UNESCO Policy Brief: Learning Analytics.” Technical Report November, UNESCO Institute for Information Technologies in Education. .
Notes Highlights The emerging conversaon goes far beyond technologists (academic and commercial), to include researchers in educaon, leaders and policymakers, educaonal praconers, organisaonal administrators, instruconal designers, product vendors, and crically, the learners themselves (who are oen the first adopters of new cloud applicaons, many of which make data available, and who are the primary consumers of certain kinds of learning analyc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Shum. (2012). Social learning analytics</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-11-17-shum2012b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-11-17-shum2012b/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Shum2012b
Shum, S. B., &amp;amp; Ferguson, R. (2012). Social learning analytics. Educational Technology and Society, 15(3), 3–26.
Notes Highlights Learning analytics has its roots in two computing endeavours not specifically concerned with learning, but rather with strong business imperatives to understand internal organisational data, and external consumer behaviour. (p. 1)
Educational Data Mining (EDM) “an emerging discipline, concerned with developing methods for exploring the unique types of data that come from educational settings, and using those methods to better understand students, and the settings which they learn in” (Baker &amp;amp; Yacef, 2009).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Siemens - 2013 - Learning analytics: The emergence of a discipline</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-01-14-siemens2013learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-01-14-siemens2013learning/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @siemens2013learning
Siemens G (2013). “Learning analytics: The emergence of a discipline.” American Behavioral Scientist, pp. 0002764213498851.
Notes Highlights The challenges facing LA as a field are also reviewed, particularly regarding the need to increase the scope of data capture so that the complexity of the learning process can be more accurately reflected in analysis. Privacy and data ownership will become increasingly important for all participants in analytics projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sinha (2015) Collaborative group engagement in a computer-supported inquiry learning environment</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-11-06-sinha2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-11-06-sinha2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sinha2015
Sinha, S., Rogat, T. K., Adams-Wiggins, K. R., &amp;amp; Hmelo-Silver, C. E. (2015). Collaborative group engagement in a computer-supported inquiry learning environment. International Journal of Computer-Supported Collaborative Learning, 10(3), 273–307. doi:10.1007/s11412-015-9218-y
Notes Highlights the quality of engagement (p. 273)
the quality of behavioral and social engagement differentiated groups demonstrating low quality engagement, but cognitive and conceptual-to-consequential forms are required for explaining high quality engagement. (p. 273)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Slade. (2013). Learning analytics: Ethical issues and dilemmas</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-11-29-oblinger2012let/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-11-29-oblinger2012let/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @slade2013learning
Slade, S., &amp;amp; Prinsloo, P. (2013). Learning analytics: Ethical issues and dilemmas. American Behavioral Scientist, 57(10), 1510–1529. doi:10.1177&amp;frasl;0002764213479366
Notes Highlights This article proposes a sociocritical perspective on the use of learning analytics. Such an approach highlights the role of power, the impact of surveillance, the need for transparency, and an acknowledgment that student identity is a transient, temporal, and context-bound construct. Each of these affects the scope and definition of learning analytics’ ethical use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Smith. (2012). Predictive Modeling to Forecast Student Outcomes and Drive Effective Interventions in Online Community College Courses</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-01-smith2012predictive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-01-smith2012predictive/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @smith2012predictive
Smith, V. C., Lange, A., &amp;amp; Huston, D. R. (2012). Predictive Modeling to Forecast Student Outcomes and Drive Effective Interventions in Online Community College Courses. Journal of Asynchronous Learning Networks, 16(3), 51–61.
Notes Highlights This is a case study from a community college utilizing learning analytics and the development of predictive models to identify at-risk students based on dozens of key variables. (p. 1)
The recent demands for increased student success efforts, most notably from the American Graduation Initiative [1], have come as colleges are facing limited funding and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Snijders2010-ua-Introduction to stochastic actor-based models for network dynamics</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-01-snijders2010-ua/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-01-snijders2010-ua/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Snijders2010-ua
Snijders, T. A. B., van de Bunt, G. G., &amp;amp; Steglich, C. E. G. (2010). Introduction to stochastic actor-based models for network dynamics. Social Networks, 32(1), 44–60. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socnet.2009.02.004
Notes Summarize: A such nicely written intro to SIENA. Should be read for more than once.
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights In this article we give a tutorial introduction to what we call here stochastic actor-based models for network dynamics, which are a type of models that have the purpose to represent net- work dynamics on the basis of observed longitudinal data, and evaluate these according to the paradigm of statistical inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Snyder - 2011 - Implementing Randomized Controlled Trials in Preschool Settings That Include Young Children With Disabilities</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-29-snyder2011-ss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-29-snyder2011-ss/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Snyder2011-ss
Snyder, P. (2011). Implementing Randomized Controlled Trials in Preschool Settings That Include Young Children With Disabilities: Considering the Context of Strain and Bovey. Topics in Early Childhood Special Education, 31(3), 162–165.
Notes A commentary on @Strain2011-sn, highlighting its contribution to finding the &amp;ldquo;best-available&amp;rdquo; evidence by running a randomized controlled trial. History of IES&amp;rsquo; emphasis on RCT is also explained.
Highlights The intent of this federal support is to increase the number of scientifically valid efficacy or effec- tiveness evaluations conducted on “early” interventions with the goal of identifying “what works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Southerland. (2014). Editors’ Introduction: What Should Count as Quality Education Research?</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-23-southerland2014-vk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-23-southerland2014-vk/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Southerland2014-vk
Southerland, S. A., Gadsden, V. L., &amp;amp; Herrington, C. D. (2014). Editors’ Introduction: What Should Count as Quality Education Research? Continuing the Discussion. Educational Researcher , 43(1), 7–8.
Notes Highlights contribute to the bigger picture of scientific knowledge and theory on learning, instruction, and education systems. (IES, 2013b, p. 11) (p. 1)
The American Educational Research Association (AERA) formally addressed some of these issues in issuing “Standards for Reporting on Empirical Social Sciences Research in AERA Publications” in 2006, followed by issuing a second set of standards in 2009 focused on humanities-oriented research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Strain - 2011 - Randomized, Controlled Trial of the LEAP Model of Early Intervention for Young Children With Autism Spectrum Disorders</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-29-strain2011-sn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-29-strain2011-sn/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Strain2011-sn
Strain, P. S., &amp;amp; Bovey, E. H. (2011). Randomized, Controlled Trial of the LEAP Model of Early Intervention for Young Children With Autism Spectrum Disorders. Topics in Early Childhood Special Education, 31(3), 133–154.
Notes Highlights 28 inclusive preschool classrooms were randomly assigned to receive 2 years of training and coaching to fidelity in the LEAP (Learning Experiences and Alternative Program for Preschoolers and Their Parents) preschool model, and 28 inclusive classes were assigned to receive intervention manuals only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Studying Online Social Networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-11-05-garton2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-11-05-garton2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @garton2006
Garton, L., Haythornthwaite, C., &amp;amp; Wellman, B. (2006). Studying Online Social Networks. Journal of Computer-Mediated Communication, 3(1). doi:10.1111/j.1083-6101.1997.tb00062.x
Summary This paper gives a great introduction to SNA, covering basic concepts, units of analysis, data collection, and data analysis. Although everything is not in great detail, but it&amp;rsquo;s a great place to start unless you wish to start with a huge textbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Studying learning in the worldwide classroom: Research into edX’s first MOOC</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-15-breslow2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-15-breslow2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Breslow2013
Breslow, L. and Pritchard, D. (2013). Studying learning in the worldwide classroom: Research into edX’s first MOOC. Research &amp;amp; Practice Assessment, 8(1):13–25.
Notes This article is one of my favorite piece about MOOC research. It was also one of the earliest to look more deeply into MOOC learner activities. The questions got answered are important, and preliminary at the same time. But these many questions the authors ask are even more important to further explore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Su (2010) A Web 2.0-based collaborative annotation system for enhancing knowledge sharing</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-07-13-su2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-07-13-su2010/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Su2010
Su, A. Y. S., Yang, S. J. H., Hwang, W.-Y., &amp;amp; Zhang, J. (2010). A Web 2.0-based collaborative annotation system for enhancing knowledge sharing in collaborative learning environments. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 55(2), 752–766. doi:10.1016/j.compedu.2010.03.008
Notes An independent implementation of an interesting web annotation system. This paper focuses on evaluating students&amp;rsquo; acceptance of the system and how the use of web annotations have helped students learn.
The use of annotations in this study, and in many others, has been focused on knowledge sharing, especially in the process of consuming or making sense of shared readings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Sun. (2008). What drives a successful e-Learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-15-sun2008b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-15-sun2008b/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Sun2008b
Sun, P.-C., Tsai, R. J., Finger, G., Chen, Y.-Y., &amp;amp; Yeh, D. (2008). What drives a successful e-Learning? An empirical investigation of the critical factors influencing learner satisfaction. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 50(4), 1183–1202. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2006.11.007
Notes Building on earlier research on e-learning, this study aims to build a model of learner satisfaction involving multiple dimensions including course, instructor, learner, tech, design, and environmental dimensions. The presentation of the study is succinct (as one could normally expect from the journal), in some cases too succinct to clarify doubts about the dataset (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Teaching as a Design Science</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-04-12-laurillard2012teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-04-12-laurillard2012teaching/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @laurillard2012teaching
Laurillard, D. (2012). Teaching as a Design Science: Building Pedagogical Patterns for Learning and Technology. (258). Routledge.
Notes Related resources  [[http://www.routledge.com/books/details/9780415803878/|Book page]] [[http://reganmian.net/wiki/ref:laurillard2012teaching|Stian&#39;s notes]] [[http://clt.lse.ac.uk/events/networked_diana_laurillard_101012.pdf|Slides]]  Note: Since colleagues in our group are working on professional development for Knowledge Building teachers, the notion of teaching as design science might be a nice ingredient to consider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Teplovs2013-yi</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-04-03-teplovs2013-yi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-04-03-teplovs2013-yi/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Teplovs2013-yi
Teplovs, C., &amp;amp; Fujita, N. (2013). Socio-Dynamic Latent Semantic Learner Models. In D. D. Suthers, K. Lund, C. P. Rosé, C. Teplovs, &amp;amp; N. Law (Eds.), Productive Multivocality in the Analysis of Group Interactions (pp. 383–396). Springer US. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4614-8960-3_21
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights The units of interaction for our analyses are documents called “notes”. Patterns of interaction amongst participants are mediated by these documents. (p. 2)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: The CSILE Project</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-29-scardamalia1994a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-29-scardamalia1994a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia1994a
Scardamalia, M., Bereiter, C., &amp;amp; Lamon, M. (1994). The CSILE Project: Trying to Bring the Classroom into World 3. In Classroom lessons: Integrating cognitive theory and classroom practice (pp. 201–228).
Notes Notes Marlene recommended this article when discussing my thesis work on (personal) epistemology. This article&amp;rsquo;s emphasis on World 3 and collective epistemology prompts me to rethink my research design. Combining with my thoughts from reading [[ref:forrester2006|Forrester&amp;rsquo;s thesis]] about epistemology, I am thinking about research of epistemology related to promisingness in two important directions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: The Education Participation Scale--Modified: Evaluating a Measure of Continuing Education</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-18-dia05education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-18-dia05education/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @dia05education
Dia D, Smith CA, Cohen-Callow A and Bliss DL (2005). “The Education Participation Scale-Modified: Evaluating a Measure of Continuing Education.” Research on Social Work Practice, 15(3), pp. 213-222. , http://rsw.sagepub.com/content/15/3/213.full.pdf+html, .
Notes This article evaluates the Educational Participation Scale–Modified (EPS-M) developed by O’Connor (1979, 1982) in the context of social work.
It has a nice literature review of subversions of EPS.
Highlights Abstract
The purpose of this study was to evaluate the measurement model and theory underlying the Educational Participation Scale–Modified (EPS-M) using confirmatory factor analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: The elements of style</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-09-strunk1918elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-09-strunk1918elements/</guid>
      <description>References Strunk Jr, W. (1918). The elements of style. New York: Penguin.
Citekey: @strunk1918elements
Notes A friend recommended this book to me as a useful guide for English writing. (Some of the advice might be dated though, since it was written a century ago.)
Highlights Chapter II ELEMENTARY RULES OF USAGE (p. 9) (1) Form the possessive singular of nouns with ’s (p. 9)
Charles’s friend (p. 9)
Exceptions are the possessives of ancient proper names in -es and -is, the possessive Jesus’, and such forms as for conscience’ sake, for righteousness’ sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Thompson. (2013). Processing and Visualizing Data in Complex Learning Environments</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-12-01-thompson2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-12-01-thompson2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Thompson2013
Thompson, K., Ashe, D., Carvalho, L., Goodyear, P., Kelly, N., &amp;amp; Parisio, M. (2013). Processing and Visualizing Data in Complex Learning Environments. American Behavioral Scientist, 57(10), 1401–1420. doi:10.1177&amp;frasl;0002764213479368
Notes I like the proposed framework and model. But the presence of LA in Case 1 is especially minimal. Case 2 involves much human coding. Appears to be a more traditional CSCL research.
Highlights We discuss, using the cases of two learning environments, how structure affects the behavior of learners and, in turn, how that behavior has the potential to affect learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Three types of conceptual change</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-06-06-chi2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-06-06-chi2008/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @chi2008
Chi, M. T. H. (2008). Three types of conceptual change: Belief revision, mental model transformation, and categorical shift. In S. Vosniadou (Ed.), Handbook of research on conceptual change (pp. 61–82). Hillsdale, NJ: Erlbaum.
Notes This book chapter systematically introduces Chi&amp;rsquo;s theory about conceptual change. She thinks misconceptions and conceptual change happen on three grain sizes: false beliefs, flawed mental models, and ontological miscatogerization. Therefore, instructions to promote conceptual change should also be conducted on those three levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Tong - 2014 - A Randomized Study of a Literacy-Integrated Science Intervention</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-29-tong2014-tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-29-tong2014-tx/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Tong2014-tx
Tong, F., Irby, B. J., Lara-Alecio, R., Guerrero, C., Fan, Y., &amp;amp; Huerta, M. (2014). A Randomized Study of a Literacy-Integrated Science Intervention for Low-Socio-economic Status Middle School Students: Findings from first-year implementation. International Journal of Science Education, 36(12), 2083–2109.
Notes Highlights This paper presents the findings from a randomized control trial study of reading/literacy-integrated science inquiry intervention after 1 year of implementation and the treatment effect on 5th-grade low-socio-economic African-American and Hispanic students’ achievement in science and English reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Tutzauer, F. (2013). A Family of Affiliation Indices for Two-Mode Networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-15-tutzauer2013-oq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-15-tutzauer2013-oq/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Tutzauer2013-oq
Tutzauer, F. (2013). A Family of Affiliation Indices for Two-Mode Networks. Journal of Social and Biological Structures, 14, 1. Retrieved from https://www.cmu.edu/joss/content/articles/volume14/Tutzauer.pdf
Notes Summarize: This paper introduces affiliation index, a new measure to characterize affiliation in a two-mode network. As the author nicely argues, this index is two-mode in nature, compared to centrality measures which are one-mode in nature and often borrowed to analyze two-mode networks. The author also introduces a family of affiliation indices and significance tests based on its binomial distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Understanding collaborative learning processes in new learning environments</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-05-22-hmelo-silver2008b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-05-22-hmelo-silver2008b/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @hmelo-silver2008b
Hmelo-Silver, C. E., Chernobilsky, E., &amp;amp; Jordan, R. (2008). Understanding collaborative learning processes in new learning environments. Instructional Science, 36(5-6), 409–430. doi:10.1007/s11251-008-9063-8
Summary This paper builds on the 2003 paper, further explaining how CORDTRA diagrams help us interpret learning.
What I found very useful in this paper in particular is the coding schemes they used to analyze collaborative learning. The coding scheme of &amp;ldquo;complexity&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;monitoring&amp;rdquo; could be especially useful for me to analyze use of promisingness tool by students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Unpacking mooc scholarly discourse</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-15-ebben13unpacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-15-ebben13unpacking/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @ebben13unpacking
Ebben, M. and Murphy, J. S. (2014). Unpacking mooc scholarly discourse: a review of nascent mooc scholarship. Learning, Media and Technology, 39(3):328–345.
Notes A review of MOOC research is useful for someone who is new to the topic (and its history). Based on a review of about two dozen journal articles, the authors identified two phases of MOOC scholarly discourse, characterizing each phase by their key ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Using latent semantic analysis to assess knowledge</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-09-26-rehder1998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-09-26-rehder1998/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @rehder1998
Rehder, B., Schreiner, M. E., Wolfe, M. B. W., Laham, D., Landauer, T. K., &amp;amp; Kintsch, W. (1998). Using latent semantic analysis to assess knowledge: Some technical considerations. Discourse Processes, 25(2), 337 – 354. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;01638539809545031
Notes In another article (Wolfe et al., 1998/this issue) we showed how Latent Semantic Analysis (LSA) can be used to assess student knowledge—how essays can be graded by LSA and how LSA can match students with appropriate instructional texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Van Noorden. (2014). Online collaboration: Scientists and the social network</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-06-28-vannoorden2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-06-28-vannoorden2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @VanNoorden2014
Van Noorden, R. (2014). Online collaboration: Scientists and the social network. Nature, 512(7513), 126–129. doi:10.1038/512126a
Notes A brief commentary on the use of social media (esp. ResearchGate) by academics.
Highlights Ijad Madisch, a Berlin-based former physician and virologist, tells this story as just one example of the successes of ResearchGate, which he founded with two friends six years ago. (p. 126)
The list of failed efforts to launch a ‘Facebook for science’ included Scientist Solutions, SciLinks, Epernicus, 2collab and Nature Network (run by the company that publishes Nature).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Vaquero, L. M., &amp; Cebrian, M. (2013). The rich club phenomenon in the classroom</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-06-27-vaquero2013-ld/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-06-27-vaquero2013-ld/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Vaquero2013-ld
Vaquero, L. M., &amp;amp; Cebrian, M. (2013). The rich club phenomenon in the classroom. Scientific Reports, 3, 1174. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep01174
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights social interactions generally imply better score for students engaging in them. We find that thesestudents, which is created during the first weeks of the course. Low performing students try to engage in theclub after it has been initially formed, and fail to produce reciprocity in their interactions, displaying more (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Veletsianos-2015-Interdisciplinarity in MOOC research and its changes over time</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-10-13-veletsianos2015-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-10-13-veletsianos2015-hd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Veletsianos2015-hd
Veletsianos, G., &amp;amp; Shepherdson, P. (2015). Who studies MOOCs? Interdisciplinarity in MOOC research and its changes over time. The International Review of Research in. Retrieved from http://www.irrodl.org/index.php/irrodl/article/view/2202
Notes Summarize: This study builds on earlier studies of the MOOC literature, but with a special focus (on interdisciplnarity) and a different approach. Briefly, it studies the scope of the literature from 2013-2015; it uses author affiliation as a proxy for Interdisciplinarity; it covers a broad range of literature extracted from multiple indices; it relies on descriptive and inferential statistics (Chi-square) to describe interdisciplinarityand compare it with data from earlier studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Vygotsky, Piaget, and Education</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-06-devries2000vygotsky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-06-devries2000vygotsky/</guid>
      <description>References DeVries, R. (2000). Vygotsky, Piaget, and Education: a reciprocal assimilation of theories and educational practices. New Ideas in Psychology, 18(2-3), 187–213. doi:10.1016/S0732-118X(00)00008-8
Citekey: @devries2000vygotsky
Notes Highlights 1. Introduction (p. 1) The current state of my search is one of some confusion. It has been di$cult to resolve a paradox in Vygotsky&amp;rsquo;s work. On the one hand, Vygotsky often sounded like a behaviorist. On the other hand, Vygotsky often sounded like a constructivist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Wagner, C. S., &amp; Leydesdorff, L. (2005). Network structure, self-organization, and the growth of international collaboration in science. Research Policy, 34(10), 1608–1618. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respol.2005.08.002 </title>
      <link>/notes/2017-08-31-wagner2005-ib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-08-31-wagner2005-ib/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Wagner2005-ib
Wagner, C. S., &amp;amp; Leydesdorff, L. (2005). Network structure, self-organization, and the growth of international collaboration in science. Research Policy, 34(10), 1608–1618. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.respol.2005.08.002
Notes Summarize: Very interesting study of international collaboration using the sociological concept of preferential attachment to make an argument about the self-organizing feature of international collaboration (driven by all sorts of rewards). Two references regarding different types of collaborators highlighted near the end are also quite interesting and could apply to an analysis of an emerging, interdisciplinary area like learning analytics and MOOCs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Wang2016-lu-Modeling customer preferences using multidimensional network analysis in engineering design</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-12-wang2016-lu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-12-wang2016-lu/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Wang2016-lu
Wang, M., Chen, W., Huang, Y., Contractor, N. S., &amp;amp; Fu, Y. (2016). Modeling customer preferences using multidimensional network analysis in engineering design. Design Science, 2. https://doi.org/10.1017/dsj.2016.11
Notes Summarize: This paper presents a case of using multidimensional network analysis &amp;ndash; powered by ERGM &amp;ndash; to model customer preferences in China&amp;rsquo;s car market. Data were from user surveys. The authors patiently set the background, introduce the techniques, compared MNA with unidimensional network analysis, and considerately presented various analytical decisions associated with these approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: What Sociolinguistics and Machine Learning Have to Say to One Another about Interaction Analysis</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-05-rose2014what/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-05-rose2014what/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @rose2014what
Rosé, C. P., &amp;amp; Tovares A. (in press). What Sociolinguistics and Machine Learning Have to Say to One Another about Interaction Analysis. In L. Resnick, Asterhan C., &amp;amp; Clarke S. (Eds.), Socializing Intelligence Through Academic Talk and Dialogue. Washington, D.C.: American Educational Research Association.
Notes  This chapter grapples with two seemingly contradictory views towards discourse analysis: a sociolinguist approach that embraces complexity (such as Gee&amp;rsquo;s intertextuality approach), and a quantitative approach that strives to best discretize discourse behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: What is an expert student?</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-28-sternberg2003expert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-28-sternberg2003expert/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @sternberg2003expert
Sternberg, R. J. (2003). What is an “expert student?” Educational Researcher, 32(8), 5–9.
Notes Sternberg discusses the notion of teaching for expertise&#39;&#39;. He argues thatwe need to identify expertise in a way that is closely aligned with the way experts are identified in the disciplines students study&amp;rdquo; (p. 5). In his framework of successful intelligence&#39;&#39;, he highlights three dimensions of teaching to help children think in ways characteristic of experts in a variety of disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: What video games have to teach us about learning and literacy</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-05-26-gee2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-05-26-gee2003/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @gee2003
Gee, J. P. (2003). What video games have to teach us about learning and literacy. Computers in Entertainment, 1(1), 20. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;950566.950595
Clippings Thus, designers face and largely solve an intriguing educational dilemma, one also faced by schools and workplaces: how to get people, often young people, to learn and master something that is long and challenging—and enjoy it, to boot. (p. 1)
I argue that schools, workplaces, families, and academic researchers have a lot to learn about learning from good computer and video games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Where Good Ideas Come From</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-09-26-johnson2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-09-26-johnson2010/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @johnson2010
Johnson, S. (2010). Where Good Ideas Come From: The Natural History of Innovation. Riverhead Hardcover.
Notes Resources from this book  Howard Gruber, who studied Darwin&amp;rsquo;s notebook2. Antonio Damasio, who studied brain-damaged patients whose inability to make intuitive snap judgments Malcolm Gladwell’s bestseller Blink focused on instant hunch  Darwin’s Paradox In Darwin’s own words, stumbling across the ecosystem of a coral reef in the middle of an ocean was like encountering a swarming oasis in the middle of a desert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Why the Learning Sciences and Instructional Systems Need Each Other</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-05-01-hoadley2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-05-01-hoadley2004/</guid>
      <description>References Hoadley, C. M. (2004). Learning and Design: Why the Learning Sciences and Instructional Systems Need Each Other. Educational Technology, 3, 6–12.
Citekey: @Hoadley2004
Notes Highlights &amp;ldquo;While both analyses varied in their coverage and techniques, they came to similar conclusions, that the literatures identified with these two communities had surprisingly little overlap, and that a small number of individuals represented a large portion of what overlap did exist.&amp;rdquo; (p. 3)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Wieman, C. E. (2014). The Similarities Between Research in Education and Research in the Hard Sciences</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-23-wieman2014-vd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-23-wieman2014-vd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Wieman2014-vd
Wieman, C. E. (2014). The Similarities Between Research in Education and Research in the Hard Sciences. Educational Researcher , 43(1), 12–14.
Notes Highlights Here I would like to offer a different perspective, how there is a considerable degree of similarity between research in the hard sciences and education, and how this provides a useful lens for thinking about what constitutes “rigorous” and “scientific” education research. (p. 1)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Winne, P. (2016). Self-regulated learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-23-winne2016-as/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-23-winne2016-as/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Winne2016-as
Winne, P. (2016). Self-regulated learning. SFU Educational Review, 1(1).
Notes Highlights  Cool to see Winne articulate assumptions of his research program. Everyone should do this :) Neat! (p. 1)
 Several assumptions undergird my research program. First, one way people learn relies on innate features of our cognitive architecture. Like Pavlov’s dogs, who learned a novel stimulus (a bell) could forecast food or Skinner’s pigeons who learned to behave in particular ways (pecking button on a wall) under particular conditions (when a red light but not a green light was illuminated) to obtain food, we assemble information in the world to create knowledge in our minds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Woodruff, E., &amp; Meyer, K. (1997). Explanations from intra- and inter-group discourse</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-28-woodruff1997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-28-woodruff1997/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Woodruff1997
Woodruff, E., &amp;amp; Meyer, K. (1997). Explanations from intra- and inter-group discourse: Students building knowledge in the science classroom. Research in Science Education, 27(1), 25–39. doi:10.1007/BF02463030
Notes An earlier paper on science education following the &amp;ldquo;progressive discourse&amp;rdquo; approach.
Highlights We have conducted three separate studies in science classrooms that implemented this approach within a science unit. Across the studies we have varied the grade level of the students (grade five, grade seven), varied the topic of inquiry (images and shadows, density), and documented &amp;ldquo;on-line&amp;rdquo; inquiry discourse within a computer software environment called CSILE, standing for Computer Supported Intentional Learning Environment (Scardamalia, Bereiter, McLean, Swallow, &amp;amp; Woodruff, 1989) that networked small groups of students in the grade five class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Worsley - 2012 - Multimodal learning analytics</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-13-worsley2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-13-worsley2012/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Worsley2012
Worsley, M. (2012). Multimodal learning analytics. In Proceedings of the 14th ACM international conference on Multimodal interaction - ICMI ’12 (p. 353). New York, New York, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;2388676.2388755
Notes Worsley&amp;rsquo;s brief description of his plan of dissertation work.
Highlights In order to develop a more appropriate measure and means for assessing SPBL I want to construct a complete picture of how learning takes place in SPBL environments through the use of multimodal learning interfaces and techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Xiong - 2011 - Bayesian prediction of tissue-regulated splicing using RNA sequence and cellular context</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-25-xiong15092011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-25-xiong15092011/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Xiong15092011
Xiong HY, Barash Y and Frey BJ (2011). “Bayesian prediction of tissue-regulated splicing using RNA sequence and cellular context.” Bioinformatics, 27(18), pp. 2554-2562. , http://bioinformatics.oxfordjournals.org/content/27/18/2554.full.pdf+html, .
Notes The Bayesian Neural Network technique created / reported in this article represents one of the new advances in neural network, which has some momentum in recent years. It would be interesting to test it in the educational setting, to compare its performance with techniques (like SVM) widely used in educational data mining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Yamagata-Lynch, L. C. (2010). Understanding Cultural Historical Activity Theory</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-07-10-yamagata-lynch2010-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-07-10-yamagata-lynch2010-eu/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Yamagata-Lynch2010-eu
Yamagata-Lynch, L. C. (2010). Understanding Cultural Historical Activity Theory. In Activity Systems Analysis Methods (pp. 13–26). Springer, Boston, MA. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4419-6321-5_2
Notes Summarize: This book chapter is a good &amp;lsquo;primer&amp;rsquo; for understanding activity systems analysis (as a methodology). It goes through the historical context of CHAT and AT back to Vygotsky, and provides useful guidance for researchers who wish to adopt activity systems analysis.
Highlights Reading and Understanding CHAT (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Yazan, (2015). Three Approaches to Case Study Methods in Education</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-01-18-yazan2015-wn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-01-18-yazan2015-wn/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Yazan2015-wn
Yazan, B. (2015). Three Approaches to Case Study Methods in Education: Yin, Merriam, and Stake. The Qualitative Report, 20(2), 134–152. Retrieved from http://nsuworks.nova.edu/tqr/vol20/iss2/12/?utm_source=nsuworks.nova.edu%2Ftqr%2Fvol20%2Fiss2%2F12&amp;amp;utm_medium=PDF&amp;amp;utm_campaign=PDFCoverPages
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Focusing on the landmark works of three prominent methodologists, namely Robert Yin, Sharan Merriam, Robert Stake, I attempt to scrutinize the areas where their perspectives diverge, converge and complement one another in varying dimensions of case study research. (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Zhang2016-ps-Understanding the dynamics of MOOC discussion forums with simulation investigation for empirical network analysis (SIENA)</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-01-zhang2016-ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-01-zhang2016-ps/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Zhang2016-ps
Zhang, J., Skryabin, M., &amp;amp; Song, X. (2016). Understanding the dynamics of MOOC discussion forums with simulation investigation for empirical network analysis (SIENA). Distance Education, 37(3), 270–286. https://doi.org/10.1080/01587919.2016.1226230
Notes Interesting and well-grounded study of MOOC forums using SIENA. It adopts a hypothesis-testing paradigm. The discussion of the literation is extensive and useful. The findings could be further discussed. For example, I would like to see the authors&amp;rsquo; discussion of why reciprocity declined across the time periods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Zheng. (2016). The role of social media in MOOCs</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-06-28-zheng2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-06-28-zheng2016/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Zheng2016
Zheng, S., Han, K., Rosson, M. B., &amp;amp; Carroll, J. M. (2016). The role of social media in MOOCs. In Proceedings of the Third (2016) ACM Conference on Learning @ Scale - L@S ’16 (pp. 419–428). New York, New York, USA: ACM Press. doi:10.1145&amp;frasl;2876034.2876047
Notes A nice paper investigating social media (more specifically Facebook groups) in three MOOCs. The key findings include that FB is a better place for social engagement, and students feel more connected, behave better, and interact more in FB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Zimmerman - 1990 - Self-regulated learning and academic achievement</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-03-31-zimmerman1990self/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-03-31-zimmerman1990self/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @zimmerman1990self
Zimmerman, B. J. (1990). Self-regulated learning and academic achievement: An overview. Educational Psychologist, 25(1), 3–17.
Notes Highlights the importance of individuals assuming personal responsibility and control for their own acquisition of knowledge and skill. (p. 2)
Gardner (1963), former Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, who suggested that (p. 2)
&amp;ldquo;the ultimate goal of the education system is shift to the individual the burden of pursuing his own education&amp;rdquo; (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Zimmerman - 1999 - A social cognitive perspective</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-04-01-zimmerman1999social/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-04-01-zimmerman1999social/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @zimmerman1999social
Zimmerman, B. J. (1999). Attaining self-regulation: A social cognitive perspective. In M. Boekaerts, M. Zeidner, &amp;amp; P. R. Pintrich (Eds.), Handbook of self-regulation. Elsevier Science. Retrieved from https://books.google.com/books?id=rv3DZSim6z4C
Notes Key take-aways:
 Triad: &amp;ldquo;A social cognitive perspective is distinctive in viewing self-regulation as an interaction of personal, behavioral, and environmental triadic processes&amp;rdquo; Cyclical phases: &amp;ldquo;From a social cognitive perspective, self-regulatory processes and accompanying beliefs fall into three cyclical phases: forethought, performance or volitional control, and self-reflection processes&amp;rdquo; Developmental Levels of Regulatory Skill: Observation, Emulation, Self-control, Self-regulation  Highlights This chapter will define self-regulation and will discuss the structure of self-regulatory systems, social and physical environmental context influences on self-regulation, dysfunctions in selfregulation, and self-regulatory development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Zimmerman. (1986). Development of a structured interview for assessing student use of self-regulated learning strategies</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-23-zimmerman1986-vd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-23-zimmerman1986-vd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Zimmerman1986-vd
Zimmerman, B. J., &amp;amp; Pons, M. M. (1986). Development of a structured interview for assessing student use of self-regulated learning strategies. American Educational Research Journal, 23(4), 614–628.
Notes Highlights High achieving students displayed significantly greater use of 13 cate- gories of self-regulated learning (p. 1)
Recently, several theoretical articles have sought to relate various views of self-regulated learning to academic moti- vation and achievement (Corno &amp;amp; Mandinach, 1983; McCombs, 1984; Schunk, 1984).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Zwitter. (2014). Big Data ethics</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-06-28-zwitter2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-06-28-zwitter2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Zwitter2014
Zwitter, A. (2014). Big Data ethics. Big Data &amp;amp; Society, 1(2). doi:10.1177&amp;frasl;2053951714559253
Notes A primer of Big Data ethics. Considering adding it to the reading list of the Tech &amp;amp; Ethics course.
Highlights Hence, much less commonly discussed are the ethical implications of impersonal data. Examples include, among others, the ‘‘likes’’ on Facebook sold to marketing companies in order to more specifically target certain micro-markets; information generated out of Twitter feed based sentiment analyses for political manipulation of groups, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: de Laat. (2007). Investigating patterns of interaction in networked learning and computer-supported collaborative learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-14-laat2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-14-laat2007/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Laat2007
de Laat, M., Lally, V., Lipponen, L., &amp;amp; Simons, R.-J. (2007). Investigating patterns of interaction in networked learning and computer-supported collaborative learning: A role for Social Network Analysis. International Journal of Computer-Supported Collaborative Learning, 2(1), 87–103. doi:10.1007/s11412-007-9006-4
Notes This paper is about applying SNA in analyzing CSCL (or networked learning as called in EU). What is unique about this study is it highlights the value of combining SNA with Content Analysis together, and put them both onto a timeline (considering the temporal dimension), to more holistically analyze CSCL processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 学习分析: 助推大数据时代高校教师在线专业发展</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-04-07-zhang14xuexi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-04-07-zhang14xuexi/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @zhang14xuexi
张进良, &amp;amp; 何高大. (2014). 学习分析: 助推大数据时代高校教师在线专业发展. 远程教育杂志, 32(1), 56–62.
Notes Highlights 学习分 析从以下四个方面促进大数据时代高校教师在线专业发展: 可以提升作为在线学习者的高校教师的学习效率, 激发其自主的专业发展意识;可以提高高校教师作为在线教学者的教学效率,发展其在线教学实践智慧;可以提 高高校教师作为研究者的研究绩效,提升其对学生在线学习的服务能力;可以提高高校教师作为管理者的管理 效率,提升其在线教学领导力。 (p. 1)
 what?
Talking about LA as a whole, vs. distinguishing different LA. (p. 2)
 学习分析不仅具有有益于学生学习的潜能,而 且对教师的教学也有帮助。 (p. 2)
 what
what? (p. 2)
 学习分析是一个破译来自教育大数据、 学生相 关系列数据的趋势和模式等领域, 其目的是进一步 发展个性化的、支持性的高等教育系统。 (p. 2)
大数据时代高等教育的变革 (p. 2)
(二)大数据时代高校教师应具备较强的数据分 析能力 (p. 3)
大数据引发了全球在线教育的热潮,MOOC 的出 现真正体现了高等教育的国际化,Coursera、edX、Udacity 等智能平台面向全世界提供知名高校的优质 课程 (p. 3)
但在大数据时代, 高校教师只具备基本的数字 化教学能力是远远不够的, 还应具有一定的数据分 析能力,以适应数据支持的决策文化。 (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 学习分析: 大学教学信息化研究与实践的新领域</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-04-07-li12xuexi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-04-07-li12xuexi/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @li12xuexi
李逢庆, &amp;amp; 钱万正. (2012). 学习分析: 大学教学信息化研究与实践的新领域. 现代教育技术, 7, 5–10.
Notes Highlights 我国学者顾小清等[5]也对学习分析 的概念、学习分析技术的发展以及其在未来教育中广泛的应 用前景以及巨大发展潜力做了较为系统的解读。本文将对学 习分析的内涵与外延做进一步的探讨和更加深入的阐释,并 尝试从推动大学教学创新的视角,阐释学习分析技术对促进 大学教学信息化深化发展的重要价值和深远影响。 (p. 1)
一 学习分析的发展脉络梳理 (p. 1)
研究表明,尽管学习分析植根于两个与学习并没有直 接联系的领域,即:商业智能(Business Intelligence)和网站 分析(Web Analytics),其目的是了解组织内部的数据以及外 部的客户行为之间的关系。但是它们在推动学习分析形成的 过程中扮演了举足轻重的角色。6
1 知识管理视角下的商业智能技术 (p. 1)
2 网站访客行为研究的网站分析 (p. 2)
3 学术分析与行动分析 (p. 2)
二 学习分析的内涵解读 (p. 2)
2 学习分析的构成要素 (p. 3)
Campbell 和 Oblinger[20]认为学术分析应包含五个步骤: 采集、报告、预测、行动和提炼。 (p. 3)
Tanya Elias则在Campbell and Oblinger[21]提出的学术分析 五步骤的基础上,提出强调分析过程循环本质的三阶段五个 层面的模型,进一步将学习分析的过程具体为七个步骤,即: 筛选、捕捉、收集和报告、预测、应用、提炼、分享。 (p. 3)
三 学习分析的过程、工具与方法 (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 学习分析: 正在浮现中的数据技术</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-04-07-%E9%A1%BE%E5%B0%8F%E6%B8%852012%E5%AD%A6%E4%B9%A0%E5%88%86%E6%9E%90/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-04-07-%E9%A1%BE%E5%B0%8F%E6%B8%852012%E5%AD%A6%E4%B9%A0%E5%88%86%E6%9E%90/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @顾小清2012学习分析
顾小清, 张进良, &amp;amp; 蔡慧英. (2012). 学习分析: 正在浮现中的数据技术. 远程教育杂志, (1), 18–25.
Notes Highlights 教育工作者利用数据考核、分析和评估教学和学习已有 悠久历史,随着参与网络学习的人数和支持网络学习活动的 工具种类的剧增,有关学习行为数据的数量不断增多并具多 样性。 (p. 1)
1.学习分析技术的定义 (p. 2)
EDUCAUSE 研究机构对学习分析技术的界定是:学习 分析技术就是利用数据和模型,预测学习者在学习中的进步 和表现,预测未来表现和发现潜在问题[12]。 (p. 2)
2.学习分析技术的要素 (p. 2)
从纵向发展角度来看,学习分析技术是 CMI 与DDDM 发 展的产物,而从横向发展角度来看,学习分析技术又是网络 分析技术(web analytics)与学术分析技术(academic analytics) 综合应用的结果。 (p. 3)
(5)多元化的理论基础。 学习分析技术的理论基础包括 分析理论和实践知识两部分:第一是协同过滤算法、贝叶斯 网络、关联规则挖掘、聚类、基于知识的建议和协同过滤算法 等理论的有效分析方法和技术。 第二是与学习理论、良好的 教学实践、知识共同体的构建、学生的学习动机、毅力和动机 等知识积累的相关领域[17]。 (p. 3)
(二)学习分析技术中的关键技术 (p. 4)
 伦理问题
不知是隐私问题，还涉及ethical use of results (p. 6)
 隐私问题 (p. 6)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 学习分析学：智慧教育的科学力量</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-04-07-zhu13xue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-04-07-zhu13xue/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @zhu13xue
祝智庭, &amp;amp; 沈德梅. (2013). 学习分析学：智慧教育的科学力量. 电化教育研究, 5, 3.
Notes Highlights LA 在国际上被称为是 “自从学习管理系统 (Learning Management System, 简 称 LMS) 问 世 以 来 , 教育技术大规模发展的第三次浪潮”。 8
第四,LA 起源于其他几个已经相对成熟的领域,如 商 务 智 能 (Business Intelligence)、 网 站 分 析 (Web Analysis)、 学 术 分 析 (Academic Analysis)、 行 动 分 析 (Action Analysis)、 教 育 数 据 挖 掘 (Educational Data Mining)、运筹学(Operational Research)[19][20]以及社会网络 分析(Social Network Analysis)等。 (p. 2)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: 访谈学习分析研究专家George Siemens教授</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-04-07-wei13xue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-04-07-wei13xue/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @wei13xue
魏雪峰, &amp;amp; 宋灵青. (2013). 学习分析: 更好地理解学生个性化学习过程&amp;mdash;访谈学习分析研究专家George Siemens教授. 中国电化教育, (9), 1–4.
Notes Highlights 学习分析产生的背景是什么?学习分析与教育数据挖掘的区别如何?学习分析过 程中如何保护个人隐私? (p. 1)
Siemens:学习分析包含丰富的内容,有时 (p. 1)
涉及复杂预测模型,有时涉及日常任务,如课堂 分配和能源保护等。 (p. 2)
那么学习分析与教育数据挖掘 (Education Data Mining,EDM)有什么区别呢? (p. 2)
国际教育数据挖掘协会 (International Educational Data Mining Society, IEDMS) 目前正在开展通过设计算法和开发技术来理解学习 过程的工作。 (p. 2)
学习分析从根本上是收集和 测量学生学习过程中产生的数据。然后我们将分析 结果反馈给学习者、研究机构以及教育工作者。我 们的目标是更好地理解学习发生的过程,进而考虑 如何改进学习经历或学习发生的环境,以上就是学 习分析的定义。简单地说,就是分析、揭示学生学 习过程中产生数据所包含的信息。 (p. 2)
在温哥华召开的第二届学习和知 识分析国际大会上,强调了教育数据挖掘与学习分 析的联系。 (p. 2)
学习分析是如何产生的呢?我认为有很多原 因,其中最主要的原因是现在可获取的大量数据。 (p. 2)
基于这些学习活动, 我们可以开始构建学习者模型,进而推测哪些学生 可能存在辍学危险;通过评估学生已具备的知识, 我们可以寻找个性化学习的方法,进而帮助学生知 道下一步应该学什么。 (p. 2)
学习分析与教育数据挖掘也存在不同。教育数 据挖掘实际上强调自动发现,因此,它侧重于模型 和发现模式。学习分析尽管也强调自动发现,但同 时还需要人为干预。 (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding students practical epistemologies and their influence on learning through inquiry</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-06-07-sandoval2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-06-07-sandoval2005/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @sandoval2005
Sandoval, W. A. (2005). Understanding students’ practical epistemologies and their influence on learning through inquiry. Science Education, 89(4), 634–656. doi:10.1002/sce.20065
Raw notes Page: 9 Page: 9 What the above studies and others show is that students at all age levels commonly have inarticulate ideas about the nature and role of scientiﬁc experimentation, and the relation between method and theory.
Page: 9 Methods of Science.
Page: 9 Although Deanna Kuhn has argued that most children, and even lay adults, fail to distinguish between theories and evidence (Kuhn, 1993; Kuhn et al.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>