<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Openness on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/openness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Openness on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/openness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ongoing Experiment: Public Scholarly Annotation</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-07-public-scholarly-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-07-public-scholarly-annotation/</guid>
      <description>Background stories I value Open Scholarship and have been practicing it for years &amp;ndash; both in terms of doing it and learning to do it. Stian Haklev, an OER and Open Access champion, introduced me to this idea. He built a wiki-based workflow system, named researchr, and convinced a few OISE friends, including Cresencia Fong and Alisa Acosta, to share our annotations publicly, in a well-organized manner. For us, the benefits of using researchr are obvious: the system scaffolds the scholarly process of reading and annotating articles, as well as summarizing and organizing our notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MOOCs, Open Universities, and Learning Analytics in Asia</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-11-03-trip-to-asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-11-03-trip-to-asia/</guid>
      <description>My October ended with a trip to Asia &amp;ndash; Beijing and Manila this time. Visiting Beijing was like going back to an ever-changing hometown, while visiting Manila (where I&amp;rsquo;ve never been before) was like venturing into a rain forest. Both very exciting!
MOOCs in China: Research and Practice Three days in Beijing was filled by a busy MOOC conference agenda, working meetings at the X-Learning Center on a MOOC project, and casual exchanges with graduate students at the Graduate School of Education at Peking University.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>