<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inquiry learning on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/inquiry-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inquiry learning on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/inquiry-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Pursuit of explanation within a computer-supported classroom</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-10-04-hakkarainen2004a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-10-04-hakkarainen2004a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @hakkarainen2004a
Hakkarainen, K. (2004). Pursuit of explanation within a computer-supported classroom. International Journal of Science Education, 26(8), 979–996. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;1468181032000354
Notes The purpose of the study is to analyse whether elementary school children, collaborating within a computer-supported classroom, may profitably participate in research-like processes of inquiry that characterize practices of scientific research. The problem addressed in the study is whether 10-year-old and 11-year-old children, in appropriate circumstances, engage in working with knowledge at a deep level of explanation instead of processing only factual and descriptive knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding students practical epistemologies and their influence on learning through inquiry</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-06-07-sandoval2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-06-07-sandoval2005/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @sandoval2005
Sandoval, W. A. (2005). Understanding students’ practical epistemologies and their influence on learning through inquiry. Science Education, 89(4), 634–656. doi:10.1002/sce.20065
Raw notes Page: 9 Page: 9 What the above studies and others show is that students at all age levels commonly have inarticulate ideas about the nature and role of scientiﬁc experimentation, and the relation between method and theory.
Page: 9 Methods of Science.
Page: 9 Although Deanna Kuhn has argued that most children, and even lay adults, fail to distinguish between theories and evidence (Kuhn, 1993; Kuhn et al.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>