<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Literacy on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/literacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literacy on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/literacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards A Longitudinal Understanding of the Growth of Productive Vocabulary in Knowledge Building</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-02-04-longitudinal-productive-vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-02-04-longitudinal-productive-vocabulary/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;My theory is that it&amp;rsquo;s all about gravity. The groundwater stays down by gravity!&amp;rdquo; (Grade one, Water unit)
&amp;ldquo;Because the plane is so big and heavy it is hard to reduce gravity because gravity can be taken away better if there are lighter, stronger materials.&amp;rdquo; (Grade two, Flight unit)
&amp;ldquo;How does gravity work? Is it a force in the ground that pulls you down or something in the air that pushes you down?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ford-Connors - 2015 - Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-11-ford-connors2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-11-ford-connors2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ford-Connors2015
Ford-Connors, E., &amp;amp; Paratore, J. R. (2015). Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond: Sources of Word Learning and Productive Contexts for Development. Review of Educational Research, 85(1), 50–91. doi:10.3102&amp;frasl;0034654314540943
Notes This article provides a comprehensive and balanced review of vocabulary instruction focusing on two aspects: (1) sources of word learning, and (2) productive contexts for vocabulary learning. This review is based upon the notion that word learning is complex, multidimensional, and incremental.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Graesser - 2011 - Coh-Metrix</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-17-graesser2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-17-graesser2011/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Graesser2011
Graesser, A. C., McNamara, D. S., &amp;amp; Kulikowich, J. M. (2011). Coh-Metrix: Providing Multilevel Analyses of Text Characteristics. Educational Researcher, 40(5), 223–234. doi:10.3102/0013189X11413260
Notes An overview of measures provided by Coh-Metrix.
Highlights Two important caveats must be raised before describing the computer analyses of text characteristics. First, computers obviously cannot identify and scale texts on all levels of language, discourse, and meaning. Available computer systems cannot fully comprehend the deep metaphors, literary devices, and historical contexts of Shakespeare’s plays, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Haneda, M., &amp; Wells, G. (2000). Writing in knowledge-building communities</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-26-haneda2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-26-haneda2000/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Haneda2000
Haneda, M., &amp;amp; Wells, G. (2000). Writing in knowledge-building communities. Research in the Teaching of English, 34(3), 430–457. Retrieved from http://www.jstor.org/stable/40171501
Notes This position piece articulates how writing is perceived and supported in knowledge building. It presents a thorough discussion of &amp;ldquo;current&amp;rdquo; understanding in writing, gaps in writing instruction, and the role Knowledge Building plays in writing (and roles writing plays in knowledge building). It also presents three examples of writing in knowledge building communities, in which roles of teachers and technology are explored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hickey. (2010). Participatory assessment of 21st century proficiencies</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-06-24-shute2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-06-24-shute2010/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hickey2010
Hickey, D. T., Honeyford, M. A., Clinton, K. A., &amp;amp; McWilliams, J. (2010). Participatory assessment of 21st century proficiencies. In V. J. Shute &amp;amp; B. J. Becker (Eds.), Innovative assessment for the 21st century (pp. 107–138). Springer. doi:10.1007&amp;frasl;978-1-4419-6530-1
Notes Highlights 8.1 New Media the Technology Proficiencies and Schools (p. 109)
Recent studies reveal the tremendous levels of “hanging out, messing around, and geeking out” in friendship-driven and interest-driven social networks (Ito, 2008).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hickey. (2011). Reading Moby-Dick in a Participatory Culture</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-06-24-hickey2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-06-24-hickey2011/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hickey2011
Hickey, D. T., McWilliams, J., &amp;amp; Honeyford, M. A. (2011). Reading Moby-Dick in a Participatory Culture: Organizing Assessment for Engagement in a New Media Era. Journal of Educational Computing Research, 45(2), 247–263. doi:10.2190/EC.45.2.g
Notes Highlights This article identifies discrepancies between traditional instructional practices that emphasize individual mastery of abstract concepts and skills and new media literacy practices that rely upon collaborative, social, and context-specific activity. (p. 1)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Kucirkova. (2015). A Vygotskian perspective on parent-child talk during iPad story sharing</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-04-11-kucirkova2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-04-11-kucirkova2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Kucirkova2015
Kucirkova, N., Sheehy, K., &amp;amp; Messer, D. (2015). A Vygotskian perspective on parent-child talk during iPad story sharing. Journal of Research in Reading, 38(4), 428–441. doi:10.1111&amp;frasl;1467-9817.12030
Notes An interesting study exploring themes of interactions in parent-child talk during iPad story sharing/creation. The analysis was largely informed by Vygotsky’s learning theory focusing on ZPD, dual representation and double stimulation. While results offer insights about parent-child talk in an interesting story-creation iPad app (something less common in traditional storytelling reading research), this study also challenges the Vygotskian frame&amp;rsquo;s explanatory power in this novel context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Laufer - 1994 - The Lexical Profile of Second Language Writing: Does It Change Over Time?</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-10-30-laufer01121994/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-10-30-laufer01121994/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Laufer01121994
Laufer B (1994). “The Lexical Profile of Second Language Writing: Does It Change Over Time?” RELC Journal, 25(2), pp. 21-33. , http://rel.sagepub.com/content/25/2/21.full.pdf+html, .
Notes One of the classic studies by Laufer around Lexical Frequency Profile.
Highlights lexical richness, (p. 2)
lexical variation. (p. 2)
lexical acquisition research would have to account for the gradual increase in the learner’s vocabulary size, as the most striking difference between the vocabulary of native speakers and that of language learners is in the number of words they can control, particularly in free production: speech or writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Laufer - 2013 - Lexical Frequency Profiles</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-11-04-laufer2013lexical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-11-04-laufer2013lexical/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @laufer2013lexical
Laufer B (2013). “Lexical Frequency Profiles.” In Chapelle CA (ed.), The Encyclopedia of Applied Linguistics. Blackwell Publishing Ltd.
Notes A encyclopedia entry about Lexical Frequency Profiles. Laufer explains the assumption, concepts, and tools nicely.
 Assumption: A large number of infrequent words would make a text more difficult to understand. More advanced learners could use a higher percentage of infrequent vocabulary than learners of lower proficiencies. Concepts: Knowledge is taken to be the information about a word which is stored and interconnected in the mental lexicon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lee2013-sl: Science and language for English language learners in relation to Next Generation Science Standards and with implications for Common Core State Standards for English language arts and mathematics</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2013-sl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2013-sl/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lee2013-sl
Lee, O., Quinn, H., &amp;amp; Valdés, G. (2013). Science and language for English language learners in relation to Next Generation Science Standards and with implications for Common Core State Standards for English language arts and mathematics. Educational Researcher , 42(4), 223–233. Retrieved from http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X13480524
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights By examining intersections between learning of science and learning of language, the article identifies key features of the language of the science classroom as students engage in these language-intensive science and engineering practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Lee2017-xm: Common Core State Standards for ELA/Literacy and Next Generation Science Standards</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2017-xm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-22-lee2017-xm/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Lee2017-xm
Lee, O. (2017). Common Core State Standards for ELA/Literacy and Next Generation Science Standards: Convergences and Discrepancies Using Argument as an Example. Educational Researcher , 46(2), 90–102. Retrieved from http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.3102/0013189X17699172
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Unlike pre-CCSS standards developed within each subject area, the new standards highlight connections across subject areas (Stage, Asturias, Cheuk, Daro, &amp;amp; Hampton, 2013). (p. 1)
While ELA is traditionally associated with literary texts, the CCSS emphasize informational texts (Pearson, 2013) (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Meara - 2000 - Lex30: an improved method of assessing productive vocabulary in an L2</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-11-09-meara2000lex30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-11-09-meara2000lex30/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @meara2000lex30
Meara P and Fitzpatrick T (2000). “Lex30: an improved method of assessing productive vocabulary in an L2.” System, 28(1), pp. 19-30.
Notes Highlights Unfortunately, it is much more dicult to assess productive vocabulary knowledge than it is to assess receptive vocabulary knowledge. The main reason for this is that the vocabulary produced by a learner, whether in written or spoken form, tends to be so context-speci®c that it is dicult to calculate from any small sample the true size or range of the learner&amp;rsquo;s productive vocabulary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Meara - 2001 - P-Lex: A Simple and Effective Way of Describing the lexical Characteristics of Short L2 Tests.</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-11-10-meara2001p/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-11-10-meara2001p/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @meara2001p
Meara P and Bell H (2001). “P-Lex: A Simple and Effective Way of Describing the lexical Characteristics of Short L2 Tests.” Prospect, 16(3), pp. 5-19.
Notes This article introduces a novel way to assess productive vocabulary &amp;ndash; P-LeX &amp;ndash; which is better at handling shorter text (in comparison with LFP) and easier to interpret.
Highlights ABSTRACT This paper describes an alternative approach to assessing the lexical complexity of short texts produced by second language learners of English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Pelletier, J., Reeve, R., &amp; Halewood, C. (2006). Young children’s knowledge building and literacy development through Knowledge Forum</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-03-pelletier2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-03-pelletier2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Pelletier2006
Pelletier, J., Reeve, R., &amp;amp; Halewood, C. (2006). Young children’s knowledge building and literacy development through Knowledge Forum{\textregistered}. Early Education and Development, 17(3), 323–346.
Notes Highlights the literacy development of 4-year-old children in a laboratory school (p. 2)
Over the course of the year, children participated in a longitudinal photo journal project. With adult support, children posted their photo journals and ideas to KF® in the form of electronic “notes,” which allowed children to view each other’s work and to build on ideas by posting their responses and comments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>