<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Temporal on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/temporal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Temporal on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/temporal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Carley. (2003). Dynamic network analysis</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-02-08-carley2003-zk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-02-08-carley2003-zk/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Carley2003-zk
Carley, K. M. (2003). Dynamic network analysis. In R. Breiger, K. Carley, &amp;amp; P. Pattison (Eds.), Dynamic Social Network Modeling and Analysis: Workshop Summary and Papers (pp. 133–145). Washington, DC: National Academies Press. Retrieved from http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.299.8946&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Clearly social network analysis can be applied to the study of covert networks (Sparrow, 1991). Many are stepping forward suggesting that to understand these networks we just need to “connect the dots” and then isolate the “key actors who are often defined in terms of their “centrality” in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Jiang. (2013). Mining the Temporal Evolution of the Android Bug Reporting Community via Sliding Windows</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-10-02-jiang2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-10-02-jiang2013/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Jiang2013
Jiang, F., Wang, J., Hindle, A., &amp;amp; Nascimento, M. A. (2013). Mining the Temporal Evolution of the Android Bug Reporting Community via Sliding Windows. CoRR, abs/1310.7. Retrieved from http://arxiv.org/abs/1310.7469
Notes This paper reports a study of applying an interesting sliding-windows social network analysis on Android bug reporting community. This technique shows clear advantage in comparison with global analysis of social networks in that it takes temporal information into consideration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Oliveira. (2014). Dynamic communities in evolving customer networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-10-02-oliveira2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-10-02-oliveira2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Oliveira2014
Oliveira, M., Guerreiro, A., &amp;amp; Gama, J. (2014). Dynamic communities in evolving customer networks: an analysis using landmark and sliding windows. Social Network Analysis and Mining, 4(1), 208. doi:10.1007/s13278-014-0208-2
Notes This article contrasts two kinds of dynamic network analysis&amp;mdash;landmark window and sliding window&amp;mdash;by applying both approaches to analysis of a customer network. Besides comparisons of well-known network metrics (e.g., centrality, density), it also tracks development of sub-communities in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>