<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vocabulary on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/vocabulary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vocabulary on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/vocabulary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Olinghouse2013-yd: The relationship between vocabulary and writing quality in three genres</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-20-olinghouse2013-yd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-20-olinghouse2013-yd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Olinghouse2013-yd
Olinghouse, N. G., &amp;amp; Wilson, J. (2013). The relationship between vocabulary and writing quality in three genres. Reading and Writing, 26(1), 45–65. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11145-012-9392-5
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Abstract The purpose of this study was to examine the role of vocabulary in writing across three genres. Fifth graders (N = 105) wrote three compositions: story, persuasive, and informative. Each composition revolved around the topic of outer space to control for background knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ford-Connors2015-dd: Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond: Sources of Word Learning and Productive Contexts for Development</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-09-18-ford-connors2015-dd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-09-18-ford-connors2015-dd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ford-Connors2015-dd
Ford-Connors, E., &amp;amp; Paratore, J. R. (2015). Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond: Sources of Word Learning and Productive Contexts for Development. Review of Educational Research, 85(1), 50–91. https://doi.org/10.3102/0034654314540943
Notes Summarize:
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Synthesizing the literature around the general topics of vocabu- lary instruction, classroom discourse, and teacher talk, this review provides a comprehensive and critical examination of instruction that supports vocab- ulary learning in older students with a particular focus on practices that promote productive discussions of content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Ford-Connors - 2015 - Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-11-ford-connors2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-11-ford-connors2015/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Ford-Connors2015
Ford-Connors, E., &amp;amp; Paratore, J. R. (2015). Vocabulary Instruction in Fifth Grade and Beyond: Sources of Word Learning and Productive Contexts for Development. Review of Educational Research, 85(1), 50–91. doi:10.3102&amp;frasl;0034654314540943
Notes This article provides a comprehensive and balanced review of vocabulary instruction focusing on two aspects: (1) sources of word learning, and (2) productive contexts for vocabulary learning. This review is based upon the notion that word learning is complex, multidimensional, and incremental.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Meara - 2000 - Lex30: an improved method of assessing productive vocabulary in an L2</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-11-09-meara2000lex30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-11-09-meara2000lex30/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @meara2000lex30
Meara P and Fitzpatrick T (2000). “Lex30: an improved method of assessing productive vocabulary in an L2.” System, 28(1), pp. 19-30.
Notes Highlights Unfortunately, it is much more dicult to assess productive vocabulary knowledge than it is to assess receptive vocabulary knowledge. The main reason for this is that the vocabulary produced by a learner, whether in written or spoken form, tends to be so context-speci®c that it is dicult to calculate from any small sample the true size or range of the learner&amp;rsquo;s productive vocabulary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Meara - 2001 - P-Lex: A Simple and Effective Way of Describing the lexical Characteristics of Short L2 Tests.</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-11-10-meara2001p/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-11-10-meara2001p/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @meara2001p
Meara P and Bell H (2001). “P-Lex: A Simple and Effective Way of Describing the lexical Characteristics of Short L2 Tests.” Prospect, 16(3), pp. 5-19.
Notes This article introduces a novel way to assess productive vocabulary &amp;ndash; P-LeX &amp;ndash; which is better at handling shorter text (in comparison with LFP) and easier to interpret.
Highlights ABSTRACT This paper describes an alternative approach to assessing the lexical complexity of short texts produced by second language learners of English.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>