<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rigor on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/rigor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rigor on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rigor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Gutiérrez &amp; Penuel (2014). Relevance to Practice as a Criterion for Rigor</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-23-gutierrez2014-qm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-23-gutierrez2014-qm/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Gutierrez2014-qm
Gutiérrez, K. D., &amp;amp; Penuel, W. R. (2014). Relevance to Practice as a Criterion for Rigor. Educational Researcher , 43(1), 19–23.
Notes Highlights The authors argue for a reconceptualization of rigor that requires sustained, direct, and systematic documentation of what takes place inside programs to document how students and teachers change and adapt interventions in interactions with each other in relation to their dynamic local contexts. (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Rudolph, J. L. (2014). Why Understanding Science Matters: The IES Research Guidelines as a Case in Point</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-23-rudolph2014-fd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-23-rudolph2014-fd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Rudolph2014-fd
Rudolph, J. L. (2014). Why Understanding Science Matters: The IES Research Guidelines as a Case in Point. Educational Researcher , 43(1), 15–18.
Notes Highlights “appropriate empirical evaluation” that can identify those things that “are in fact improvements,” that will in turn “contribute to the bigger pic- ture of scientific knowledge” (p. 11). (p. 1)
s far back as the 1950s (as many education researchers well know), federal efforts to reshape education drew on research practices and organiza- tional approaches from the natural sciences, where instrumental success and cumulative progress are the norms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Wieman, C. E. (2014). The Similarities Between Research in Education and Research in the Hard Sciences</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-09-23-wieman2014-vd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-09-23-wieman2014-vd/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Wieman2014-vd
Wieman, C. E. (2014). The Similarities Between Research in Education and Research in the Hard Sciences. Educational Researcher , 43(1), 12–14.
Notes Highlights Here I would like to offer a different perspective, how there is a considerable degree of similarity between research in the hard sciences and education, and how this provides a useful lens for thinking about what constitutes “rigorous” and “scientific” education research. (p. 1)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>