<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moocs on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/moocs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Moocs on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/moocs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Guo. (2014). Demographic Differences in How Students Navigate Through MOOCs</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-26-guo2014-ve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-26-guo2014-ve/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Guo2014-ve
Guo, P. J., &amp;amp; Reinecke, K. (2014). Demographic Differences in How Students Navigate Through MOOCs. In Proceedings of the First ACM Conference on Learning @ Scale Conference (pp. 21–30). New York, NY, USA: ACM.
Notes A nice study exploring demographic differences (age, gender, country origin) among MOOC learners. Interesting findings that many learners skipped a significant portion of course content, navigated in a non-linear manner, etc., pointing to opportunities for future research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Littlejohn - 2016 - Learning in MOOCs: Motivations and self-regulated learning in MOOCs</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-08-26-littlejohn2016-um/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-08-26-littlejohn2016-um/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Littlejohn2016-um
Littlejohn, A., Hood, N., Milligan, C., &amp;amp; Mustain, P. (2016&amp;frasl;4). Learning in MOOCs: Motivations and self-regulated learning in MOOCs. The Internet and Higher Education, 29, 40–48.
Notes Nice research investigating SRL in MOOCs. Survey used for measuring SRL of learners; interviews were used to understand learners in greater details.
No use of clicklog data to triangulate these findings could be a future direction.
Highlights Massive open online courses (MOOCs) require individual learners to be able to self-regulate their learning, determining when and how they engage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>