<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CanvasNet: Formative feedback for &#39;social learning&#39; on Canvas</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-11-19-canvasnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-11-19-canvasnet/</guid>
      <description>I have been teaching an undergraduate course using Canvas this semester. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how it happened because I&amp;rsquo;m essentially a disbeliever in Learning Management Systems (LMS). I believe one&amp;rsquo;s learning should not be managed. &amp;ldquo;LMS is the minivan of Education,&amp;rdquo; says Phil Hill. Even better, &amp;ldquo;the LMS is more like a bus than a minivan - someone else is driving, it only travels on a pre-arranged route, the bus is often late but you still have to be on time because it won&amp;rsquo;t wait if you miss it&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; says Stephen Downes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>link>/blog/2013-12-09-mongodb-java-r-a-handy-toolbox-for-archiving-and-analyzing-twitter-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-12-09-mongodb-java-r-a-handy-toolbox-for-archiving-and-analyzing-twitter-data/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Martin Hawksey&amp;rsquo;s brilliant Google Spreadsheet TAGS for archiving Twitter data for y-e-a-r-s. It works very well, and allowed me to develop little R toys like twitterytics-shiny to interactively explore Twitter archives.
However, I have a few complains. First, Twitter API authentication needs to be set up for each archive. The task which require a few steps in Google Spreadsheet is not trivial. Second, I often ended up getting hundreds or even thousands of duplicates that may cause the file size to exceed Google Spreadsheet&amp;rsquo;s size limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyze Text Similarity with R: Latent Semantic Analysis and Multidimentional Scaling</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-03-11-analyze-text-similarity-in-r-latent-semantic-analysis-and-multidimentional-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-03-11-analyze-text-similarity-in-r-latent-semantic-analysis-and-multidimentional-scaling/</guid>
      <description>Background One of the most pressing questions I have been pondering upon when redesigning Knowledge Forum is how to represent the knowledge space of a community to better support idea improvement. Many people think Knowledge Forum as another discussion forum (or learning management system) with a 2-D interface (see below). This notion lead people to treat a Knowledge Forum view merely as a container of notes. The reason why this happens is because users usually fail to recognize one important principle behind the design of Knowledge Forum view: to support multiple perspectives of community knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo of Using twitter-hashtag-analytics to Analyze Tweets from #LAK13</title>
      <link>/blog/2013-02-26-demo-of-using-twitter-hashtag-analytics-package-to-analyze-tweets-from-lak13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013-02-26-demo-of-using-twitter-hashtag-analytics-package-to-analyze-tweets-from-lak13/</guid>
      <description>Building on Ben Marwick, Martin Hawksey and Tony Hirst&amp;rsquo;s work on analyzing tweets with R, I started an R project for tweet analysis, namely twitter-hashtag-analytics. This project is hosted on Github and welcomes anyone who&amp;rsquo;s interested to contribute. It is my very first attempt to write a package in R, so I admit the capabilities of it is still limited and its structure may be not properly planned. Any advice will be highly appreciated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>