<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social network on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/social-network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social network on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/social-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Choudhury - 2004 - Characterizing social interactions using the sociometer</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-27-choudhury2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-27-choudhury2004/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Choudhury2004
Choudhury, T., &amp;amp; Pentland, A. (2004). Characterizing social interactions using the sociometer. Proceedings of NAACOS, 1–4. Retrieved from http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.153.7399&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf
Notes A much earlier version of sociometers when they only measure voices for conversation and turn-taking.
Highlights SENSING &amp;amp; MODELING HUMAN NETWORKS (p. 1)
This paper describes our work in developing a computational framework to model face-to-face interactions within a community. We have integrated methods from speech processing and machine learning to demonstrate that it is possible to extract information about people’s patterns of communication, without imposing any restriction on the user’s interactions or environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Goel. (2014). Predicting Individual Behavior with Social Networks</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-09-30-goel2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-09-30-goel2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Goel2014
Goel, S., &amp;amp; Goldstein, D. G. (2014). Predicting Individual Behavior with Social Networks. Marketing Science, 33(1), 82–93. doi:10.1287/mksc.2013.0817
Notes Highlights For over a decade, online marketers have predicted behavior at the individual level using variables such as age and sex (demographic targeting), location (geographic targeting), and website usage patterns (behavioral targeting). Today, ad servers can respond to the text of the page being viewed, be it a news story or personal email, and deliver ads on the fly that match page content (contextual targeting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Onnela - 2014 - Using sociometers to quantify social interaction patterns</title>
      <link>/notes/2015-08-27-onnela2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2015-08-27-onnela2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Onnela2014
Onnela, J.-P., Waber, B. N., Pentland, A., Schnorf, S., &amp;amp; Lazer, D. (2014). Using sociometers to quantify social interaction patterns. Scientific Reports, 4, 1–8. doi:10.1038/srep05604
Notes One of the most clear description of how sociometers work. Study focuses on gender difference in terms of proximity and talkativeness. &amp;ldquo;The strongest effect discovered in our study is the difference in gender participation as a function of tie strength and group size.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>