<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Knowledge building on Bodong Chen</title>
    <link>/tags/knowledge-building/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Knowledge building on Bodong Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/knowledge-building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Engestrom. (2009). The future of activity theory</title>
      <link>/notes/2017-04-04-engestrom2009-fq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2017-04-04-engestrom2009-fq/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Engestrom2009-fq
Engeström, Y. (2009). The future of activity theory: A rough draft. Learning and Expanding with Activity Theory, 303–328. Retrieved from https://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;id=pyY5EusnjBcC&amp;amp;oi=fnd&amp;amp;pg=PA303&amp;amp;dq=the+future+of+activity+theory&amp;amp;ots=KRW_JyuHpy&amp;amp;sig=mvpfOxH73y4RFSPYguo4CrM0LDY
Notes Summarize: A thoughtful piece that explains AT deeply and also explores its neighboring concepts.
Assess:
Reflect:
Highlights Recently Aaro Toomela has published two papers in which he critically assesses the contents and potential of activity theory. The first one is titled ’Activity theory is a dead end for cultural-historical psychology’ (Toomela, 2000), the second one ’Activity theory is a dead end for methodological thinking in cultural psychology too’ (Toomela, 2008).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards A Longitudinal Understanding of the Growth of Productive Vocabulary in Knowledge Building</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-02-04-longitudinal-productive-vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-02-04-longitudinal-productive-vocabulary/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;My theory is that it&amp;rsquo;s all about gravity. The groundwater stays down by gravity!&amp;rdquo; (Grade one, Water unit)
&amp;ldquo;Because the plane is so big and heavy it is hard to reduce gravity because gravity can be taken away better if there are lighter, stronger materials.&amp;rdquo; (Grade two, Flight unit)
&amp;ldquo;How does gravity work? Is it a force in the ground that pulls you down or something in the air that pushes you down?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Course: Learning Analytics in the Knowledge Age</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-01-27-learning-analytics-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-01-27-learning-analytics-course/</guid>
      <description>There has been tons of learning going on for me after moving to Minnesota two months ago: getting used to the imperial unit system; finding out it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to purchase alcohol on Sundays; realizing we need to &amp;ldquo;import&amp;rdquo; our car; people actually can fly kites on lakes; and, of course, people don&amp;rsquo;t have the accent as in the movie Fargo :)&amp;hellip; It has been an amazing experience so far to get accustomed to MPLS (I am not saying &amp;ldquo;Twin Cities&amp;rdquo; because local Minnesotans prefer MPLS &amp;ndash; another lesson learned).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Forum API: A demo</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-06-06-knowledge-forum-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-06-06-knowledge-forum-api/</guid>
      <description>Knowledge Forum (KF) has been recognized as the founding software in the computer-supported collaborative learning (CSCL) community. And it was also one of the earliest to offer embedded analytic tools for formative assessment. Thanks to contributions from a broad international community, a number of analytic tools have been developed for KF, including a suite of embedded applets (e.g., Contributions, Social Networks, Semantic Overlap, Vocabulary Growth, and Lexical Analysis; see Teplovs et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promisingness Judgments by Grade 3s</title>
      <link>/blog/2011-09-16-promisingness-judgments-by-grade-3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011-09-16-promisingness-judgments-by-grade-3s/</guid>
      <description>I started working on a tool called &#34;Promising Ideas tool,&#34; firstly named as &#34;Big Ideas tool,&#34; one and a half years ago. It is an add-on to Knowledge Forum (KF), a knowledge-building environment used in many kinds of settings but mostly in primary schools. The Promising Ideas tool is really simple in terms of functionality. It looks like a lite and KF-confined version of Diigo or SparTag.us, which are both used for people to tag important information on the Web and leave traces for later-comers for better browsing heuristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The meaning of promisingness</title>
      <link>/blog/2011-05-25-meaning-of-promisingness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011-05-25-meaning-of-promisingness/</guid>
      <description>Although I have been using the word “promisingness” in my writing and conversations since last year, I am still not 100% percent sure about the meaning of it. When we discuss this concept with primary school teachers, they also found it not easy to grasp, let alone young kids (however, we are teaching this concept to grade 3s). This situation is not surprising because promisingness is not even recognized as a word in many popular dictionaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Knowledge Building with Open Educational Resources</title>
      <link>/blog/2010-12-24-integrate-knowledge-building-with-learning-in-open-educational-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2010-12-24-integrate-knowledge-building-with-learning-in-open-educational-resources/</guid>
      <description>Open Educational Resources Inspired by the MIT OpenCourseWare (OCW) which was launched in 2002, the open educational resources (OER) movement, which strives to “champion the sharing of knowledge worldwide to increase human intellectual capacity,” has rapidly expanded throughout the world and is becoming increasingly powerful in the era of knowledge creation and lifelong learning. Most OER projects to date have been concentrated on making quality educational content openly and freely accessible on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: An Exploration of Epistemological Understanding and Participation in Online Knowledge Building Communities</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-29-forrester2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-29-forrester2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @forrester2006
Notes Highlights References Forrester, B. (2006). An Exploration of Epistemological Understanding and Participation in Online Knowledge Building Communities. University of Toronto.
Notes Marlene recommended it to me, to inform me of my thinking on epistemological issues in KB and promisingness.
The idea of belief-mode vs. design-mode epistemology is interesting. (This thesis integrates Marlene&amp;rsquo;s analysis of Kuhn and Perry research, clarifying that it represents a belief-mode epistemology.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: CSILE/Knowledge Forum</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia2004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia2004/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia2004
Scardamalia, M. (2004). CSILE/Knowledge Forum. In A. Kovalchick &amp;amp; K. Dawson (Eds.), Education and technology: An encyclopedia (pp. 183–192). Santa Barbara, CA: ABC-CLIO.
Notes ::The origins of CSILE (Computer Supported Intentional Learning Environments) are in research on knowledge building, on the nature of expertise, and on the socio-cultural dynamics of innovation. CSILE was designed to (a) make advanced knowledge processes accessible to all participants, including children, (b) foster the creation and continual improvement of public artifacts or community knowledge (Scardamalia, 2002), and ( c ) provide a community space for carrying out this knowledge building work collaboratives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Chai, S. C., &amp; Khine, M. S. (2006). An Analysis of Interaction and Participation Patterns in Online Community</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-01-chai2006a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-01-chai2006a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Chai2006a
Chai, S. C., &amp;amp; Khine, M. S. (2006). An Analysis of Interaction and Participation Patterns in Online Community. Journal of Educational Technology &amp;amp; Society, 9(1), 250–261.
Notes Highlights Although the KBC model draws on the constructivist-oriented theories, researchers directly involved in developing KBC argued that the KBC has moved social-cultural framework beyond the acquisition of knowledge and appropriation of practices to that of creation of knowledge. (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Chan, C. K. K., &amp; van Aalst, J. (2006). Teacher Development through Computer‐supported Knowledge Building</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-03-chan2006b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-03-chan2006b/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Chan2006b
Chan, C. K. K., &amp;amp; van Aalst, J. (2006). Teacher Development through Computer‐supported Knowledge Building: Experience from Hong Kong and Canadian teachers. Teaching Education, 17(1), 7–26. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;10476210500527907
Notes Highlights We propose a framework for designing teacher education courses premised on the knowledge-building perspective developed by Scardamalia and Bereiter (2003) to illustrate how teacher education may encourage teachers to become inquirers and knowledge creators in a knowledge-building community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Community knowledge assessment in a knowledge building environment</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-07-18-hong2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-07-18-hong2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hong2014
Hong, H.-Y. and Scardamalia, M. (2014). Community knowledge assessment in a knowledge building environment. Computers &amp;amp; Education, 71:279–288.
Notes Highlights According to Stahl (2006) group cognition requires a theory of collaboration that takes the group as the unit of analysis rather than the individual. ‘Learning by groups’ is not the same as ‘learning in groups’ or individual learning through social processes. (p. 1)
1.1. Community knowledge (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Computer Support for Knowledge-Building Communities</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia1994/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia1994/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia1994
Scardamalia, M., &amp;amp; Bereiter, C. (1994). Computer Support for Knowledge-Building Communities. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 3(3), 265–283. doi:10.1207/s15327809jls0303_3
Notes It has seemed to us that a promising approach to school restructuring would start by examining how schools (including the high-achieving ones) limit knowledge-building potential. By addressing fundamental shortcom- ings, we may find it possible to do more than struggle to catch up.
 informal knowledge that has been found to characterize expert competence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Computer-supported intentional learning environments</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-16-scardamalia1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-16-scardamalia1989/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia1989
Scardamalia, M., Bereiter, C., Mclean, R. S., Swallow, J., &amp;amp; Woodruff, E. (1989). Computer-supported intentional learning environments. Journal of Educational Computing Research, 5(1), 51–68.
Notes This article explains design principles of CSILE. These principles are very much based on literature about successful learning. Comparing to knowledge building principles, they are very different in that they emphasize on learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Fostering epistemological beliefs and conceptual change in chemistry using knowledge building</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-10-04-lam2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-10-04-lam2008/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @lam2008
Lam, I., &amp;amp; Chan, C. K. K. (2008). Fostering epistemological beliefs and conceptual change in chemistry using knowledge building. In Proceedings of the 8th international conference on International conference for the learning sciences Volume 1 (Vol. 1, pp. 461–468). Utrecht, The Netherlands: International Society of the Learning Sciences. Retrieved from http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1599812.1599868
Clippings Abstract:
Various measures were collected at pre and posttests including epistemological beliefs, conceptual-change questions and online discourse and reflection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hakkarainen, K. (2003). Emergence of progressive-inquiry culture in computer-supported collaborative learning</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-01-hakkarainen2003a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-01-hakkarainen2003a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hakkarainen2003a
Hakkarainen, K. (2003). Emergence of progressive-inquiry culture in computer-supported collaborative learning. Learning Environments Research, 6(2), 199–220. doi:10.1023/a:1024995120180
Notes Highlights ABSTRACT. The study focused on analysing the emergence of a progressive-inquiry culture in two CSILE (Computer-Supported Intentional Learning Environment) classrooms across a three-year period. A principal feature of this kind of culture is the processing of explanatory knowledge instead of merely factual knowledge. The results of the study indicate that the classroom culture changed over the three years following the introduction of CSILE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Haneda, M., &amp; Wells, G. (2000). Writing in knowledge-building communities</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-26-haneda2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-26-haneda2000/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Haneda2000
Haneda, M., &amp;amp; Wells, G. (2000). Writing in knowledge-building communities. Research in the Teaching of English, 34(3), 430–457. Retrieved from http://www.jstor.org/stable/40171501
Notes This position piece articulates how writing is perceived and supported in knowledge building. It presents a thorough discussion of &amp;ldquo;current&amp;rdquo; understanding in writing, gaps in writing instruction, and the role Knowledge Building plays in writing (and roles writing plays in knowledge building). It also presents three examples of writing in knowledge building communities, in which roles of teachers and technology are explored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Hewitt, J., &amp; Scardamalia, M. (1998). Design principles for distributed knowledge building processes</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-22-hewitt1998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-22-hewitt1998/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Hewitt1998
Hewitt, J., &amp;amp; Scardamalia, M. (1998). Design principles for distributed knowledge building processes. Educational Psychology Review, 10(1), 75–96. doi:10.1023/A:1022810231840
Notes A great review article (sort of) that summarizes design principles of knowledge-building communities in the late 90s. Interesting insights into the historical development of KB as an ed approach.
Highlights In this paper we explore various interpretations of the term &amp;ldquo;distributed cognition,&amp;rdquo; then turn our attention to communities grounded in the practice of collaborative knowledge building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Higher Levels of Agency for Children in Knowledge Building</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-28-scardamalia1991/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-28-scardamalia1991/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia1991
Scardamalia, M., &amp;amp; Bereiter, C. (1991). Higher Levels of Agency for Children in Knowledge Building: A Challenge for the Design of New Knowledge Media. Journal of the Learning Sciences, 1(1), 37–68. doi:10.1207/s15327809jls0101_3
Notes This paper is particularly useful: * It connects agency with ZPD, and makes it clear KB turns more agency to students and lets students decide ZPD. * It reports a set of interesting studies on student questioning, especially the one examining whether students can pick promising questions from those generated by themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Knowledge Building as a Mediator of Conflict in Conceptual Change</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-09-28-chan1997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-09-28-chan1997/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @chan1997
Chan, C. K. K., Burtis, J., &amp;amp; Bereiter, C. (1997). Knowledge Building as a Mediator of Conflict in Conceptual Change. Cognition and Instruction (Vol. 15, pp. 1–40). doi:10.1207/s1532690xci1501_1
Abstract This study examined how individuals and peers process scientific information that contradicts what they believe and assessed the contribution of this activity to conceptual change. Participants included 54 students in Grade 9 and 54 students in Grade 12, who were randomly assigned to four conditions: (a) individual conflict, (b) peer conflict, &amp;copy; individual assimilation, and (d) peer assimilation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Knowledge Forum: altering the relationship between students and scientific knowledge</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-10-07-caswell2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-10-07-caswell2002/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @caswell2002
Caswell, B., &amp;amp; Bielaczyc, K. (2002). Knowledge Forum: altering the relationship between students and scientific knowledge. Education, Communication &amp;amp; Information, 1(3), 281–305. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;146363102753535240
Clips ABSTRACT This paper explores the use of Knowledge Forum, a networked computer program designed to support knowledge building communication and to foster thinking and learning skills. The paper focuses on a Grade 5&amp;frasl;6 classroom and looks at how students view scientic knowledge and what it means to learn science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Knowledge building: Theory, pedagogy, and technology</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-20-scardamalia2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia2006
Scardamalia, M., &amp;amp; Bereiter, C. (2006). Knowledge building: Theory, pedagogy, and technology. In R. K. Sawyer (Ed.), The Cambridge handbook of the learning sciences (pp. 97–115). Cambridge University Press.
Notes From Computer Supported Intentional Learning to Knowledge Building Environments  an elementary school (Scardamalia, Bereiter, McLean, Swallow, and Woodruff, 1989).   an elementary school (Scardamalia, Bereiter, McLean, Swallow, and Woodruff, 1989).   an elementary school (Scardamalia, Bereiter, McLean, Swallow, and Woodruff, 1989).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Oshima, J. (1998). Differences in Knowledge-Building Between Two Types of Networked Learning Environments</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-28-oshima1998/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-28-oshima1998/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Oshima1998
Oshima, J. (1998). Differences in Knowledge-Building Between Two Types of Networked Learning Environments: An Information-Flow Analysis. Journal of Educational Computing Research, 19(3), 329–351. doi:10.2190/YLLX-M9CW-15X9-BJJ9
Notes Interesting work comparing S-CSILE with D-CSILE. A probable indication of pedagogical transition from intentional learning to KB and also tech transition from CSILE to KF.
Coding schemes are also interesting &amp;ndash; revealing an earlier differentiation of referent vs. problem-based knowledge which gets less discussed in later literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Oshima. (2006). Knowledge-building activity structures in Japanese elementary science pedagogy</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-03-oshima2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-03-oshima2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Oshima2006
Oshima, J., Oshima, R., Murayama, I., Inagaki, S., Takenaka, M., Yamamoto, T., … Nakayama, H. (2006). Knowledge-building activity structures in Japanese elementary science pedagogy. International Journal of Computer-Supported Collaborative Learning, 1(2), 229–246. doi:10.1007/s11412-006-8995-8
Notes Efforts to introduce KB into Japanese elementary classrooms: created two practical design principles&amp;mdash;idea-centered lesson and collective knowledge advancement&amp;mdash;based on 12 KB principles. In two design studies, these two practical principles were integrated with Japanese science activity structures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Pelletier, J., Reeve, R., &amp; Halewood, C. (2006). Young children’s knowledge building and literacy development through Knowledge Forum</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-02-03-pelletier2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-02-03-pelletier2006/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Pelletier2006
Pelletier, J., Reeve, R., &amp;amp; Halewood, C. (2006). Young children’s knowledge building and literacy development through Knowledge Forum{\textregistered}. Early Education and Development, 17(3), 323–346.
Notes Highlights the literacy development of 4-year-old children in a laboratory school (p. 2)
Over the course of the year, children participated in a longitudinal photo journal project. With adult support, children posted their photo journals and ideas to KF® in the form of electronic “notes,” which allowed children to view each other’s work and to build on ideas by posting their responses and comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Porcaro. (2014). Educational change in Oman</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-23-porcaro2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-23-porcaro2014/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Porcaro2014
Porcaro, D. S. (2014). Educational change in Oman: a design research study of personal, institutional, and societal reactions to collaborative knowledge building. Technology, Pedagogy and Education, 23(2), 199–223. doi:10.1080/1475939X.2013.802993
Notes I am reading this article when reviewing literature on knowledge building. However, knowledge building is not a central concept in this article as its general sense is applied here. Maybe constructivist collaborative learning is the general approach here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Pursuit of explanation within a computer-supported classroom</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-10-04-hakkarainen2004a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-10-04-hakkarainen2004a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @hakkarainen2004a
Hakkarainen, K. (2004). Pursuit of explanation within a computer-supported classroom. International Journal of Science Education, 26(8), 979–996. doi:10.1080&amp;frasl;1468181032000354
Notes The purpose of the study is to analyse whether elementary school children, collaborating within a computer-supported classroom, may profitably participate in research-like processes of inquiry that characterize practices of scientific research. The problem addressed in the study is whether 10-year-old and 11-year-old children, in appropriate circumstances, engage in working with knowledge at a deep level of explanation instead of processing only factual and descriptive knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Quantified measures of online discourse as knowledge building indicators</title>
      <link>/notes/2014-09-02-zhang2011c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2014-09-02-zhang2011c/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Zhang2011c
Zhang, J. and Sun, Y. (2011). Quantified measures of online discourse as knowledge building indicators. In Spada, H., G., S., Miyake, N., and Law, N., editors, Connecting computer-supported collaborative learning to policy and practice: CSCL2011 conference proceedings, volume 1, pages 72–79. ISLS, Hong Kong SAR, China.
Notes Highlights This secondary data analysis examined a set of social interaction (e.g., social network patterns), content (e.g., questions, ideas), and lexical measures (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: The CSILE Project</title>
      <link>/notes/2013-08-29-scardamalia1994a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2013-08-29-scardamalia1994a/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @scardamalia1994a
Scardamalia, M., Bereiter, C., &amp;amp; Lamon, M. (1994). The CSILE Project: Trying to Bring the Classroom into World 3. In Classroom lessons: Integrating cognitive theory and classroom practice (pp. 201–228).
Notes Notes Marlene recommended this article when discussing my thesis work on (personal) epistemology. This article&amp;rsquo;s emphasis on World 3 and collective epistemology prompts me to rethink my research design. Combining with my thoughts from reading [[ref:forrester2006|Forrester&amp;rsquo;s thesis]] about epistemology, I am thinking about research of epistemology related to promisingness in two important directions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Woodruff, E., &amp; Meyer, K. (1997). Explanations from intra- and inter-group discourse</title>
      <link>/notes/2016-01-28-woodruff1997/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/notes/2016-01-28-woodruff1997/</guid>
      <description>References Citekey: @Woodruff1997
Woodruff, E., &amp;amp; Meyer, K. (1997). Explanations from intra- and inter-group discourse: Students building knowledge in the science classroom. Research in Science Education, 27(1), 25–39. doi:10.1007/BF02463030
Notes An earlier paper on science education following the &amp;ldquo;progressive discourse&amp;rdquo; approach.
Highlights We have conducted three separate studies in science classrooms that implemented this approach within a science unit. Across the studies we have varied the grade level of the students (grade five, grade seven), varied the topic of inquiry (images and shadows, density), and documented &amp;ldquo;on-line&amp;rdquo; inquiry discourse within a computer software environment called CSILE, standing for Computer Supported Intentional Learning Environment (Scardamalia, Bereiter, McLean, Swallow, &amp;amp; Woodruff, 1989) that networked small groups of students in the grade five class.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>